Until now, we already learned a lot about TypeScript, we learned about a lot of the core features.
Now it's time to also come to some features which are brand new, brand new introduced by TypeScript, something
we didn't really know before from the Javascript world because modules, classes and so on,
these are all things we already knew from Javascript even though we might have had some different approaches
of getting there
but it's not brand new. Now
this module looks at interfaces which really is a concept you didn't know before in Javascript.
Now I'm not going to spoil the fun,
what are interfaces and why would we use them?
Let's have a look at that in the next lectures.