So now it's the time to talk about interfaces, what interfaces are and how interfaces can be useful to
us.
I'll start with a very simple example which hopefully shows why interfaces are useful.
Consider we have this function greet
and this takes a person which we want to greet, so person and let's say it's of type
any for now. In this function here, what I want to do is I want to say console log or I want to print
something to the console and I want to print hello and then person.name.
Now if I call this function here, greet and I pass in a Javascript object which I will create here, constant
Max or let's name it person
and this will just be a Javascript object which has a name, which is Max and it maybe has an age, 27, something
like that and then I pass this person to the greet method here, like so.
Well let me compile this code and go to my webpage and you see Hello Max,
everything is working fine, isn't it?
Now let me change something, I'll set this to be firstName and I'll compile this again,
I'm not getting any compilation errors but here I get
Hello, undefined
and the reason is pretty clear I hope because we're accessing person.name but person doesn't have
a name anymore.
So for situations like these when we have a function in this case here or whatever code which needs
to know that what it uses has a certain property or method or whatever, then we might need an interface
because an interface basically is a contract signed by an object which says I guarantee you that I have
a certain property, function, whatever. So our greet function here would require that person object
to have signed such a contract,
now let's create the necessary contract. I'll set
or I change the type here from type any to type object and to type object which has a name which then
is of type string.
So while this might look cryptic, all I'm saying here is that the person argument should be an object
which has this name field where the value is a string.
It might have more fields than that by the way,
this does not mean that it only should have a name but it needs to at least have a name.
With that if I now compile this, I get an error and the error tells me that or the argument I'm passing
to the function here, my person, doesn't have a name but the function requires this to have a name,
so now we're getting warrant at compile time and not
once our application runs. So I can fix this by changing this back to name, running the compiler again,
this time it finishes without an error and our application runs fine
as you can see here.
So that is basically what an interface is,
we define a type where we want to make sure that a certain field is available.
Now since this definition here is pretty annoying because we might have a different function which
might be changeName where we also want to get a person where we have the name which is a string and
where we then simply want to set person.name equal to Anna,
well this would use the same interface if you want to call it like that but we had to define it twice
and if we change it, we need to change it in two places.
So while this will work, I can greet this person, greet again and in between, call change name on person,
so this will work without any issues as you will see,
Hello Max and then Hello Anna,
it is annoying because we have to change it in two places, if we want to change everything to use
firstName,
well then we have to change it all over the place here, which is pretty annoying, right?
So the better way is to actually create an interface with the interface keyword here. With that, I can
set up an interface which I'll name NamedPerson or whatever, this name is totally up to you,
then you have curly braces and in here, you define how this contract should look like, what your requirements
are.
My requirement here is that in this case now, I have a first name of type string.
Now with that, I can change this person type here to be of type name,
NamedPerson
and the same is true down here,
this should also be of type NamedPerson. With that if I compile this and I'll reload the application,
we see it's working again,
we didn't get a compilation error but we will get one if I change this to name and I try to compile this
now,
now we get a bunch of errors all telling me that I'm not fulfilling the contract this interface here requires
me to fulfill.
So interfaces are a way to guarantee your code that certain properties or methods or whatever are available.