So to fix this, I'll set this back or change this back to firstName and next, I want to show something which
might look strange. You see that here, my person, if I change it back to that, everything compiles fine.
Now if I pass an object that it'll direct without assigning it to a constant first and here, I'll add
the first name, also set to Max and set the age to 27,
it's exactly the same as this person which I just passed a second ago.
If I compile this, now I suddenly get an error where I get that the object literal may only specify known
properties and age does not exist in type NamedPerson.
That's a special check TypeScript performs
when directly passing object literals like this. Even though I'm doing almost the same here when assigning
this object literal to a constant first, this does not get checked as strictly as this does.
So once you pass an object literal directly, it's checked much more
strictly and here TypeScript recognizes that this age property here isn't defined in the interface.
So whilst this extra property is no problem here in our constant,
it is a problem here and that's just important to know,
you either want to make sure that you're not passing object literals directly or even better, that you
create your interfaces as explicit as possible.
So if you want to make sure that an age property is possible but not required, you can add age which should
be a number
and then you add a questionmark after age, which means it's an optional argument.
So now this will work again
and of course that would have worked
also if this weren't an optional argument but it allows me to also pass let's say person here still
where we don't have the age because age is optional.
So now that all still works
but now I'm not getting any errors
if I have the age and I could also have a person which doesn't have the age because age is optional.
Again, I could also make this non-optional, change this back to also have an age of 27 and now or whatever
number you like
and now everything would work again too.
So that's just so that you know that such optional arguments exist,
I'm just changing it back to use this optional argument again and this is also very important and not
directly connected to optional arguments, that object literals getting passed as an argument directly
are checked much more strictly
than if you are assign them to a constant first.
Now what if you have an interface and you want to set up the type like this
but then you might have some properties where you don't know the name of the properties in advance?
You know there might be some properties but you don't want to get any errors just because you don't
know the name of them yet.
Now for such a case, TypeScript has a special notation you may use,
you can use square brackets here as a key name,
this is not an array, that's just a special notation,
then you use any name you want, propName for example
but that is up to you, then of type string
since Javascript object keys can be written as strings too, right. So of type string and then that should
be of type any if you don't know the type this alternative property or properties might have.
Now the difference to the optional property here of course is that here, we clearly state the name and
also the type of the value, name of the key and type of the value
whereas here we don't know the name of the key yet
and in this case, we also don't state the type of the value, though we could do that if we know it might
only be a number for example. So with that, we're able to add something else to person,
let's say hobbies and then this is just an array is just a coincidence,
it doesn't have to be an array,
again these square brackets don't have anything to do with an array,
it's just the TypeScript notation for setting up a flexible key name.
So hobbies might be cooking and sports and with that if I compile this, it would also work because
I have this chance of setting up a new property which is neither age nor first nor firstName as long as
I match this type here, any is pretty easy to match though.
So that's just to give you more flexibility with your interfaces and allow you to set up dynamic
properties where you don't know how they might be named at the time you create your interface.