Well so far we only considered properties here on our interface but that's not all we can do,
we could also add a method. So let's say our NamedPerson should be able to also greet itself,
so we might have a greet method on our person. Now setting up a method is actually pretty easy too. We
just write it like we write method in a class, like so, greet, then we might have any inputs we want,
in this case this might be none but if we need let's say something or let's say we have the lastName
as a input which would be a string and then we specify what should be returned by this function.
So void if we here want to
console log in the method or whatever type you need.
Well with this, we get errors here because our person is not really implementing this greet method.
So actually I can set this NamedPerson type here already so that we're getting the errors
here too
and I can fix it by adding the greet method to it, like so.
Now here of course, I need to get lastName as the input and then I can simply log I am and then
just log this .firstName plus and then an empty space, lastName like so.
Now what that allows me to do of course is here,
this will not work anymore because here I don't have that method, so I will just comment it
out
but here I can then call person.greet and enter any lastName, then compile my code
and if we have a look at our console, well then we see
Hello Anna,
Hi I'm Anna anything because I'm changing the first name here with changeName and then I'm calling
greet anything.
So that's how you set up the requirement that your object here also has this greet method.