Now since we set up everything here, we not only can create objects like that, we could also create a
class,
so this class person could also implement the NamedPerson and that would require me to implement all
the things I require in this interface in my class here too,
of course except the optional things.
Now the greet method here of course also needs to implement a body here and simply should log the same
as here,
so I'm just copying this code for now and that allows me to then create a new person, so const new or
my person here, it could be a new person and then I could set my person name or first name it is equal
to Maximillian
and then of course here, I can also call the greet method, pass my person.
So here with greet just to remember you, I'm calling not the greet method in the person here, so maybe
we should rename this to greet me but I'm leaving it like this for now. Here, I'm calling the greet
method up here, this one and I'm passing my person to it and thereafter I'm calling myPerson.greet.
So now this is the greet method inside the person where I need to add the last name.
So again if I compile this and reload this application, we see these two outputs which are from the old code
but then we see Hello Maximillian and Hi, I am Maximillian anything,
so we see the code based on the class we created here.
So not only the objects we create can be of that type, we can also create a class which implements
an interface, here the implements keyword is important
and then we need of course, we can make sure that we actually implement all the methods and properties
as defined in the interface, the required ones at least.
We might also implement age
and what happens if we implement something else which isn't set up in the interface?
So if I also would have let's say a last name here of type string.
Well, let's try this by setting the myPerson.lastName here too, set it to anything here too and then maybe
even pass it here,
myPerson.lastName, if I compile this, it compiles without an error and it still runs fine.
So this will work and we may of course also add new properties to our class, just as we were able to
use extra properties when creating the object in a constant, remember the only very strict
check happened when we were directly passing an object literal to the function which requires a certain
interface.
So again, just to reinforce this or to make this really clear, the interface is a contract which can be
signed or which can be used as a type and which then makes sure all the conditions set up in the interface,
so that property being a required one, that being an optional one and the method here being required
with that exact argument and return type,
all these conditions have to be fulfilled by whatever
is of this type, for example each argument passed to the greet method or this class here.
That is what interfaces are there for, these are or this is the power
this contract offer you.