So we covered interfaces which defined properties and methods and how to use them on objects and classes
or here as a type for our argument which gets passed to the greet function.
These are the most common use cases after all
but you can also create interfaces for function types.
So I'll just add this little separator so that the code stays clear to or easy to be read,
I'm just keeping all the old code so that you have it there for reference
but now I want to create a new interface which I'll name DoubleValueFunc,
then again curly braces as before
but now I'm not setting up any property or a method like before but instead, I'll use parentheses to
kind of set up a function type here and here, I will have a number one which will be a number and number
two which should also be of type number and it will return a number.
So that is a function type as you learned it
and this interface basically says whatever uses this interface must be a function of this type.
So now I can create myDoubleFunction,
so myDoubleFunction maybe here like that and this should be of type DoubleValueFunc.
Now with that, I can say myDoubleFunction equals function
and of course this has to be let so that I can change it after creating it.
So here, I can then say or of course I also need to add the arguments here,
so number one which should be a number and number two which should be a number and you could use different
names here,
so I'll just rename this to value to show that this is allowed as long as the types match the
types from your interface
and then here, I will just return value1 plus
value2 times two
and of course we need some parentheses around that to
give us the right result and then I can call myDoubleFunction, pass 10 and 20,
so we should get back 60 I assume, compile everything, don't get an error, clear the console, reload and
see 60 down here.
So with that, I'm creating an interface which just says the type should be a function which gets two arguments
where both arguments are numbers
in this case and which returns a number which clearly is the case for this function
and if I change this here to be a string let's say and then I try to compile this, as you see, I get an
error that this is not the right type basically.
So that is where you can also use interfaces to set the type of functions.