Now to get to an end of this lecture, I'll also want to talk about interface inheritance. So we can inherit
from classes or we can extend classes with classes as you learned in the class module and we can do
the same for interfaces. So I can also use my, let's say NamedPerson from up here, this NamedPerson, create
a new interface which I'll name AgedPerson which extends the NamedPerson interface, so it will require
all the methods and properties as set up in this interface
but I can add additional ones,
in this case I want to set the age to be required.
It is optional in the NamedPerson,
now it is required. If I now create an old person here which should be of type AgedPerson,
well then I need to implement of course the age but that's not enough,
I also need to implement the firstName which should be Max for example and I need to have the greet
method remember that, here I need to get my lastName and then simply do something like console log and
here I'll keep it simple and just say hello.
So with that, if I then console log my old person
to the console, print it out,
compile this,
it finishes without an error and you see this is our object here, you get the age, first name and the greet function
and the most important thing is we're using the interface, AgedPerson which extends another interface
and therefore this person needs to have all the properties of the AgedPerson interface as well as all
the properties and methods from the NamedPerson interface.
We don't need that one because this is a flexible one and age was an optional one but now in this case
is a required one
since AgedPerson overwrites the optionality of the age property.