So we really learned a lot about interfaces and with that, you have all the core tools you will need to work
with them and to use them in production and your applications. Now there is
one interesting thing I want to show you with all that code
but if we have a look at the app.js file, there is something interesting you will see.
We see the function changeName, we see the person, we see all our function calls here of course and
this file is much shorter than the app.ts file
and that's not just because of the empty lines I have in here.
Where is this interface code,
how does this get compiled to Javascript?
Yes, here is the greet function,
so it should be before the greet function but this file starts with the greet function.
Well the very simple answer is interfaces get not compiled at all,
they're just there to check your code
during compilation to give you compilation errors.
Javascript doesn't know explicit types, it doesn't know interfaces therefore,
so interfaces get totally ignored when transforming your code to Javascript. In this Javascript code,
you see no trace of any interface and they're only there to give you errors
if you make an error at development time when working with TypeScript before or during compiling
it. That's the time when you will get errors and when interfaces matter, thereafter they're just left
out.