So time to solve this exercise, I'll create a new TypeScript file, solution and in the index.html, I'm
loading the solution.js file here with my module loader which I still have in place
but you could use a script tag here too since we're not really using modules
and the exercise was certainly difficult to create a generic map class. So a map is basically a collection
object where you stored key-value pairs, like an object in Javascript.
So let's create this, I'll name it MyMap, it should be a generic class, any type could be hold
so no constraints are specified
and then I have a private property, map which will be my internal storage in this class and this map
here should be of type object
where this object in turn has a key, which is type string, so just saying it should have a
key here of this type,
this has nothing to do with an array
again, remember this, we had this before in another module and the value stored for this key should be of
type T,
so this generic type set up for this class and then I'm just assigning this to be an empty object at
the beginning.
Now with this, I will add four methods here to this class,
the setItem method which allows me to store a new key-value pair.
Now setItem takes a key of type string as you again can see here and then the item of type T,
so of the generic type of this map.
So this map will only be able to hold either numbers or strings or whatever but not mixed
objects or values.
So with that, I then access MyMap, access this key here and set it equal to item
and yes I'm deliberately overwriting any existing items with that key,
so a map will store key-value pairs,
so each key can only appear once
so overwriting is the only behavior which makes sense here.
I also add the getItem method where I specify the string which I or the key for which I want
to get the value back
and here I will simply return this map and then access this key. Of course if this key doesn't exist, I'll get
an error but I'll leave out any complicated error handling logic for now.
I'll add a clear method where I then want to simply set this map equal to an empty object again to
clear it
and of course map is no function, little mistake here and then I'll add the printMap method which simply
should print out the complete map.
So here, I'll add a for/in loop and loop through all MyMap keys here,
so of this internal map, this private property and then I'll simply log the key and then the appropriate
value stored in the map.
With that, I'll create a number map here which is a new map,
this should be const of course and I'll set the generic type to be of a number, of type number so
that only numbers can be stored in this map and then I'll access number map,
set an item let's say 10
but of course I also need to give it a key which should be a string as we said,
so I'll name it apples so that we have 10 apples here or whatever,
add another where I set this to bananas, let's say 2,
then I want to print an item which I get from this map,
so number map getItem and I want to get the apples
and then I want to print MyMap,
so printMap before I then call the clear method on it
just to use all of the methods I created and then print it again.
So with this, let's save it and go to the console, reload and have a look at it.
Now you see 10 which is this console log where I simply get my apples item,
then you see apples 10, bananas 2 which you see result from this printMap call.
Well then you see nothing because this printMap call here doesn't print anything
since I don't have any items left because I cleared MyMap and of course since this is generic, I can
copy this and change it to be a string map here where this should be of type string.
Now of course I can't add ten and two to anymore but I could add 10 and 2, like this
and then if I save this, we shouldn't have any errors,
looks fine,
let's have a look at the console,
well I'm getting pretty much the same output but as you can see by the coloring, now I'm having strings
here instead of numbers.
So that is a pretty cool example on how such a generic would make sense if you want to create a
map where you only want to store any type in theory but in one map, only one type, either type number
or type strings
and of course here again you have the advantage that I get support here
since my IDE knows this will be a string in this case, I could access the length, here it knows this
will be a number so I could use all kinds of methods numbers can be used on or methods which can be
used on numbers.
So that is an example for a generic class and how to use generics.