So we're done on generics. Now generics are a really cool feature but you're probably not using them
all over the place simply because they're a really specific feature and oftentimes, you don't need to
use them but you will know when to use them and then they really add extra flexibility and make your
code more flexible or for you as a developer
more flexibility. If you want to learn more about generics,
well unfortunately the greatest hint or advice I can give to you is simply googling for generics because
it's a concept not exclusively introduced by TypeScript,
you will also find it in other languages and the idea behind it is always the same.
So any article diving deeper into generics might be a great starting point to learn more about the theory
behind them if you're interested in that.
Well now with that, let's continue with the course.