So back I am in the well-known set up here with my app.ts file, I get my server running as always
and now let's look at these generics. Now in order to understand what they do, why they are useful,
let's start with a very simple generic here, so just a little example of what could be a generic
or why this might be useful.
So I'll create a function here and I'll simply name it echo, it gets data of any type which obviously
makes this function very generic
and then I return this data.
Now you might think or rightfully ask which sense does this function make if it simply returns what we
input there.
Well it's kind of like an echo command and we will reach more complicated functions later on
but in order to understand generics, it's really helpful to start very basic here.
So I got my echo function
and with that I can then log this to the console for example, calling echo, inputting Max and and doing
the same, inputting 27 and doing it again and this time inputting an object where my name is Max and
my age is 27.
So with all that being input, if I then go to a new console window and compile everything with
the tsc command, I can then switch over to my running project, open up the console and we see Max 27 and
the object.
Now I could understand if you're not super impressed right now because it's not really that strange
what is happening here or not that great but the important thing to realize here is this function here
is kind of a generic function because we have this any type here but we do have a big disadvantage with
this any type, you see I get back any data I enter here.
So since I enter a string in this first echo call, I could not only log the data I enter but I could
also enter let's say length because a string, like an array, has a length, the number of characters.
If I save this and
yes
compiling also help, so if I
save this and compile the code, we see three here because Max has three characters. Now what's the
issue I got here?
Well it's pretty clear or it becomes pretty clear if I just entered the dot here, my IDE is not offering
this length.
Yes I can type it and then it appears but it's not fatly written here
which means my IDE doesn't know that we're getting back a string here. Now
OK you might say IDE magic,
not really that important but maybe the problem becomes clearer with the next example.
If I go to this echo function and enter length here, I can do this right, now I can run the TypeScript compiler
and then go to the console
and now I get undefined here.
So the issue I got here is a number doesn't have a length which is why I get undefined and that
has a certain problem to it.
If I do the same on the object here, compile and have a look,
now I'm getting undefined too and just entering watch mode so I don't have to compile if I handle the kind.
So the issue here clearly is that we don't know the type you're in, would be nice if we get a compilation
error, if we try to access length here on this number but we can't get this because the data type
is any and therefore, TypeScript doesn't know any better than we do
if this data actually has a length property for example. So we might want a generic function like this
which can handle all kinds of data but once we get back the data, it would be nice if TypeScript would
be aware of the exact data type and not of type any.