So let's write this function in a better generic way.
So here the betterEcho function would be also getting data as an input but now I'm making this a
generic and I'm doing this with the following syntax.
I enter the lower than or smaller than sign, then any character of your choice, typically you choose
an uppercase T for that, for type but you can take any character you want,
you don't have to use an uppercase character here
and then the greater than sign.
Now this strange construct here makes this a generic function,
it tells TypeScript that this is a generic function
and with this T character here, we're telling TypeScript hey when using this function, give me the
type
and then I will be able to use this type. Therefore we can now use T here as a type
and we know the data we get will be of type T because again, that's what we will assign when using this
function.
Now with that, I can still return data here and now I'm copying my three console logs from above here
and let's see. If I change the echo here to the betterEcho,
now you can see if I press the dot after this, I get the better IDE support and I can access length.
Now if I go down to my number and enter betterEcho like this,
now I don't have the length property
and if I try to use length here, let's have a look at the TypeScript console,
you see I'm getting an error that property length does not exist on type number and that is exactly
what I want.
Now with this set up here, I do have a generic function, I can use a number but I can't use the length
property on it thereafter.
So if I save this and have a look now at the output, you see I'm still getting three for the length of my
Max string, then 27 and then the object, so all the types work but since TypeScript is aware of the result
type, I can't do any operations with it that aren't supported by that type.
By the way, you can also explicitly state which type you will use in this function.
Right now, TypeScript is inferring it by the type of the argument but it could also state number here,
also contained in these smaller and greater than signs.
So with that, I would make clear that I want to have a number and if I then pass let's say a string here,
I would also get a TypeScript error
as you can see because I explicitly said that this would be a generic function using the number type
but the data I'm passing doesn't match this type and that is why types or generic types, generic functions,
generics in general are a powerful tool to improve your code, make your code both flexible and yet manageable
by the TypeScript compiler.