Now in TypeScript, there also are some built-in generics,
so let's have a look at them,
the most prominent built-in generic probably is the array.
So let's say we have some test results and they are stored in an array.
Now of course we can simply create this array
like so, for example I'll have two values in that array
and that would work
and there's nothing wrong with that but in the back,
this is a generic type. So we can assign a type to this test results array and the type would be array
and then assign which types this array should be able to hold.
So now if I push a new item on that array, that works but if I try to push let's say a string,
well my IDE is already complaining and so is TypeScript
if I try to compile this.
So by explicitly setting this type here, I'm getting the compiler support which makes sure that I'm not
accidentally pushing something on that array which doesn't work.
So with that, I can of course log that array and that will just work
but now I explicitly set which values this array will be able to hold.
Normally you can mix strings, numbers and whatever you want but if you want to be explicit and don't
want to have them mixed,
well this is how you would do that and with that, if I could go to the console, print it out, you see my
array here with all numbers because I assigned it as this. So array is a generic type by default.