Speaking of arrays, you can also assign a generic type to be an array for example.
What do I mean with that?
Well let's have a look at this function, printAll which also is a generic function and which takes some arguments
and then I could of course also say that the arguments I want are an array of the type I use in this
function
and with that, I could then call forEach because TypeScript knows that the arguments I get will be an
array since I'm specifying that here, it doesn't know the type of the elements in that array but it knows
that it will be an array
and then I can just say element
console log element, so just the fat arrow function here with the built-in forEach method on that array.
With that, I can then call printAll, pass an array of let's say apples and here I want that banana,
close that array
and that would be fine but I can also be more explicit and also tell TypeScript that this will be of
type string array
excuse me, string because just string, not string array because the argument here is of type than of
array of strings.
So with that, if I save this,
well we see apple and banana down here being printed to the console.