Now so far we had generic functions but we can also have generic types,
so generic types is not this thing between the opening and closing tag
here or the smaller and greater sign but a generic type would be the following.
I have a constant and I'll just name it echo2
and this would be of type generic, then a function
where we get data as an input and then return this type and I can assign my echo function.
Now that looks extremely cryptic, I believe,
so let me tell what I am or explain what I'm doing here.
So I'm creating a new constant, that should be fairly clear and then I'm assigning a type here.
Remember everything after the colon but before the equal sign is a type assignment,
so this is a type. It's a generic type as you can tell because I'm using this type set up here with the
strange generic syntax you already know
and then it's a function type thereafter,
so I'm just telling TypeScript that this constant will hold a function where the input is one argument
of type, of this type the user specifies
and all this function will do is it will return something of that that input type.
So I could assign any function but here I'm assigning the echo function from the beginning because this
function actually does exactly what I want and the betterEcho function would even be better because
this function does exactly fit
this set up. It takes an argument of a type specified here, a generic function it is and returns
data which also fits this input type.
With that, I can then simply call echo2 and pass something, a string for example and I can be more explicit
and also tell TypeScript that this will be a string and maybe also enter console log here
now that I think about it, well with that at least it should work,
yes here we see something.
So I'm just reusing the betterEcho function but I'm assigning this whole generic thing here, the generic function
type to a normal constant, making this a type assignment.