Besides generic functions and types, we also have generic classes,
so let's have a look at them. Generic classes are a very important construct
you will often use, probably if you use generics, it will oftentimes be a generic class.
So we could create the SimpleMath class here and I will make it non-generic to begin with,
so let's just open the curly braces to go to the class body and let's say the SimpleMath class should
have a basic value and it should have a multiply value property and I'm deliberately not assigning types
right now.
It then has the calculate method here which will simply return me this space value times this multiply
value,
OK.
I can of course use this class to create let's say a simpleMath constant which uses this SimpleMath
class where I then can assign the base value to be 10 and the multiply value to be 20 let's say
and then I can call or I can log the result of my call to simpleMath.calculate.
So with that if I save this, go to the console, I'll reload so that we can see everything,
I get 200 which clearly is the result of 10 times 20.
Now the issue I got here is if I change this to something, so a string,
I'm not getting any compilation errors
as you can tell but of course here, I get not a number as a result because I can't multiply a string
with the content of something with 20.
So we should probably make this more generic, to make sure that we actually can use it in a generic way.
So I will continuously improve this class
but let's start simple and make it a generic class first by using the same syntax as for the function,
just telling TypeScript hey this is a generic class and the user should specify the type which will
then be stored in this T type if you want to call it like this, this internal type which can be used in
this class
and then I can tell the class that the base value should be T and that the multiply values should
be type T and the calculate result actually should always be a number here.
Now with that if I save this and have a look at the compiler,
now we see we get some errors that the left-hand side of the arithmetic operation must be of type any
number or enum and the right-hand side too. So the issue TypeScript has with my setup here is that
well I can enter any type and it recognizes this and it recognizes that this could be a type which does not
really match this.
So if I change this to 10 here, well that does not change it because the general problem still persists,
Typescript knows that T could be a value which can not be used in this calculation.
Therefore I will explicitly cast these values to a number by adding a plus in front of them, saving this
and now you see the errors have gone away,
so now everything works.
Now if I go back to the console, we still see 200
but the problem which persists is if I enter something here, we're not getting an error but we're still
getting not a number. I will come back to this
but for now we generated a generic class even though it's not that useful yet.