I can make it more useful by explicitly stating that T should extend something.
Now with the extends keyword here in the generic type declaration and the same is true for generic methods,
you could use the same syntax,
I can tell which base types should be allowed.
So this is a generic constraint,
I'm constraining which types can be used in this generic class.
I can constrain this to number and you could argue if that makes that much sense because now
I could just say that this class should only be able to use numbers but if I do it like this, I can go
down to my SimpleMath class, enter number here and save this
and now if I try to add something here as a parameter,
now you see I'm getting an error because string clearly is not of type number.
So with this set up, I'm still getting not a number here but I'm getting this compilation error,
so I will have to fallback to number.
Now I could use a string because this would work,
this can be cast to a number.
So if I know yes you should be able to enter strings and those strings will always be castable,
so always be numbers just as a string,
I could also extend multiple values, so I could say, or multiple types.
So I could say T should be of type number or string,
so here I can now tell that this should be of type string, of course 20 then also has to be a string because
all the values here use T, right and with that, I wouldn't get an error any more and it would work,
I would get 200 again. Yes if I enter something here, I would also not get a compilation error but not
a number again
but that's not really an issue,
all I wanted to show here is that you can create a generic class, that you have
this extends keyword here and that with that, you can control which values can be passed,
for example you will never be able to pass a boolean here.
So if I try to create a generic class with booleans and I assign true or false and I compile this,
well now I get the error that type boolean does not satisfy the constraint number or string.
So while my IDE doesn't actually give me any errors, TypeScript will and that's just what I can control
here.
As a matter of fact, boolean could be cast to a number but that's not really what this example is about,
right,
it's just about how you can constrain your generic type here and how you can create a generic class
in
the end.