Now for this example, you could say that it's a little bit annoying that if we assign this of type string,
that both values have to be a string, that we can't say OK base value is a string of 10 and multiply value
is a number, 20. It would be nice if we could be more flexible here
and we can because we can use multiple types here in the generic type declaration.
So I get my T type here and I will change this to U
and that's just a convention, if you use multiple types, then you have T
and U, just the alphabetical order.
So I'll add a new type T and I'll leave U, U still extends this
and now with T, I also want to extend number or a string because I want to be able or I want to give the
user the chance to use two different types,
so multiply value will be of type U which is a number or a string and base value is T, which could
be anything at the moment.
If I also want to restrict T to be of type number or string,
well then I could either say extends number or string like I did before or I actually say it should extend
U.
Important to know is though if I do it like this, then I'm not saying that T should have the
same constraints as U,
it means T has to be the same type as U.
So if I pick number as a type for U, then T also has to be a number.
So in order to be able to really mix them, I have to add this constraint instead, that allows me to say
down here that the first type should be of type string and the second should be of type number.
So to wrap this all up and stop the confusion, what I'm saying here is this generic class has two types
which can be set up by the user,
the first type which is used internally should be a number or a string and it's used for base value
and the second type, U here also should be a number or a string and is used for the multiply value
and then here when using or instantiating the class, I'm saying the first value,
so T should be a string
in this case here and the second value, U should be a number and therefore I'm using two or I'm able
to mix the values here.
Now if I save this, you'll see it finishes without an error here and going back to the browser and reloading
it, we see 200 again
and this works fine.