Welcome to this course in TypeScript, I'm so happy to have you onboard. Now
no matter if you're onboard because you want to learn what this thing you are using in your Angular 2
project
actually is
or if you're onboard because you want to dive deeper into TypeScript and actually use it in other projects
besides Angular 2,
this course is for you.
We're going to start simple, learn what TypeScript is, why we might use it and how we use it, how we install
it and how we set up a basic project with it.
Throughout this course, you will then learn what types actually are,
it's the thing what gives TypeScript the name in the end but why are they useful,
how do they work?
Before we dive into the compiler, learn about some of the ES6 features TypeScript supports and then dive into
classes, namespace and modules to modularize our application and use the many benefits TypeScript offers
us there. Thereafter
it's time to have a look at some more TypeScript specific features which you won't find in plain or
vanilla Javascript,
I'm talking about interfaces, generics or decorators to really enhance your project and give you brand
new opportunities in your project or code.
We will also have a look at how to integrate TypeScript in your existing workflow, like your webpack
or Gulp workflow or build a brand new workflow using TypeScript only.
Now oftentimes, you will also use third-party libraries like JQuery which are written in Javascript and
not in TypeScript.
We will learn how to implement them in our TypeScript project and let the compiler, the TypeScript compiler
know what the library is all about it, even get IDE support and to wrap this all up,
we're going to have a look at how to use ReactJS together with TypeScript.
Yes this is possible and it's awesome and it shows you that you really can use TypeScript in any project
of your choice.
Now there are a lot more things, exercises and well I really love this course and I'm happy to have
you here,
so enough of the talking, let's dive into it.