So let's start with the most important question first, what is TypeScript? Before then in the next video, I'll
have a look at why and how.
So what is TypeScript?
Well you know Javascript, Javascript is the script language you're using in the browser to make your web
sites reactive to run any code in the browser.
Now Javascript is a great language and it's continuously getting extended,
it offers us a lot of features like constructor functions or prototypes and it uses dynamic types.
Now I'm highlighting this types thing, that in Javascript a variable may be a string and then may get
a value of a number without any issues because the types is something I'll come back to as we're talking
about TypeScript here and you might tell by the name that types play an important role there.
So this is Javascript as we know it,
specifically you could say this is ES5,
we also get ES6 which is the next version of Javascript to put it like that, which introduces new
features to Javascript, like for example the class keyword and so on.
But the problem for one is that ES6 is not yet supported by all browsers,
so we do have some issues here with using native ES6 and the other issue is while it does enhance
Javascript, it does introduce new features,
there are still a lot of things where you could say that could be better, that it's a bit better in other
languages and there are some features we might want to use in Javascript which aren't available, now this
is where TypeScript comes in. TypeScript is a wrapper so to say, it compiles down to Javascript in
the end and introduces new features which we can use in our code and which will then run in the browser
as the TypeScript compiler will make sure to find ways to compile all these great new features into ES5
code to then run in any browser.
Now some of these features are generics or interfaces and of course, you will learn about these features
throughout this course, they're also a lot of other features and the most important feature are types or the fact that
TypeScript is a strongly typed language, which means you have to be specific which type a variable
is, so that you can't have a string variable and then assign a number to it and get through with it
and this actually is a great improvement as you will see the next video. Before coming to that video,
I already mentioned one important fact,
Typescript is a wrapper around Javascript so to say. TypeScript does not run in the browser,
we need to compile it to Javascript to run there.
Now whilst you might ask, well how can we compile features which aren't available in Javascript to
Javascript,
well I got a module on TypeScript compiler which also has a look at this but for now, just be aware that
we have to compile all our TypeScript code to Javascript as this will run in the browser in the end. So
TypeScript is only an extra language we can use during development,
it's not what runs in the browser.