So we had to look at the what, we also briefly saw the why,
well now let's have a look at why in a greater detail and also see how. I'm on typescriptlang.org which
is the official web page of TypeScript
and there, you may click on playground which is a great resource to really play around with TypeScript
and actually, a lot of the examples shown in this course may be recreated here.
So here we have this left box which holds our TypeScript code and we have the right box which holds the compiled
Javascript code because remember, TypeScript compiles to Javascript.
Now here you may select classic Javascript
if you don't see that code here by default and this actually is really just Javascript. It happens
to be ES6 version with the let keyword here but it's Javascript, it's not really TypeScript,
what we're using here, though we could use any TypeScript code here in the left box since it will get compiled
to the right box. Therefore the right box is very equal to the left box
since again, we already have Javascript here.
Now what happens here is a greeter constructor function is created,
then we extend it with this prototype and add the greet method
and then we basically instantiate this object, create a new button on the document which you can then
click to execute the greet method on this object.
We can see this code in action by clicking on run here which opens a new tab, gives us this button and
shows us this alert
and here we already see an issue, we're seeing hello object object.
So let's have a look at that code,
why does this happen?
Well we create this prototype or we extend the prototype, add the greet method and there we say return
Hello
and then this greeting,
so whatever this greeting is equal to. Now in the constructor, we pass something to this constructor
which is then actually assigned to this greeting
and the thing we pass happens to be an object and not just a string.
Now the issue with normal Javascript is that here, we're not getting any warnings or errors,
this is code which is perfectly valid but which will give us an undesired result when we run it
as you saw before. Now we can easily enhance this with TypeScript by simply specifying that greeting
here should be of type string
and we do this by adding a colon and then simply string.
Now all of a sudden with this simple change, you see that now we get some error here
and if we hover over it, we see that the argument of type this here is not assignable to parameter
of type string, so that basically we may not pass an object here because we're expecting a string.
So in order to make it work, I have to remove the object part and change this to a string,
the error is gone and if I now hit run and click the button, we see hello world and that is really what
TypeScript is, why we like might want to use it and how it works.
We simply mix our TypeScript code with Javascript code as you see here, there is any degree of mixture
possible
and then we get the benefits from using TypeScript by simply getting this extra check for the type here
and making sure that not somewhere in our code, we're kind of introducing a bug because us using a wrong
type for example. Now types are only one,
though also the most important but only one of the many features TypeScript offers
and throughout this course we're going to learn about a lot of other features too and see how to use them and
how they help us.