So in the last video, we use the playground
and as I said in the last video, you may use this playground to follow along the examples in this course
or play around with the playground in any way you want to play around with it.
There are only some parts of the course, for example where we use multiple files, where you will get issues
when using the playground since it doesn't support this, at least not at the point of time when I recorded
this video.
But anyways, you probably not only want to use the playground for TypeScript development, you want to be
able to work with it on your local machine,
therefore we need to install TypeScript there
and that's actually really easy to do.
Open up a command line on your computer, on Mac or Windows and then you need to have Node installed on
your machine or specifically Nodes Package Manager, npm to install TypeScript.
Now as a developer, you probably already do have this because you use npm in a lot of projects to manage
your dependencies
but if you don't, simply head over to node.org
and download the latest version here, 6.5 in my example, download it, run through the installer
and again we won't really use Node here but we need npm, it's package manager. So download it, install
it and you will have npm as well.
Now with that finished and again we only need it to manage all the dependencies or our packages,
we can now globally install TypeScript on our machine by running npm -g install typescript,
this will fetch the latest version and install it on your machine.
Now on Mac, you may need to throw a sudo in front of it,
the same is true for Linux.
Now if you do this and well then of course enter your password,
in my case here at least, it will download TypeScript and install it on your machine. At the point of
time when I record this video as you can see,
1.8.1 was the latest version of TypeScript
but of course that may be higher in your case.
Now with that, you've got TypeScript on your machine and what we can do next is use it.