So with TypeScript installed, in order to use it, you may create an example project like this one here,
simply an index.html file and a script.ts file.
Now ts is important, that's just the extension because it's TypeScript not Javascript, .ts is the file
extension then. So I open both in Sublime here or use any text editor of your choice of course, including
very basic ones like Notepad, so whatever you like and as you can see my index.html has really just a
basic HTML5 skeleton with doctype, head and so on,
no extra code
whatsoever
and the script.ts file is completely void.
So with that, let's head over to the playground and fetch the code we use there to stay with that example.
Back in the script.ts file,
I'm going to paste it in because I can use it as it is there,
I got my index.html file where I'll add the button later on and in order to use this file there, I of
course need to import it. So I'm doing this at the end of the body section here by adding script tags
and now I'm not importing script.ts even though that's the only file we have right now
but instead I want to use script.js
because remember it's Javascript code which runs in the browser, not TypeScript.
It will get compiled to Javascript code and this .js file will get created by TypeScript.
So I'll make this a relative import by adding ./ at the beginning here.
Now of course if I simply double-click index.html and view it in the browser,
you see nothing happening,
well that's going to change.
Let's get back to the command line and navigate into this TypeScript folder which has the script.ts file
and the index.html file.
Let's now finally compile our file by navigating into this folder which holds the script.ts file and
then run tsc which is a command available once we install TypeScript as we did before which runs the
TypeScript
compiler and then passing the file we want to compile,
in this case it's script.ts. With that command we're telling TypeScript,
please take this script.ts file and compile it to Javascript.
So once I hit enter,
well we're not seeing any errors,
we would see any compilation errors at this step in this console and once we did this,
you can see we now got the script.js file here as well which was created by the compiler and
which will hold our compiled Javascript code.
Now with that in place, if I now reload this page and click the button, you get the same effect as in the
playground
but now on our local machine.