Now the set up from the last videos will work
and allows you to use TypeScript on your machine.
Now for the rest of this course, I will have a specific folder structure which I will always keep and
a little helper which makes the TypeScript development a little more convenient and makes these examples a
little bit more enjoyable and it's also required for some of these modules,
I'll install a very lightweight little server which will run automatically, a NodeJS server that is,
which will host our index.html file.
Well right before we executed it by double clicking on it, which works fine for this basic example but
once we reached a point where we use modules and multiple files, we need a little server able to serve
these files,
our default file protocol which is used when we double-click on a file will not suffice in this case,
also you might be interested in seeing a bit more of a realistic setup.
So I'm here in Web Storm which is just my IDE I'm using for development,
you may use any other editor like Sublime or Atom and as you can see here I opened a folder which holds
an index.html file which looks like the one before basically, which already has this script import, of course
you may place it also at the end of the body section here,
doesn't really matter for this course and that I got the app.ts file which only prints console
log
it works.
So no TypeScript code at all
but as I already said before, you can mix it with Javascript,
there is no pure TypeScript code,
it is Javascript code plus some extra features in the end.
So with these two files of course, the job is or the task is to set this folder up in a way that we can
use it throughout this course.
Now I can do this by simply going to the command line and that's just the normal terminal window here
in the bottom just included in my IDE already
and the first thing I want to do is I want to put this project here, this folder under control of npm,
this package manager of Node
and the reason for this is that throughout this course
and also in this video, I'm going to add a few packages to this folder, to this project. I simply
do set this under control of
npm by running npm init inside of his folder.
Now that prompts me a couple of questions here and I just hit enter all the time since the defaults
are fine for me and it will create this package.json file here.
Now once you open that file, it should look something like that
and while it's really lean, you get the dependencies in-depth, dependencies nodes here which will basically
save all the dependencies you will use in your project
and one dependency and that means package
I am using or I will use is lite-server. I can install it by running npm install lite-server, don't
use the -g flag here because we don't want to install it globally, we just want to install it
locally in this project, by adding --save-dev, I'm making sure that this gets added as a development
only dependency,
it's not needed for whenever you shipped as code on a server or to any of your websites.
So this will download lite-server which again is just a very lightweight server which hosts the index.html
file and will also automatically updated whenever we change our Javascript code,
so really just convenient to have an easier workflow and not have to hit reload all the time and
so on.
So with that, you see the dependency was added here in this file and then I can write a convenient script to quickly
start the server by adding in the scripts section here, in the package.json file start and then
the command
I want to run here is simply lite-server, the package I just installed.
What this will do is that once I run npm start just like that, it will open up a new tab in the browser
here, typically at localhost:3000 but it will search for a free port automatically and serve your index.html
file, as you can see if I type hello here and save this,
it automatically reloaded without me having to hit reload and displays the content of the index.html
file.
So that's why I'm using it,
it's really convenient. Now the last piece missing here is that right now we got the index.html file,
we can compile our TypeScript files by running tsc, as a side note keep that server running, don't close
it, open up a new tab for running additional commands.
So I can compile app.ts
by running tsc app.ts but it would be more convenient if I could only run tsc and it would
automatically look for all the TypeScript files and compile them.
I can do this by first running tsc --init to not only put this folder under control
of npm which we did before with npm init but now also to put it under control of TypeScript so to say.
This will in the end create a tsconfig.json file which tells TypeScript, hey this folder here is
of TypeScript project by running tsc,
please compile all TypeScript files and you can see this hold some options on or for the TypeScript
compiler and I will come back that is in the module, the TypeScript compiler which is following after the
next module
but right now, keep this file as it is, the default configuration here is fine and well what we now can
do is we can simply run tsc without
app.ts,
so just tsc and this will search for all TypeScript files, in this case only app.ts and compile them
to the Javascript file as you can see here.
Now with that, if we now open up the console here and reload this page for once, we see it works.
That's the base set up
I'm going to use throughout this course and you can also find it attached to this video of course
and as you saw, it was really easy to get started with that
and that's also a setup
you may want to use for your own basic project.
Enough of setting up,
let's get started in the next module.