In this course you'll learn a lot about TypeScript and there is one particular use case one scenario
where you could all use typescript which we hadn't had a look at.
Thus far we primarily focused on using typescript to write browser side JavaScript code in the end.
And that is totally fine and might be the most common use case of working with typescript but it's not
the only one.
You can also use typescript to build.
Note J.S. applications although of course in conjunction with the popular express J as framework.
Now while notorious on its own is not capable of executing typescript In this module you will learn
how you can still use typescript to write notorious scripts and we will build a very simple web application
a very simple REST API here where we also utilize typescript on the server side with no trace and express
just as in the react section.
Here's a little disclaimer for this section this section here requires node and expressed knowledge.
It's about using typescript with node Express it's not teaching node from the ground up.
So if you never heard about node and express before definitely take some dedicated resources like my
node J.S. to complete guide course first before you explore this section.
So let's dive in.