So let's get started with a typescript and note J S and for that I'm essentially in an empty new folder
here.
Just some configuration files there and let's start.
Very simple let's add an app dot Tia's file in here.
You can name it however you want of course.
And in there let's write some code which we want to execute with node J.S..
But where we want to use typescript as simple script could be that we just console logs something.
This works in the browser but does all the works with node J.S..
Now make sure you got node J.S. installed which you definitely should have if you followed through that
course because we used it and NPM with web Pag and with many other tools and libraries we installed
with NPM already.
So you should have no chance installed it if you got it installed you could execute this file if you
compile it to javascript.
So if you run TSC apt dot.
Yes.
And I produce my apt or James file they offer I can execute this with node and I print something here
no when I delete the app dot J.S. file and I try to execute app dot yes with node you'll see something
strange.
This also works.
So is node capable of executing typescript.
No it is not.
And that's really important.
It just doesn't care about the file extension but whatever it finds in the file it treats as a regular
javascript.
And this year doesn't use any types of features so it works.
That changes if we add different content here let's say instead we have a h variable which is a number.
And then here I set this to 30 and then a console log H here.
This of course is valid typescript code but if we tried to execute this with node you will see we get
an error.
So node is not capable of parsing and compiling typescript it just treats every file you execute with
it as javascript.
And if you're not using any type good features in the file yes then it does work but if you do it won't
work.
You always have to compile the file to JavaScript first then in order to then execute the javascript
file which has only valid Charlotte code in it.
That's really important to understand.
Node does not execute typescript.
Now you can actually install a package t s dash node which in the end gives you dad types of compiler.
Combined with the node executable you could say so that you can install a tool globally which you can
use to run times good files just like that.
But behind the scenes it will then just do the compilation for you and execute the compiled code.
So it basically combines the TSC and the node step into one step.
So it is a package you could use.
But whilst this might be nice for development for production for really serving your files on some web
server on some web host This is probably not ideal because having this extra compilation step every
time your code gets executed simply adds a bit of extra overhead which is fine during development.
But what you probably don't want when your code is production ready and you really want to serve it
somewhere.
Therefore in this module will not use ti as known and will not try to execute any types code files with
node.
Instead I will show you a setup we can use to build a node Express Web application or rest api here
with just TypeScript and the types of compiler and vanilla node J.S..