So that's it for this module you learned how you can use typescript in a node express application that
you can install extra types for Express and for node for example to get great types of support in your
files that you write the application like you would always write it but that for example your import
and export some text differs and that you can of course use types and also any other type could feature
you learn about you could use interfaces you could use decorators you could use in arms and tuples and
everything that's typed exclusive that all works here because we're writing a regular typescript application
here and it gets compiled with the normal types of compiler to regular javascript code javascript code
which then is executed with node J.S..
Now if you want to have more examples on how to work with TypeScript and Node express you can of course
from one simply google for node express typescript to find more examples but I can also strongly recommend
that you check out nest.
J.S. it's a notorious framework which embraces typescript whilst you can make note express work with
typescript as you solve for out this module.
This is a framework which gives you project node projects with Python support out of the box and it
embraces all these types of features like decorators and so on with Nestlé as you can build node web
applications rest api but all the applications where you render views or graph to LAPD you can build
that all with no choice but also with TypeScript and this project heavily uses features like decorators
interfaces and so on.
So definitely check out Nestlé s if you want to build service side web applications with node and typescript.
It's a great framework really fun to use and uses all the cool features types has to offer.
So no custom type installation work arounds or anything like that is needed here.
You get great types could support out of the box.