Earlier in the course
you learned a little bit about objects, you learned
objects are collections of key value pairs, so if you have
properties that are highly related, we want to encapsulate them
inside of an object. Here's an example. Let's say we are building
an application for drawing different kinds of shapes, like circles,
rectangles and so on. So we could declare multiple variables,
around circles for example radius we set that to 1,
let x and y
we're defining multiple variables, but all these variables are highly
related, they represent the circle. A better approach is to
put these variables inside of an object. Now we can
send that object anywhere in our programs, we can pass that to any functions,
and all these variables would be available in that object. So,
I'm going to define an object, we could use let
or const, in this case it doesn't really matter, so let's define a
circle object using the object literal syntax, so
we add these curly braces, and inside them we add
1 or more key value pairs. So, the first key
is radius, and the value is 1. Now this value we have
here can be any type in JavaScript, it can be a number,
a string, a boolean, null, undefined, it can
even be another object. or an array, or a function. Let me show you
so instead of defining two other key value pairs
as x and y, I'm going to add a key called location, and
set it's value to another object. Now in this object we can
have two key value pairs or properties
the first one is x and the second one is y.
We can also have another property here like isVisible,
and set that to a boolean, true or false, okay?
So the purpose of an object is to group
related variables. But it's not just grouping related variables,
quite often we have functions that should operate
on these variables. For example, we can have
a function like draw, for drawing a circle. Or,
we could have another function for moving a circle, right?
So again these functions are highly related to these
variables we have to find here. So instead of defining these functions,
in a stand alone way, it's better to put these functions,
inside of the circle object. Again with this, where we
have the circle object in our program, we have access to all
of it's properties and functions. So let me show you how to add
this draw function inside of the circle object. We add
another key value pair, the key is draw, and the value
is a function, so I told you that the value of a key value pair
can be anything in JavaScript, here the value is a function.
Now for simplicity I just want to do a console.log
here, let's log draw on the console.
So now with this circle object, we no longer need
these independent variables, and
functions, all of these are now part of a
circle object. So we can access them using the dot notation,
circle. look, all of them are here. We can simply call
this draw function like this. And if I save the changes, you see
the draw message here. Now what you see here,
is what we refer to as object oriented
style programming. So object
oriented Programming, also abbreviated as OOP.
Object oriented programming is basically a style of programming
where we see a program as a collection of
objects that talk to each other to perform some functionality.
So here we have a circle object, and this object has a few properties
and a function. In object oriented programming terms,
if a function is part of an object, we call
the function a method. So here more accurately instead of saying
we're calling the draw function of the circle object, we
say we're calling the draw method of the circle object. So draw
method. So that's the difference between a function and a method
if a function is part of an object, in object oriented programming
terms, we refer to that function as a method. Now,
using this object literal syntax, is an easy way to
create an object, but as our applications get more complex we need a
different way to create objects. And that's what you're going to learn next.