In low level
languages like C or C++, when creating an
object, we need to allocate memory to it, and when we're done we need to
reallocate memory. But in JavaScript, we don't have this concept.
We can easily create the new object,
at the time we initialized this object, the memory is automatically
allocated to this object, next we can use that, and
when we are done using, we don't need to deallocate the memory. So,
our JavaScript engine has what we call a garbage
collector. The job of this garbage collector is to find the
variables or constants that are no longer used and then deallocate the
memory that was allocated to them earlier. So you as a
JavaScript developer do not have to worry about this. Memory allocation
and deallocation automatically happens behind the scenes, and you have no control over
that. You cannot tell garbage collector when to run and what
variables to remove from memory. So based on some complex algorithms,
this garbage collector runs in the background, it figures out
what variables are not used, and then it will automatically
deallocate their memory.