So you have learned a lot about
objects, now let's take a look at a few of the built in objects in
JavaScript. The first one we're going to look at is the math object.
So here in Google let's search for JavaScript math
the first link is on developer.
mozilla.org, this is your first reference for learning about all the
objects in JavaScript. So let's take a look at the math object,
you can see this is one of the built-in objects with properties
and methods for mathematical constants and functions.
So if you scroll down you can see the properties, for
example one of the useful properties is math.PI
so this is the pi number. We have a bunch of other properties here,
and below them we've got all the methods, the first one is
absolute, which returns the absolute value of a number so
if you give it a negative number, it returns it's positive value.
So there are a lot of methods here, I'm not going to go through each of them, it's really a waste of
your time and my time, all I want you to know is that we've got this math
object built into Javascript, so in your applications if
you ever have to deal with mathematical calculations, just come
back to this page and see what methods we can use. In this lecture
I'm going to give you a quick demo of a couple of these methods, the first one
is the random method. So, let's take a look,
for each of these methods we have a comprehensive
documentation along with examples.
Really, really easy. So here in the console, lets
call the random method. So every time we call
this method we get a new random number between 0 to
1. Now if you want to map this to a given range you need a simple
mathematical formula. Back to the documentation for the
random method, if you scroll down from the list of examples,
we can see this example. Getting a random number between two values.
So basically you need a function like this, that takes a min and
max, and generates a random number between these two values.
Pretty self explanatory, you don't need more explanation. Another
useful method is math.round, so we can give it 1.
9, and it returns 2. We also have
math.max. We can give it a bunch of arguments, and it will
return the largest number in the list. Now later in the course
this is going to be one of your exercises. So you're going to write a
function like the max method here, that takes a very (?) number
of arguments and returns the largest value. We also
have math.min which returns the
smallest number in this list. So I leave it npm to you to look at all the
methods available in the math object.