In the
last lecture you learned that /n adds a new line to a string.
Now what I don't like about this approach is that it doesn't allow us
to visualize what the output looks like. In other
words, if we log message on the console, we can see this is what the
outcome looks like, so on the first line we have this is my, and on the second line we have
first message. But when writing code, our string
looks different. Now if you want to make this string similar to what
the output looks like, we have to do something like this. So,
we break this string into 2 parts, and
concatenate them like this, and then we add the second
part on a new line. We can also put the first part
on a new line. And now this kind of looks similar to what we have in the
output. But we still have this /n getting in the
way creating some noise in the code. To make the matter worse,
if you want to surround first with single quotes, you'll have to
escape the single code character like this.
Again, this is very very ugly, let's log this one more time,
very very ugly and noisy. That's where template
literals come in the picture. So far you have learned about different kinds of
literals in JavaScript. So we have object literals which are
indicated by curly braces, we have boolean literals which are
true or false. We have string literals which are indicated by
single or double quotes. Now starting from
ES6 we have template literals. Which are indicated
by the back tick character. This back tick
character is the character before number 1 on your keyboard.
So let's see how template literals help us write cleaner code.
I'm going to define another constant, but this
time I'm going to use a template literal instead of a string literal.
So, we add the back tick character, this is
my, now to add a new line, we don't need to add backslash n here,
we can simply add a line break and then type first message.
So we can format our string the way we want it to look
like. So now, let's log message,
and another. See? What we
have in code looks very similar to what we have in the output.
Now we can also put this on a new line, now if you want to
surround first with single quotes we can simply add them here, there is no
need to escape them. Because we have used a different character
to define our string. So save the changes, one more time,
message another, they look identical
but compare this code with the former code.
This is particularly useful if you want to send out email
messages in your application. For example, let's say you want to
send an email to the user like this. Hi John,
Thank you for joining my mailing list. Regards,
Mosh. So we can format our string exactly the way
we want it to look like. There is no need for any of these
plus or /n characters. So, let me delete all this
stuff. Now, another benefit of using template literals
is that here we can add placeholders. So let's say we want to
add the name dynamically, with a regular string we'll
have to do something like this. So message,
we set it to hi, then we have to concatenate this with
some variable or constant, that we define name
here set it to John, now we'll have to concatenate
this message with name, then add a comma, then /n
this is really, really ugly. Let me show you a better way.
With template literals, we can add a place
holder using a dollar sign and curly braces.
Now inside these curly braces we add an expression. We can pass
the name of a variable or a constant, now let's save the changes,
let's take a look at another, you can see we've got
John here dynamically. So this is a placeholder
for our name constant. Now here we can add any kind of expression.
We can also add a simple mathematical expression,
like this, let's log this one more time,
so, Hi John 5.
So technically we can add any expression that produces
a value in between the curly braces. We cal also
call function that returns a value, and that's perfectly valid. So
these are the benefits of using template literals.