And
finally, the last built in object we're going to look at in this section is the date
object. Now just to clarify, the objects that we're looked at in this section
they are not the only built in objects in JavaScript, there is more and you're
going to learn about them as we go through the course. So let's see different ways
to create a date object. We can create date1
set it to new date, so date is a constructor
function. Now when you open parenthesis here, you can see
this number here, 2 of 6, that shows
different versions of this date constructor. You can use
the up and down arrows to cycle through these,
so we can use the date constructor without any parameters,
and this returns the current date time. So let's rename this to
now. Let's create another
date object, new date, we have another
constructor with 1 parameter called value, which can be a string
or a number which is the number of milliseconds from
January 1st 1970 or another date object.
So here I'm going to pass a string
let's say May 11 2018,
9 AM. Now this format is not the only format
that you can pass here, if you want to find out about all possible formats that are
supported, simply search for JavaScript
date, on this page, if you scroll
down, here under date
String, you can read about various formats that are supported.
And finally, another way to create a date object,
is by passing numbers. So here we have another
constructor, with these parameters, year, which is a number,
month is also number, and then so on. So I'm going to pass 2018,
now the confusing thing about isDate objects
is that month is 0 based. So, 0
represents January, and 11 represents December.
So we're going to use 4 for May. The third parameter
is the date parameter, and that's the day of the month. So,
11, next parameter is hour, so
9 am, and minutes is 0. Now we can exclude this argument,
because all the other the arguments are initialized to 0 by default.
So this is how we create a date object.
Now, all these date objects have a bunch of get and set
methods. For example, now.get
so get date returns the day of the month. getFull year.
getHours, milliseconds, minutes, so on. We also have
set methods. So, let's call set
FullYear and change the year to 2017.
We also have set date
hours milliseconds, minutes and so on. Alright, now,
let's see how we can display this on the console. To save the changes,
all these date objects have a few methods for
converting them to a string. You can call toDateString
and we get a string like this. So Thursday May 11
2017, note that we changed the year on line 6.
We also have toTimesString which returns
the time component of this date object, and
another useful method is to ISOString which returns a string
like this. So we have date, then T, and
time, this is a standard ISO format, and it's commonly used in
applications, so if you're building a web or a mobile app that talks to
a back end. This is the format you commonly use to transfer date
between the client and the server.