So in the
last exercise we used the object literal syntax to initialize
an address object. In this exercise, I want you to initialize an
address object, first using a factory function and then using
a constructor function. So your exercise is to write two different functions
one is a factory function, the other is a constructor function, to initialize
an address object. So go ahead, and when you're done come back, continue
watching.
Alright, first I'm going to do the factory function,
so factory functions simply return a new object,
here we can call this function createAddress
we should give it three parameters, street, city,
and zipCode, and here we simply return
a new object. With three properties. Street,
which we set to the street argument we received. Now as I told
you before, if key and value are the same, we can make our
code cleaner by dropping the value, so in this value we're going to have
these three properties.
That's it. So that's our factory function, and we can simply create
a new address like this. So Instead of using the
object literal syntax we call createAddress
and give it these three values. Now,
let's log the address in the console to make sure it's working
okay, here we have a new object, with these three properties.
beautiful. Now let's write the constructor function.
So, constructor function. As I told you before
constructor functions have a different naming convention, so
instead of camel notation that we use in factory functions.
Here we use Pascal notation, so the first letter of the
first word should be capital. So we're going to call this function
address. Again, we're going to pass three parameters,
Now here instead of returning an object, we're going to use the this keyword,
to initialize this new object, so
.this.street we set that to the street argument
then this.city and finally this.
zipCode. Now to create
a new address object using this constructor function,
here we use the new operator and call
our constructor function. Once again we pass these values.
And log this address object in the console. So save
the changes and we get the exact same object.
So the purpose of this exercise was to help you get familiar
with the syntax for creating factory and constructor
functions. In the next exercise we're going to look at
object equality.