In the last
lecture you learned how to use the object literal syntax to create an object
but there is a tiny problem here. Imagine you want
to create two circle objects, so, I'm going to copy
this code here, and call this second circle
object circle 2. Now the problem that we have here
is that we have duplicated the implementation,
of the draw method, so right now it's a simple method
with only a single line of code, but what if we had 10 lines of
code here. You wouldn't want to repeat all these lines here, because if you
bug in this method, then we'll have to fix it in multiple places.
And also take into account that our circle object currently has only
a single method. What if we had 10 other methods here?
We don't want to duplicate or repeat all that logic, alright?
So, if our objects have logic, we need a different way to
create objects. That's when we use factory or constructor
functions. In this lecture you're going to learn about factory functions
and we'll look at constructor functions next. So I'm going to delete
this second circle and show you how to create
a factory function. So factory function,
just like a factory producing products, these factory functions
produce objects. So we define
a function and call it create circle.
Now we're going to move
this definition of the circle object inside
our factory functions so you have a circle object here,
finally we need to return this. Now one way is to
return it like this, but we don't really need this circle constant defined
because we are not going to reference it anywhere, we only want to return it.
So we can make this code shorter by removing
the circle constant and simply returning
this object. So whenever we call the create circle function
we'll get a circle object. However, we have
hard coded these values here, so every circle that is created by this
function, it's radius will be one. That's not what we want, we want
to have a circle with a bigger radius. So we want to pass
radius as a parameter here. So radius and then
instead of hardcoding 1, we want to set the value
to this radius argument that we supply when calling this function.
Similarly we can add another parameter here
like location, and instead of hard coding this object here,
we simply set location to this location argument.
However, for simplicity, I'm going to remove these two properties.
Location and is visible, so we can focus on
the core of factory functions. So, let's delete these properties,
we don't need the location parameter either, now we can make
this code a little bit shorter. So in modern JavaScript
if our key and value are the same, we can make our code
shorter by removing a value and simply adding the key.
So that is exactly equivalent to this code.
Alright? So that is better, next we have our draw
method, there is also a shorter syntax to define this method,
so instead of defining it as a key value pair, we can
define it like this. So draw parenthesis
and a code block. This is similar to how we
defined a function outside of an object, right? So if you want to
define a function, this is how we define it, right? So we have the
function keyword, then the name of the function, parenthesis, and code block.
Now when we put this inside of an object, basically we're dropping the
function keyword and simply adding this inside
of the object. You can see that this syntax is a little bit shorter than
here. So let me delete this. And move
this console.log statement in our draw
method. So now we have
a factory function, we can simply call this
to create a circle object. So I'm going to define this constant
circle1, and call the create
circle function, and pass 1 as the radius.
Now let's log this circle object on the console. So circle1,
save the changes, so you can see radius is set to 1,
we also have this draw method, so we can
call circle1.draw and
here's our draw message on the console. Now the beauty of this
factory function, is that you have defined our logic
in one place. So we can call this function with different values
or different arguments, we get different circle objects but we have
defined the draw method only in 1 place.
So if there is a bug in this method that we need to fix in the future, there is a
single place that we need to modify. So I'm going to create another circle object,
circle2, createCircle
I'm going to pass 2 as the radius, let's log this on the console.
Circle2, save the changes, look we have 2 different
circle objects and a single definition of the draw method.
So this is all about factory functions. But factory
functions are not the only way to create objects, we can also use
constructor functions, and that's what you're going to learn next.