And finally
the last exercise for this section. Here on Yelp.com
we have these price range buttons. So we've got inexpensive
moderate, pricey, and so on. If we want to implement
this concept, using objects, what properties do you think
those objects should have, that's the four on this exercise.
So I want you to create an array of objects each object is what we call
a price range object. It's one of these objects here. Now here we
have 4 price range objects, in this exercise we can create
only 3 price range objects. Think about the properties
that each object should have. So pause the video, spend a couple of minutes on this
exercise, and when you're done come back and see my solution.
Alright I'm going to create an array called price ranges
in this array we're going to have three objects,
each object should have 4 properties, one is the
label that we display to the user, like a dollar sign.
The second property is a tooltip
so here when I hover my mouse over each button, you can see
a tool tip. So for each price range object
we need this tool tip property. Let's call this inexpensive.
Now we need two more properties and with
this we can determine the minimum and maximum price of a meal,
per person. We can call them
minPerPerson or maxPerPerson.
So for this object I'm assuming that the average price of a meal per
person falls between 0 to 10 dollars. And this is
important for filtering. Because if we are building an application like
Yelp, somewhere we need to store the list of restaurants. So,
we might have another array here,
restaurants. In this array we're going to have restaurant objects,
and each restaurant object should have this property. Average
PerPerson. Let's say the average per person is 5 dollars.
Now when it comes to filtering, let's imagine that the user
only wants to see inexpensive restaurants, so
this is the object that we're going to work with, and in this object we can see
the price per person is between 0 to 10 dollars. Now
we want to filter the list of restaurants and pull out
those where the average price per person is between
these values. So that's the whole point of having
these two properties, okay? Now similarly we can create two more
objects, we just need to change the value
of these properties. So here we have the moderate price range
let's say that's between 11 and 22 dollars, and
finally the last one is going to be expensive
with price per person from 21 dollars to
let's say 50 dollars. So I hope you successfully
completed this exercise, if not don't worry, there are a million
examples out there for you to practice. Whenever you're using an application,
look at the features of that application, look at the concepts, and imagine
if you wanted to model one of those concepts, using an object
what properties would you put in that object?
The more you practice this, the easier it becomes. And that brings us to the end
of this section. I hope you enjoyed this section, and thank you for watching.