In this
lecture you're going to learn about another pattern for creating objects.
That is a Constructor Function, so
just like the factory function, we're going to create a function, and
the job of this function is to construct or create
an object. However, the naming convention
we use for constructor functions is different. So the naming convention
we have for factory functions is what we call camel notation,
so the first letter of the first word is lowercase, but the
first letter of every word after is uppercase. This is what
we call camel notation. So it looks like this,
camel notation, you've got 1, 2, 3, 4
You can see the first letter of the first word is lowercase.
And these upper case letters, look like camel humps, that's why we call it
camel notaton. In contrast, we have another notation that
is called Pascal Notation, and in this notation, the
first letter of every word should be upper case. So
OneTwoThreeFour. You can see the pattern right?
Now, when naming constructor functions, we should use Pascal
Notation by convention, because that's something other JavaScript developers
expect when they read your code. So we're going to call
this function circle with a capital C. Note that
I did not call this create circle and you will see that in a second.
Now, just like our factory function, here we need to add a parameter, radius
however, instead of returning an object,
we're going to use a different approach to initialize an object.
In JavaScript, we have a keyword called
this. And this is a reference to the object
that is executing this piece of code. You're going to see that in a second.
For now, just imagine this references an empty object.
Now you know what with dot notation, we can access
properties of an object, we can read a property, or we can set a property, so
on this new empty object, we want to add a property
called radius, and we set that to this radius argument that
you receive here. So in JavaScript our objects are dynamic.
Once we create them we can always add additional properties or
methods to them. So here we are adding a new property but
empty object. Now similarly, we are going to use this
approach to add a draw method to this new empty object.
So this.draw, but we set this to a function
and in the body of this function we simply do
a console.log of draw. Now finally
in order to create a circle object using
constructor function, we're going to define a constant called
circle and here we're going to use another keyword,
that is new, circle, and pass
1 as the radius. What is happening here?
Well, when we use this new operator here, 3
things happen. This new operator creates an empty
JavaScript object. Something like this. Constant, x,
set to an empty object. That is happening under the hood, but you don't see
that. Next, it will set this
to point to this new empty object. So in this code
we have access to this empty object, and we set this
radius property as we left the draw method in this new object.
Finally, this new operator will return
this new object from this function, so it looks like
this. Return this. We don't have to explicitly
add the statement here in this function, this will happen under the hood.
So let me recap, when we use the new operator,
3 things happen, this operator first creates an empty object
then it will set this to point to this object
and finally it will return that object from this function.
So what we get here is that new object, and we simply set the circle
to point to that object. Now let's see the difference
between factory and constructor functions.
Though with factory functions we create an object like this.
Constant myCircle here we call createCircle
and pass an argument. So with factory functions,
we simply call a function and in this function we return a
new object. In contrast, with constructor functions
we used the new operator, and instead of returning an object,
we use the this keyword. Also in terms of
naming convention with constructor functions we use the Pascal naming
convention, but in factory functions we use
the camel notation. So you might be asking which approach or which
pattern you should use to create new objects. Both these patterns are
equally good for creating new objects, the constructor function
pattern is familiar to developers who have some experience
programming in languages like C# and Java. So
with this pattern you can see that we're creating a new circle.
Alright, if you don't have any experience in languages like C# or Java, you might want to go
for a factory function. There is really no difference between
these two patterns, however, there are some discussions online by some
strongly opinionated developers comparing these to patterns, my
suggestion to you is do not get hung up on these discussions, they're just a waste
of time, pick one pattern, and just stick to that.