One of the
confusing concepts in JavaScript is here functions
are objects. So this circle function we have here,
is actually an object. Don't believe me? Let me show you. So
circle. look, these are all the
members of the circle function or circle object.
So the purple icons are methods, like call, bind, and apply,
and the blue icons are properties. So let's take a look
at a few of these members in the console. Here in the console
circle.name,
that returns the name of this function. Circle.length
returns the number of arguments, now
earlier in the last lecture I told you that every object in JavaScript
has a constructor property, and that references the function
that was used to create that object. Now here's the interesting part,
who do you think, created this object?
Let's have a look, so circle.constructor
so here we have another built in constructor called
function, and when we declare a function using this
syntax, internally, JavaScript engine will use
this function constructor to create this object.
Let me show you. So, I'm going to define
a constant called Circle1, to separate from our
circle. Set it to new Function, now here
our function requires one parameter, radius, so we
add that here as a string. Now as a second
argument, I'm going to pass the code
inside of this function. So to break it up into multiple lines.
I'm going to use the back tick character,
and then simply copy all this code
and put it here, so, when we declare
a function internally, it's represented like this.
Now we can call this circle 1, just like calling our
circle function. So, we can create a circle object
by sewing up circle1,
and pass 1 as a radius, save the changes,
now in the console, let's log circle. Look,
it's a real circle object with these two members.
Now let's take a look at a couple methods that are available in your
functions. So I'm going to delete all this code,
Circle.here we have this
call method, and with this we can call a function.
Look at the arguments. The first argument,
is this argument. Here we need to pass
an empty object and this will reference
this object that we pass here. Okay? Now
after that we add our arguments explicitly, so here
we have one argument, we pass 1, if we had multiple arguments
we would pass them explicitly like this, okay?
So, this expression is exactly
like expression on line 11,
when we use the new operator, this new operator will internally
create an empty object and pass that as the first
argument to the call method. And this object
will determine the context of this, so,
this will reference this object. Earlier I told you that if you
don't use the new operator, this by
default will point to the global object which is window. So,
if I want to rewrite this expression in this way,
instead of passing an empty object, I would pass window.
Of course we don't want to do this, I'm just explaining to you what happens
under the hood. So, let's revert this back,
so the first argument here, specified the target
of this. Okay? Now we have another method
called apply.
It's exactly like the call method, with this we can call a
function, but instead of passing all the arguments explicitly
we pass them in an array. So this is useful
if you already have an array somewhere in your application, and you want to pass
an array as the second argument to the apply method.
So this is the takeaway. In JavaScript, functions
are objects.