In JavaScript we have two
categories of types. On one side we have value types,
also called primitives, on the other side we have
reference types. So in the value types category we have number,
string, boolean, symbol, which is new
in ES6, as well as undefined
and null. These are the primitive or value types. On the
other side we have objects, functions, and arrays.
So in the last lecture you learned that functions are also objects.
The same is true about arrays, so in a nutshell in JavaScript
we have primitives and objects. Now in this lecture, I'm going to show you
how primitives and objects behave differently, because this
is absolutely important for you to understand, before we move onto the next section
where I talk about prototypes. So on
this empty canvas, I'm going to define two primitives,
x and y. I'm going to set y
to x, so here y is 10, now I'm going to change
the value of x to 20, what I want you to note here,
is that x and y are two independent variables,
so, let's save the changes, go back in the console,
let's log x, x is 20, and y
is 10, they are independent. So when we work
with primitives. This value, this value that we have here is
stored inside of this variable. When we copy that variable
that value that is stored in the variable is
copied into this new variable. So they are completely
independent of each other. Now let's see what happens
if we use a reference type or an object here. So I'm going to
change this to an object that has a property called
value. And then instead of saying x
to 20, I'm going to set x.value to 20.
So save the changes, back in the console,
let's log x so you can see value property is 20,
now let's log y, you can see the value property of y
is also 20. So this is the takeaway. When we use
an object, that object is not stored in this variable.
That object is stored somewhere else in the memory, and the
address of that memory location is stored inside that memory variable.
So then when we copy x into y,
it's the address or the reference that is copied. In other
words, both x and y are pointing to the same,
object in memory. And when we modify each object using x,
or y, our changes are immediately visible to
other variable. So here's the conclusion. Primitives
are copied by value, reference types or objects are copied by
by their reference. Let's take a look at another example.
So I'm going to define a function
called increase that takes a number,
and here we simply increase this number by one.
Let's declare a number
variable and set it to 10. And then call increase
and pass this number. Now, if I
log this number on the console, what do you think
you'll see? Let's have a look. So save the changes,
we see 10. But didn't we increase the number,
well, when we call increase and pass this number variable
it's value is copied into this
parameter that is local in this function. So this
variable here is completely independent of this
other number variable. Here in this function, we increment this number
by 1, so it will be 11, but after this function this number
is going to go out of the scope. So when we log
this number on the console, we're essentially dealing
with this first number. So I told you that primitives
are copied by their value. So here we're dealing with two independent
copies. That's why you see 10 on the
console. Now let's change this to a reference type or an object.
So, I'm going to change 10 to an object, that
has a value property. Okay? Let's
rename this variable to object, and
similarly, anyone rename the parameter in this function
to object, and then increment object.
value. Now when we log this on the console,
what do you think we're going to see? We're going to see 11. See?
We got this object with value 11. The reason for this
is because when we call increase and pass this object.
This object is passed by it's reference. So this local
parameter that we have here will point to the same object
that we defined here. So in this case we are not dealing with
two independent copies, we have two variables that are pointing to the same
object. So any changes we make to this object will be visible
to the other variable. So remember this, in JavaScript
we have value types, also called primitives, as well as
reference types which are objects. Our primitives are
number, string, boolean, undefined and
null. Primitives or value types are copied by their value
reference types or objects, are copied by their reference.