Now with that we had a thorough look at all the core types and the types good basics you hopefully now
understand how we create and the sign types how we assign types to variables and two parameters and
why we do that.
How.
Type assignments and types could differ from javascript type checks that JavaScript uses runtime types
and typescript uses static types that mattered during development that the built javascript code Dale
for does not include any type assignments.
It of course includes any type checks because dad is regular javascript code but something like this
year does is simply not allowed in JavaScript does not support its syntax.
That's typescript only so that's hopefully clear.
And then we had a look at numbers strings boolean ends at function types and setting return types argument
types and also describing the type of an overall function which can be helpful if you want to have a
variable that eventually holds a function.
We had a look at objects and arrays and E numbers and how that can be interesting and help you the same
is true for tuples.
And now we also had a look at aliases type aliases where you can merge complex types into aliases which
you can reuse.
We had a look at literal types and union types which can be useful for scenarios where you expect more
than one possible type.
And now at the end we all had a look at unknown and never which are niche types but still in their niche
they can be very useful.
And now with these basics we'll dive deeper into individual aspects and of course also explore other
types and JavaScript constructs where typescript can be helpful.