When working with
complex expressions, one thing that you need to account for is the
precedents of operators. Let me show you an example.
So, let's declare x and set it to 2,
plus 3 x 4. What do you think is the
result of this expression. Well, let's log this and have a look.
So, we get 14. The reason for that
is because the multiplication operator has higher
precedents so this expression is evaluated first, so 3
x 4 is 12, and then the result is added to 2.
Now, all these operators you have learned in this section, they have their own
precedents. It's really hard to memorize which operators have
higher precedents or lower precedents. So when working with complex expressions
you can use parenthesis to determine how these
operators are applied. For example, here we can put parenthesis
around 2 plus 3, and this means this expression
is evaluated first, so we get 5, and then the result
is multiplied by 4. So now if we save the changes we get
20.