The second
category of operators we're going to look at is assignment operators.
We have already seen an example of an assignment operator. So here,
we are using the simple assignment operator to assign a value
in this case 10 to x, but we have a few more
assignment operators. Let me show you. So in the last lecture you learned
about the increment operator. With this we
increment the value of x by 1. This expression here is
exactly equivalent to this.
So, we read the value of x, add 1
to it, and then using the assignment operator, assign this new
value to x. But what if in this example
instead of adding 1 to x we want to add let's say
5. Well, this increment operator will not work.
So, how can we do that. Well this is one simple way, but we have
a short hand, we can use the addition,
assignment operator like this. So line 5,
and line 4 are exactly the same. Here's another example.
Let's imagine we want to multiply the value of x by 3. So,
we can write it like this, x = x
times 3, or we can use, v
multiplication assignment operator like this. So all the other
arithmetic operators you learned about in the last lecture,
addition, subtraction, division, multiplication, and
the remainder operators, all of this have a combination
with the assignment operator.