Alright now
let's take a look at comparison operators. As the name implies
we use these operators to compare the value of a variable with some
thing else. So here we have x set to 1,
let's look at the first comparison operator, that is greater
than. So we want to check if x is greater
than 0. I'm going to save the changes, look what we get,
true. So the result of an expression, that includes a
comparison operator is a boolean, it's true or false.
Now, let's look at another example,
this second operator is greater than or equal to
so we can change 0 to 1 to see if x is
greater than or equal to 1. Obviously it is, so
save the changes to get true again. The other operators are
very similar. So we have less
than as well as less than or equal to.
Now let's save the changes. Look at what we get on the console.
So the third item is false, because x is not less
than 1. It's less than or equal to 1, that's why we got
a false here. So these 4 operators we have here,
you refer to them as relational operators.
We also have Equality operators,
so we can check to see if x is equal
to 1. So we have triple equal signs.
Save the changes, obviously x is 1, that's why we get true.
Now if you want to check if x is not equal to a given value,
you replace the first equal sign with an exclamation mark.
So, let's save the changes, the result of the last
expression is false, because x is equal to 1.
So these are all the comparison operators in JavaScript.