In
the last lecture you learned about the equality operator.
Now technically in JavaScript we have another equality operator,
that is indicated by 2 equal signs instead of
3 equal signs. So you might be wondering what the difference is.
Well, first of all what we have on the top is what we
refer to as strict equality operator.
What we have on the bottom is what we call lose equality
operator. Now this strict equality operator
ensures that both these values we have
on the sides of this operator have the same type and same
value. What do I mean by that? Well, in this
example, on both sides of this operator we have two
numbers. So their type as well as their value are equal. So
if you save the changes, we get true and true.
Now, let's take a look at another example, this time,
I'm going to change one of these numbers to a string. Now if I
save the changes, this expression is going to evaluate to false
because here we're comparing a string to a number.
So the types here do not match, that's why we'll get false.
Let's have a look. Save, and here's false, right? So
the strict equality operator ensures that both uprand
are of the same type and of the same
value. Now loose equality operator behaves differently.
So, to focus on this operator, I'm going to comment
out these two lines, so here we're comparing one with
one, and we get true. Now, what if
we compare 1 as a string with 1.
We still get true. In contrast,
in a previous example, we got false. So let's see what's happening here.
In this case, this operator looks at the value on the left side.
Here we have a string, so it will automatically convert
what we have on the right side, to a string, so it will
look like this, and now because these values are exactly the same,
we get true on the console. Now what if on the
left side we have a boolean, well, this operator,
looks at what we have on the left side, because it's a boolean, it will automatically
convert the value on the right side to a boolean. So, it's like
comparing true with true. And if you save the changes,
again we get true. So here's what you need to take away.
The strict equality operator ensures that both
values have the same type and the same value. The loose
equality operator doesn't care about the types matching, if the types
don't match, it will convert the type of what we have on the right side
to match what we have on the left side. And then it will only check
if the values are equal. Now most of the time,
we should be using the strict equality operator, because it's more
precise and accurate.