In the last lecture
you learned about logical operators, in all the examples you saw
in the last lecture, we used these logical operators with boolean
values. But in JavaScript, unlike in many programming languages,
we can use these logical operators with non boolean values.
And that's extremely powerful. Let me show you a few examples.
Let's say we have false or true. What do you
think is the result of this expression? Well, it's true, right?
Now what if we have false or
the string Mosh? What do you think is the result of this
expression? Well let's take a look, we get Mosh back
what if we have false or number 1?
We get number 1 back. So here's the first thing you
need to realize, the result of a logical expression is not
necessarily a true or false. That depends on
the value of the operance we have. In the first example
our second operand is true, that's why we get true back.
In the second example, our second operand is a string, that's why we get
a string back, and by the same token, in the third example.
We get a number back. So when our javaScript engine tries to
evalue this expression, it looks at each operand
if that operand is not a boolean true or false, it will try
to interpret it as truthy or
falsey, so in JavaScript we have
is values which we refer to as Falsey, that's not
boolean false, it's falsey. What are
these falsey values? Well we have undefined
null, number 0, the boolean
false, and empty string and
not a number. Now we haven't talked about this yet, that's going to come
later in the course, for now, just remember, not a number
is a special value in JavaScript, and when we are dealing with a mathematical
calculation that does not produce a valid number,
this value is returned, not a number. Now we're going to look at that later in the course,
so don't worry about it. So these are the falsey values
in JavaScript, if we use any of these values in a logical expression
they will be treated as falsey, which is kind of like
a boolean false, but it's not exactly the same. Now,
anything that is not falsey is truthy.
So, back to these examples.
In the second example, our second operand is a string with
4 characters. So this is not an empty string, it's not
falsey, so it's truthy. So when our JavaScript
engine tries to evaluate this, it looks at the first operand
it's false so the search continues because with a logical or
operator, as you learned in the last lecture, as long as one of the operands
is true the result will be true. Now here in the second
example, the first operand is false, so the search continues
hoping that maybe the other operand is true or
truthy. In this case we are dealing with a truthy value, so
this value is immediately returned. The same goes for
third example. So here one is not a boolean true, it's truthy,
that's why the value of this operand is returned.
Now, what if we have an expression like this, false
or 1, or 2. What do you think we're going to get?
Let's take a look. You get 1. So this is another thing
you need to understand about the logical or operator. The evaluation
starts here, as soon as we find an operand that is
truthy, that operand is returned, so here our second operand is
truthy, it's value is returned, and here the evaluation stops.
It doesn't matter what we have on the right side, we could have a million other operands,
they are completely ignored, this is what we call
short-circuiting. Short-circuiting. That's
exactly like short circuiting that we have in electricity.
Now that you understand how these logical operators work with non-boolean values,
let me give you a real world example on when to use this. So
let's imagine an application, and
somewhere the user has to pick a color, or we're going to use a default
color. Maybe this is the color of the t-shirt they want to buy. So,
I'm going to declare a few variables, userColor.
We set that to red, defaultColor
we set that to blue, and currentColor,
which we set to userColor or
defaultColor. Now let's read this exprsssion
in plain English. userColor or defaultColor
that basically means if we have a value for userColor
we're going to use that, if we don't, we're going to use the defaultColor.
Now, let's log this on the console. So currentColor
we get red. Because our user
has selected a color. In contrast, if the user
has not selected a color, let's set this to undefined,
save the changes, we get blue.
Because defaultColor is blue. So this is the power
of using the logical or operator, between nonbooleans.
With this technique, we can provide default values.
So if the user has selected a color, we're going to use that
otherwise we're going to use our default color and that determines
the current color which we are going to display on the screen.