And that is already it for this module.
Now obviously there are tons of third party libraries out there you could use.
There also is more you can explore on the class validator and class transformer packages.
But the idea here is not so much to dive and do all the features of these packages.
I rather leave that up to you to explore.
The idea is that you get a feeling for two important things.
The first thing is Dad with typescript you can use regular javascript packages like low dash without
issues.
You might get errors initially.
Keep in mind that technically it works though.
But you can also work around these compilation errors then by importing the right types.
The right translation from javascript to typescript in the end and such translation packages exist for
all major and popular and even a lot of small javascript libraries.
You also might be working with javascript libraries which have these translation files.
These DTA s files built in already.
They are of course you don't need to install such translations thereafter.
Well and besides these vanilla javascript libraries which might need translations you also might have
libraries like class transformer which work fine in vanilla javascript in modern vanilla javascript
at least where you also have classes but which all the work without any extra translations and types
of projects.
And then we have packages like CLOs the validator they really embrace typescript specific features and
give you a brand new way of thinking about your project and of solving certain problems.
In this case here by utilizing decorators knowing all these things is super important and gives you
all the flexibility you need for your future projects.