In the last module, we had a look at how to add third-party packages. In this module,
I kind of want to stay in the world of TypeScript project management or projects, workflows and so
on.
We're going to have a look at how we may integrate TypeScript into various workflows, including a
pure TypeScript compiler usage workflow where we only use the TypeScript compiler and see how we can configure
that to work really nicely, how to integrate it in a Gulp workflow
if you were to use Gulp as a builder tool or as a last option, how to integrate TypeScript with webpack
so that any of your projects under control of webpack could be enhanced by adding TypeScript to it.
So let's have a look at these three options and how to use TypeScript there
in this module.