Consider TypeScript workflows in this module, I want to start with a pure TypeScript workflow.
So without a task runner like Gulp or a bundler or a dependency management system like webpack
but instead with a pure TypeScript workflow, a set up which might be all you need for a lot of projects.
I loaded the JQuery project where we simply use JQuery to help give this text some styling here.
So a very basic set up
and if you remember this, we import some typings to let TypeScript know where to find its JQuery
dependencies here and we're using SystemJS in the index.html file to
load JQuery here in the end.
What we also do is we simply compile our TypeScript code by running tsc,
so this compiles the app.ts file to the app.js
file here which then gets loaded in the index.html file.
Well this tsc command, by using this, we're basically using TypeScript as our only workflow tool,
right,
we don't have a task runner watching for any changes and then recompiling or something like this,
we're doing this with the tsc command and I showed you earlier in this course that the first thing which is
very important or which is very helpful is that on the tsc command, you can add the -w flag to enter
watch mode which basically means we're now watching all TypeScript files for changes
and whenever we make such a change, well we will re-trigger compilation,
so compilation will then run automatically without us having to run tsc which of course is a great convenient
enhancement in our workflow and something you definitely want to use when only using TypeScript.
But while this is nice to know but a pure TypeScript workflow also means that you have to understand
how the tsconfig.json file, the place where you configure your TypeScript project actually works.
And with works,
I'm not talking about compiler options here,
I already had a look at these in the module about the TypeScript compiler and I explained some additional
options throughout this course
and really again, I already pointed towards the official documentation regarding these options because
there are just too many and a lot of them
you will probably not use that often, to go through them step-by-step.
Now what I want to consider this module though is this exclude node here or generally, how we can control
with the tsconfig.json file which TypeScript files in your project should get compiled.
So let's have a look at this.