So what does the tsc command do
if we run it like this? Well it basically looks for the tsconfig.json file and then read said
to learn how it should behave.
Now here in this sample, tsconfig.json file which is pretty much the default tsconfig.json
file you automatically create by running tsc --init, in this file
here, we learn that we got some compiler options and then we have the exclude node.
Now what this file tells the TypeScript command, the TypeScript compiler command is that it should compile all
TypeScript files in this folder, except for any files in the node_modules folder, which we can see here,
which basically holds the lite-server and so on and the set up.
So all other files in all other folders in this project folder will be considered during compilation.
This is the reason why in our app.ts file, we automatically detect the JQuery typings which
live in the typings folder,
remember we set them up in the third-party modules module in this course. We never import the index.d.ts file
which refers to the JQuery typings, we never import this in the app.ts file,
it gets found automatically by TypeScript simply because we only specify what not to include, the node
modules folder but all other folders are taken into account and therefore TypeScript recognizes
OK I have this app.ts file,
it's the only ts file so I'm only going to compile this file,
if we had other ts files, it would also compile those files and then it also finds the .d.ts files
Now it won't compile them because it recognizes that .d.ts is not a file that should be
compiled but a file which holds some definitions and should be taking into account during compilation and
it does so, it takes this file into account which then references the JQuery typings in this case here
and therefore, it knows about these definitions when compiling the app.ts file here.
So this is how it knows how to work with your directory, with your project and which files to take into
account and therefore by simply adding exclude here, we'll let TypeScript do the rest for us and only
tell it what not to use.
Now why do we exclude the node_modules folder?
The reason for this simply is
there are a lot of third-party libraries or packages by other creators and we probably don't
want to recompile those,
those packages should ship in a finished mode, in a finished version.
We don't need to recompile these packages,
so we definitely want to exclude them.
We are including certain things like JQuery explicitly with the import statement here, which then
again of course is used or is considered when compiling this here but it's not recompiled because we
don't want to do this.
An alternative to excluding would be to instead explicitly tell it what to include,
we can do this with the files node here.
So we're simply adding files which would then also be an array,
now in this array we could simply tell TypeScript to use the app.ts file.
Now if I now run tsc,
it only takes the app.ts file into account
which is why I get this error that we can't find dollar sign because now all of a sudden, the typings
in the typings folder here are no longer considered, those .d.ts files here are no longer considered
because they are not automatically scanning for all the ts or .d.ts files,
we're only considering the files I specify here
and that's just the app.ts file.
So one way to get this working is to simply add the typings folder and then the index.d.ts file which
basically holds the JQuery typings
and we may also specify the extension here of course.
So if I now run tsc again,
we now no longer get the error because now the typings in the typings folder are again taking into account
but we tell TypeScript explicitly that we want to do this.
So this is how you can control which files are taken into account when you run the tsc command, with files
and exclude, you can control what you compile and what to include in the compilation step and what not
to look at.
Again if you want to learn more about this, you can also check out the official documentation where some
additional examples are given and the exclude and files node is again explained, also add how the compiler
behaves when looking for files.
Generally, you should keep in mind that if you don't specify the files node here, it will take all files
into account,
then you can be a bit more precise by adding exclude and for example excluding the node_modules folder,
so a complete folder and all its files in this folder by just specifying the top root or the
top level folder here and that you can be specific with
the files node and just tell it what to use, which files to specifically use
if you don't want to use the more general approach taken here.
It really depends on your project, which set up you want to use, tell it which files to take into account
or use all files and only exclude some folders, like in this case here.
Generally, it will always look for .ts and .d.ts files, so these definition files here when compiling
your project.