Now there's one other approach to compile files,
you can also run tsc and then target a specific file, app.ts
for example.
Now if we do this, then we only compile this file and as, you can see I'm now getting the error that
we can't find the dollar sign symbol anymore.
Now this error makes sense because we're only targeting one file,
it doesn't care about other files now,
it's like if we were to just specify in the files
node here, this single file and then run tsc, the same thing happens if we use a specific file here
when running the tsc command.
So if you target a specific file, your tsconfig file will not be used,
it is ignored because you're just compiling one file.
If you still want to pass some compiler options, well then you have to simply use it and or use these
options with their flags like you see them here in the leftmost column.
You can chain those flags to the command, like for example here if we wanted to make sure that we use
source maps, we could scroll down and learn that we have to use --sourceMap and this would
allow me to use the same as if I were to specify source map through here.
So it is important to keep in mind, if you target only one file, you can't use your tsconfig.json
file.
Now what if I want to run tsc but my tsconfig.json file is not positioned in the root folder?
So let's say I have a folder named config here and my tsconfig file would live in this config
folder here,
so now if I run tsc, I get an error that we don't find a tsconfig file and this of course makes
sense because by default, TypeScript doesn't scan your whole computer for this file,
it only scans the folder in which you're running the tsc command,
so which is the root folder,
the project folder in this case.
You can still tell TypeScript where to find the tsconfig.json file by simply adding
--project or just -p after the tsc command and then the path to this file.
So in this case, the path would be config and then tsconfig.json.
If I run it like this, you'll see the command now runs without any errors because it now finds
the tsconfig.json file again. So I'm just reverting this and moving it back to the top level,
getting rid of the config folder
but this is important to know and to understand, how you can tell it where to find your configuration
file
if you are using a pure TypeScript workflow.