Sometimes you want to integrate TypeScript into your workflow when you are using a task runner like
Gulp.
So in this video, I want to show you how to do this how to combine TypeScript with Gulp.
For this, I will make or I will set up a simple Gulp workflow here by simply installing as a development dependency,
Gulp and then in order to use Gulp and TypeScript together, gulp -typescript. So by hitting enter,
both packages will get installed which allows me to set up a very basic Gulp workflow where I then can
integrate TypeScript.
So now, I will then as you will learn no longer use the tsc command but instead, use Gulp to compile
my TypeScript code.
Well let's see how this works.
I will first add a Gulp file of course to configure my Gulp workflow, the task runner. Here
I need to import Gulp of course,
so let's require Gulp here and I will also import TypeScript or specifically, gulp-typescript here, like
this.
Now gulp-typescript is a wrapper around TypeScript,
we can look at it on the official npm page of gulp-typescript or the Github page which you can simply
find through Googling if you're interested.
Here you will find a description on how it works, how to configure it which certainly is very interesting
and you will also learn that it wraps TypeScript, so that it contains the TypeScript compiler and
simply adjusts it to work in a Gulp workflow but it works the same way as the normal TypeScript works.
It is the normal TypeScript, just wrapped to work with Gulp in the end.
You will also learn how to use the options you can specify which you also learn about in the TypeScript
handbook and how to use them here in the Gulp workflow.
There are some options like watch which are not supported because you should use gulp.watch
but I will show you this.
So this is TypeScript or specifically, gulp-typescript which you can use here in Gulp
and then we also want to use our tsconfig.json file.
We're not using the tsc command anymore but we want to use the compiler options which we set up here,
so in order to use this file, I go to my Gulp file and here what I do is I add another variable and
I'll name it
tsProject to simply give this a name fitting to the project configuration here
and I use the TypeScript package, so the gulp-typescript package and here, the createProject method and
now to this method, you pass the path to your tsconfig file.
So here since both the Gulp file and the tsconfig.json live in the root folder, I simply pass
the file name but you would pass the file path here,
tsconfig.json.
So with this, I can now run the Gulp task here,
set up a Gulp task and I'll name it TypeScript, typescript like this.
Now in this task, what I want to do is I want to return tsProject,
so using this tsconfig.json file, source and I don't specify a source here because I want
to use the automatic file resolving of the TypeScript compiler,
so with the exclude and files node. You can overwrite this, you can of course target individual files here
and resolve your files
through Gulp and you can also learn more about this here in this article or in this page about
gulp-typescript
but here I will simply target all the TypeScript files as we did before by simply letting the TypeScript
compiler handle this
and then I pipe another workflow or another task and here I want to use ts, this is the gulp-typescript
package, so the TypeScript compiler and I use it like a method and to this method,
I again pass tsProject.
So while this might look strange, what happens here is we're basically telling gulp-typescript or we're
telling Gulp here
please use the tsconfig file which is connected to the TypeScript compiler of course since we connect it
here and then resolve all the files, the tsconfig.json file,
things we need to compile. Again, we're configuring it with exclude and the files
node here and in the next step, then use the TypeScript compiler and compile all these files, taking
the tsProject which again is this tsconfig file into account.
So compile it whilst using the options specified in the tsconfig file.
Now as a last step,
also adding it here with pipe, as a last step, simply output it here in the root folder,
this is why I pass an empty string because I want to keep all the paths like we found them here,
so we're outputting it here.
And of course fine tune this to your needs,
it's impossible here to set up the perfect workflow which will fit to any of your projects.
You will still use Gulp like you always used it,
you can still use it to pass in specific files here and pass them, pass an output path here.
You can also pipe other tasks, like bundling or uglifying
and again, definitely have a look at this description at this article here to learn more about how to
combine your gulp-typescript workflow here with source maps and with bundling and so on.
This is just a very basic workflow to show you how to integrate gulp-typescript and use a tsconfig.json
file which is of course key.
So with this task set up, I can now add another task which I'll name watch which is my watcher task and
all I want to do here in this closure is I will simply run gulp.watch and I will watch any TypeScript
files for changes in my project here and we'll then run the TypeScript task, like this.
So this will basically do the same as before with tsc -w
but now through Gulp.
Now the final thing I will do is, I will set up a default task and when running just Gulp,
I just want to run watch mode.
This is my very simple Gulp file,
again you could integrate this with your more advanced Gulp file, with uglifying, bundling, compiling CSS,
the TypeScript compilation is just one step in this workflow and you learned how to use the tsconfig
file,
how to use the file resolving through the tsconfig file
but again let me tell you, you don't have to use the tsconfig file for this,
you could also specify specific files and again, you will learn more in the official description or documentation
on this TypeScript package.
So with this Gulp workflow set up,
I'll go to my package.json file and add a very simple script which I'll name build and here I
will simply run
Gulp.
Now with this set up, I can run npm run build and now this will enter watch mode and if I now change this
to red for example here and save this, you see it recompiles
and if we then also restart the lite-server with npm start, you now see it is red and
again if I change this to something else like blue, it will trigger the recompilation and change tthis
to blue here too.
And this how you can integrate Gulp or TypeScript into your Gulp workflow, again
fine tune it to your needs.