Maybe you want to integrate TypeScript into your webpack workflow.
Now here again of course it depends on your specific workflow, how you want to configure all the details
but in this video, I will show you how easy it is to get webpack to compile your TypeScript code.
Now in order to show this, I will install webpack here as a development dependency and I not only need
webpack, I will also install the ts-loader and as the name implies,
this seems to have something to do with TypeScript.
It's a loader or you will use or you can use in webpack to compile TypeScript code.
So I'll just hit enter here to install both packages
and once these packages are installed, it's time to start configuring it.
Now the first step I will do is I will get rid of all the SystemJS related code here in my index.html
file because since we're using webpack now, we're no longer using SystemJS to load our files, instead
webpack will do all this and bundle the files for us.
So this is not the only change
therefore, what I will also need to do is get rid of the SystemJS import up here and now I will
simply import a bundle.js file which of course doesn't exist yet but webpack will create this
for us.
A next step is in the tsconfig.json file,
now I no longer need the exclude path here because now since webpack will handle all the bundling, importing
and compilation, webpack will automatically resolve for us which files it needs to bundle and we no longer
need to configure this here in the tsconfig.json file,
we also can get rid of the source map since webpack can do this for us and we may also get rid of the module
key here since we no longer need to compile our code to use any Javascript modules because we
don't use a module loader like SystemJS anymore,
again instead webpack will import all files we need and bundle them for us, so we may use a set up
like this which only has some compiler options which we want to use.
Now with this set up, I will add a new file,
the webpack.config.js
file which will hold my webpack configuration of course.
Now I will set up a very simple configuration here, one to show you how to easily compile your TypeScript
code.
I will of course export a Javascript object in this file as you always do in your webpack configuration
files
and then I need to specify an entry here.
Well the entry should be my app.ts file,
so this will be a relative path to app.ts.
I then will add output,
this is an object of course
and here I simply one to output anything or everything into a bundle.js
file
also in the root folder, of course you can fine tune this to your needs
and in the next module which is about ReactJS and TypeScript, you will also see a more
advanced or a slightly different version of this webpack.config file in the next example
to suit the needs of a ReactJS
setup
or project
but here I'll keep it simple and just show you how to compile your TypeScript files.
So this is the basic set up for entry and output files, as a next step here,
I will add the module key and this is again an object where I have my loaders. Now if all of this is
brand new to you,
definitely have a look at the webpack configuration because this is not TypeScript specific here.
So in my loaders, here of course I will only use one loader defined as a Javascript object where I
want to test all my, this should be forward slashes to have a regular expression where I want to test all
my TypeScript files, like this.
So this will make sure that all TypeScript files or all files ending with .ts are run through or are
compiled with this ts-loader here.
This of course is the loader we installed as a development dependency and this loader uses
TypeScript.
Now with this setup, we're done,
this is the very basic setup we need.
Now if you're also having a project where you are importing other TypeScript files, you might want to
add module resolution or the file extension resolution to automatically search for .ts files
if you import something like import JQuery and this were a jquery.ts file actually, you might want
to add the respective configuration here in the webpack config file to automatically tell webpack
that it should look for .ts files and you will see an example for this in the next module
when we implement or when we use TypeScript together with ReactJS, which is why I am keeping this a
bit shorter here.
So that is the very basic set up to compile my app.ts file here with webpack.
Now with this set up, what I can do is I can go to my package.json file and add two new scripts here,
for example I can add a build script where I want to run webpack -d and then maybe
--watch to enter watch mode with webpack and I can also add a build prod workflow,
of course these script names are all up to you where I simply run webpack -p
to well use webpack's production set up to create my bundle without any source maps or stuff
like this.
Well let's try this,
if I now run npm run build here,
select this, run build, we enter watch mode but I get an error that we can't load
TypeScript.
Now this might sound strange because we certainly have TypeScript installed, we used it all throughout
this course, right?
Well the reason for this error is that the ts-loader doesn't use our global TypeScript installation, it
looks for a local one and with a local, I mean a project specific one which has the huge advantage that
if we have different versions, let's say in our project we're using TypeScript version 1.7 and globally
we have version 1.8,
we're not interfering with this,
we will always use our local project specific version.
So in order to get our ts-loader to work, I will simply install, as a development dependency, TypeScript
like this and this is the TypeScript version the ts-loader will then use.
So if I now run npm run build, we're almost there
but no I get this error regarding JQuery
and the reason for this of course is that now we're no longer having our SystemJS set up where we tell
it where to find this JQuery package,
we're only importing JQuery here right, like this.
Now this of course would resolve to a jquery.js file by default which isn't found,
so that's something we're going to have to fix,
besides that we can see the bundled files were created,
so this works. We can simply fix this by changing our import statement here a bit. By default, webpack
here
use the ES5 import syntax or the
NodeJS import syntax to be specific. So we can simply tell it that we want to import the dollar
sign which we want to import with the require keyword
and here we just use JQuery, you like this.
So using require webpack will search through our node_modules folder where we of course have a JQuery
folder and it will done automatically find the file we need to use to import this and to get this to
work correctly.
So this is just the node_modules or the NodeJS import syntax which webpack knows and by adjusting it
like this, we get this to work.
So if I now run npm run build, you will see that it now bundles this correctly
and if I then also run npm start to run lite-server, we see it running though we don't see that this
would change the background color.
Now to finally fix this, what I'll do is I will move the script import to the end of this page
to only import it and run through it once the page has been completely loaded
and if I save this, you now see we get the styling,
we don't get any more errors here when compiling this
and you see, we are also in a watch mode.
So if I change this to green, it will recompile and change this to green here too.
And this is how we have a very basic webpack workflow
and if I remove these two files here, the files created through webpack and run npm run build prod,
you will see that the production workflow also works,
it now only creates our bundle.js file which is now also minified and so on and we no longer have
the source maps
and this of course is a very basic webpack workflow. As you see,
we have a very lean config file.
If we were to import other files than the JQuery package, so if we were to import our own files in the
app.ts file, again we might need to use or we might need to add the configuration here in the
webpack config file
to let webpack know that it should also consider .ts files when importing
since we don't specify the file extension here in the import, which we could also do though.
But again, you will see this in the next module when we use TypeScript with ReactJS
which is why I keep this relatively short.
So here, we got a very basic workflow, using webpack, specifying an entry point, creating a bundle and using
ts-loader together with a local TypeScript version which we installed here to compile our TypeScript
code and to make TypeScript work in our webpack set up.