In this lecture, we're going to have a
closer look at the this keyword in JavaScript, this is one of those features
that confuses a lot of developers, but honestly, I think it's because
of the poor teaching materials out there, because I personally was
confused about the this keyword for a long time. So in this lecture I'm going to
make it super simple for you, so you can explain it to your 7 year old brother.
So what is this? This references the
object that is executing the current function. Here I'm going to
give you a very simple rule of thumb. If the function
is part of an object, we call that function a method, right? So if that function
is a method in an object, this references that object
itself. Othewise if that function is a regular
function, which means it's part of an object, this
means the global object, which is the window object in browsers
and global in Node. Let's take a look at a few examples.
So, I'm going to start by creating a video object,
in this object we're going to have a title property and
a play method. Let's log this
here, and finally call video.play.
Save the changes, so we get our video object
on the console. So in this example, because
play is a method in the video object, this references
this object itself. By the same token, we can add
method later in this object, and we'll get the same result. For example,
we can add a stop method here, set it to a function,
and here we can do console
.log of this, if we call the
stop method, once again we're going to see the video object
on the console. So save the changes and here is our
video object. Because again, stop is
a method in the video object. So that's an example
of the first rule. Now let's take a look at an example of
the second rule. A regular function. So let's delete
this, and instead add a function called
playVideo. If we log this
on the console, we're going to see the global object which is window
in browsers and global in Node. So let's call this function
playVideo and save the changes so we get
the window object here. Now what if this is a constructor function?
We call the constructor functions using the new operator.
So, let's rename play video to video
with a capitol V, that's the convention for constructor functions,
now here we're going to pass a title property,
and set this.title, title. Now we can
use this constructor function to create a new video object.
So we use the new operator, save the changes,
oops, I forgot to pass a title here, that's the title,
so, what do we get here, instead of a window object,
we get a new object. The note that this object is not, this video
object here is completely separate. To demonstrate this I'm going to change
this argument to b, so, instead of the window
object, we get this video object,
because earlier in the course I told you that when you use the new operator
this new operator creates a new empty object
like this, and sets this in this
constructor function to point to this empty object. So,
here on line 12, we add the title property to this new object.
So let's recap. When dealing with a regular function,
this by default references the global object,
but if you call a function, using the new operator, which is the case
for constructor functions, this will reference a new
empty object. Now the last example.
I'm going to clean up this code. Let's add
another property in this object, tags, we set it
to an array of 3 strings.
Now let's rename the play method to showTags
so here you can use this to get the current object,
and then get the tags property, because this is an array
we can call the forEach method, and here we need to pass
a callback function. So function, in each
iteration this function will get a tag, and then we can
display the tag on the console. So console.log of
tag. Finally, let's call video.showTags.
Save the changes, so we get a, b, c. Beautiful.
But what if we want to display the title of the video next to
each tag? Well, you can add this.title
here, save the changes, you've got undefined.
What's going on here? Well, let's remove the title
property and see what this is referencing.
Save the changes, it's referencing the window object, but aren't
we inside a video object here? Shouldn't this
reference the video object? No, because here we are
inside this callback function, this function is just
a regular function. It's not a method in the video object.
The only method we have here is showTags.
So because this is a regular function, this
references the global object. So it's the global object that is executing
this anonymous callback function. But how can we
solve this problem and display the title of the video next to each tag?
Well, we have a few different solutions for this, in this
particular case, the for each method has two parameters,
the first parameter is our callback function, the second parameter
is thisArg? So
we can pass an object here, and this will reference that
object. For example, here I can pass a new object,
the firstName, set to Mosh,
now when we save the changes, we can see this
is referencing this new object. Now in this example, we don't really want
this object, we want our video object. So we can pass
this here. Because at this point, we are
in the showTags method, so this references the current object.
So here we are not inside of a callback function.
We are still in the execution context of the showTags
method. So now if you save the changes,
next to each tag we can see our video object with this title
property, so we can add the title property here,
and with this, we see the title of the video next
to each tag, beautiful. But not all methods in JavaScript
give you the ability to pass the this argument.
So we have a few different solutions for that, and that's the topic for the next lecture.