Now
it's time to practice what you've learned in this section. So here's your first exercise.
I want you to create a function called some that
takes a varying number of arguments, and returns their sum.
We can pass 1 argument or 2 or 3 or more. So here
we should get 10. So do this first, then
challenge yourself to modify the sum function to be able
to accept an array and still return the same
result. Now as part of this challenge, you need to
detect if the argument is passed is an array.
To do that, we use array.isArray method.
So let me how you how this works. We can call array.
isArray. If we pass an array object, we get true,
if we pass anything else like a regular object we get false.
So pause the video, when you're done, come back and continue watching.
Alright, let's create this function called some.
Now to have a varying number of parameters, we use the rest operator.
So...items. Now we can pass as
many arguments as we want, and this spread operator will convert
them all to an array. So we have an array
to get the sum of items in an array we can use the reduce method.
So, items.reduce, we pass an arrow function
a and b, goes to a + b,
and finally you return the result. Now, let's call
this function, so console.log, of
sum of 1, 2, 3, 4, save the changes,
we get 10, beautiful. Now let's work on the challenge.
So if you pass these arguments in an array,
with the current implementation, instead of getting 10, we
get the array itself. Let's see why this is happening, so,
in this function, I'm going to log items,
save the changes, so items is an array of
arrays. Note here we have an array, and the first element
within this array is this array of numbers. Because I told you
that the rest operator converts whatever we pass here into an
array. So because we are passing an array of 4 numbers.
This rest operator will put this array inside of
another array, and that's why we don't get the sum of these arguments.
How can we solve this issue? Well we need to check to see
if this items array has a single element, and the first
element is an array itself. So,
you can do something like this. If items
.length = 1. And
you want to see if the first item is an array, so array.
isArray, we pass items of 0, if
that's the case, we need to flatten this structure. So
instead of having an array of arrays, we want to have just an array of
numbers. How do we do that? We use the spread operator.
So, you reset the items to a new array
and we use the spread operator to spread items of 0,
which is another array. That's the array we have here, right?
Now, let's save the changes, we get 10,
beautiful, so, we can pass an array to our function,
or individual arguments, and either way we get their sum.