This
second exercise is pretty easy, it's just to help you get used to the syntax.
So I want you to create a circle object using the
object literal syntax. Now this object should have a
radius property that we can read or write to, for example, we can set
circle.radius to 2, we should also have
an area property that is read only. So we should not be able to set
the area from the outside but we should be able to read it.
For example, we can do a console.log of circle
.area. So, spend a couple minutes on this exercise,
you can see my solution next.
Alright, so let's declare
a circle object. We can give it a radius
initially, now to create a read only property,
we need a getter. So we use the get keyword,
here's the name of our property, but actually it's implemented as
a method. Now here we need to return math
.PI times this.radius
times this.radius. Okay?
And finally we can do a console.log of
circle.area, save the changes,
so this is what we get if we change radius to a new
number, and then read the area
we get something different, but we cannot set the area from the outside.
Because this is a read only property, we don't have a setter here.
Now to prove this, even though here I set the area to 20,
if I read it again, you can see it has the old value
that is computed based on this formula.