In
the last lecture we assume that the value that we receive here is a
valid string. But what would happen if we pass
a boolean here? That doesn't make sense, right? So let's run this code
we get this error. Uncaught type
error, value.split is not a function. Because
split is a method that belongs to strings. Booleans don't have a
split method, right? What would happen if we pass null
or undefined? Save the changes, we get a different error.
Cannot read property split of null. Again, for the same
reason we cannot call the split method on a null, it's only available
on a string. So here we need to add error handling.
Typically, in situations like this, we should do error handling
at the beginning of a function or a method, this is what we call
defensive programming. So we want to make sure that the values coming in
are valid, they're in the right shape, so we can execute
our logic. So, the first line of this method should be something like this.
You want to make sure that this value is a string. So,
we can use the type of operator, with type of value.
isNot String, then, when simple appraoch
is to return and with this we'll no longer see
this error message here. Save the changes, so we can see the person object
with the original first name and last name. So what we passed here
null did not take effect. But sometimes we want to report an error
in our application. That's where we need to throw an exception.
Throwing an exception is a technical jargon that you might here in a lot of
programming languages. So let's see how that works in JavaScript.
So instead of returning from this method, use the
throw keyword and then create a new error object. So new
error, that looks familiar right, so error
as a constructor function, because here we have the pascal case.
And we're calling it, we're calling this function using the new operator
to create a new error object. Right? Now,
as an argument we can pass an error message. So
value is not a string.
This is how we throw an exception, now
some people confused errors with exceptions, but there is a slight difference between
the two, here we can create an error object,
let's call it e new error. This is just a plain JavaScript
object, there's nothing special about this. But the moment you throw
this error, we refer to that as an exception. So this is an exceptional
situation that should not have happened. Okay?
Now, in this method, we have some basic error handling,
so this method is throwing an exception, now somewhere else we need. to catch
that exception, we need to catch that, and quite often when we catch an
exception, we display an error to the user, so this is how
we accomplish this. Line 15 is where we receive
this exception, so we need to wrap this line, in a try block,
so, try, we move this line here,
so try block can have
1 or more statements, one of these statements at least can
throw an exception, now, we
add the catch block after, in parenthesis, we give an
identifier, this is the error object that we are throwing
here. So in the catch block we can get that error object and
do something with it. So here,
we can display it on the console, but as you know this is only
visible to developers, so an end user will not see this error, so
temporarily we can use the alert function, this is not something I'd
recommend you to do, because that's a very old and poor way of reporting errors to users.
The proper way is to display a label, perhaps a red label on
the user interface, but that's a topic for a future video, so for now
let's just use the built in alert function. Now,
save the changes, and here's our
alert. Value is not a string. Now,
let's take this to the next level. Instead of passing null, I'm going to pass
an empty string. Save the changes,
we don't get any errors, but first name is an empty string and
last name is undefined. Hm, again that's not desirable.
So, ideally we want to make sure that our user is typing a first name
and last name. So, when splitting that string,
we can check the length of this array, so,
if parts.length is not 2,
that means something is missing. So here we can throw another
exception. Throw new error,
with a different message. Enter a first and last
name. Okay,
now, save the changes, and here's
our new exception. Enter a first and last name. So,
basically when we throw an exception, the lines after the
throw statement are not executed. Will jump out of this method
and the control will move to the catch block. Here we catch
the exception, and do something with it. So this is the basic of error
handling in JavaScript.