In this lecture
we're going to talk about a very important concept called scope.
So I'm going to define a constant called message
and set it to hi. Now let's log this in the console
so obviously we get hi on the console.
But what would happen if I add this message
in a code block? Let's save the changes and see what happens.
We get this error. Uncaught reference error, message
is not defined. This is all about scoping.
So a scope of a variable or a constant, determines
where that variable or constant is accessible.
And when we declare variables or constants with let or const,
their scope is limited to the block in which
they are defined. So message is accessible in this block,
but it's not accessible outside of this block. Now you might be wondering
why do we need this code block here? Well, this code
block can be part of a function. So here we can have a function
called start. And now we have a constant
in this function. So because the scope of this constant is
limited to the block in which it's defined, we cannot access
this constant outside of the start function. The same
is true when we declare a variable or a constant in an if block.
So, let's add an if block here, some condition,
we don't care, let's declare another constant,
and set it to bye. Now, this constant is
only accessible in this block, if I go out of this block,
and try to log it on the console, we're going to get an error.
So, I'm going to remove the last line, let's just call
the start function. Save the changes, we get the same
error. Reference error. Another is not defined. We have the same
concept in our loops. So let's define a for loop,
let i = 0, we're gonna run it
5 times, now i is a variable
that is only accessible in this block. So here,
we can log i, let's save the changes,
we get numbers 0-4. But if we go outside of this for block,
and log i, we're going to get the same
error. Reference error, i is not different.
Now, let me simplify this code. So we're going to have
a function with a constant called message. We can
have another function, let's call that stop. And in this
function we can have a constant called message, with
a different value. That's perfectly valid JavaScript code.
Because the scope of this constant is limited,
to the block in which it's defined. So we can have two variables or
constants with the same name but different functions. That's perfectly
valid. Now, what if we defined a variable or a constant
outside of a function. So here I'm going to define a
constant, color, and set it to red. Now here we don't have
any code blocks, so what do you think is the scope of this
constant? This constant has global scope. Global
means this constant is accessible everywhere, globally.
So we can go to the start function and log
color, save the changes you can see we have
access to this constant, color, so this constant
is accessible in all the functions we have in our programming.
Now what if we have a constant with the exact same name,
in our function. So let's take a look, I'm going to define
this color constant, we'll set it to blue.
What do you think we're going to see when I save the changes, let's take a look.
We get blue. So, local variables, or
local constants in a function, take precedence over
global variables or constants. Now in general you should avoid
defining global variables or constants, that is considered
bad practice. Let me give you a metaphor. Imagine this is a tooth
brush, and each function is a person. You don't want to have
a tooth brush that is shared with multiple people. Each person should have
their own tooth brush. So you should avoid defining global variables
or constants because they're accessible everywhere, globally, and
each function can accidentally change their value, and this will lead to
all kinds of bugs and issues in our programs.