In this course will obviously learned a lot about TypeScript and you'll all learn how to work with TypeScript
and third party libraries like lo Dash.
Now there is a very popular third party library which you might be interested in using to gather with
TypeScript and that is react react.
J.S. is a extremely popular javascript library for building amazing user interfaces and you can use
it with typescript as well.
It's not the default in most react projects.
You don't work with typescript but you can absolutely do that.
And in this course module you will learn how it works.
Now a little disclaimer at this point this is not a react course I will not teach react here.
This module is for you if you already know react and you want to learn how to use TypeScript and react
not if you don't know react and you want to learn both TypeScript and react to gather.
But with that let's dive right in and let's see how we can build a reactor up with typescript.