Now to finish up this application let's add some styling attached to find a new to do C S S and a To
Do List C S as file simply drag and drop them into your components folder and then in New to do t is
x.
Let's import dots slash new to do dots see us s.
This uses DB behind the scenes project setup we have here which will pull out that C is US code and
then add it to our single page H TO MAIL file we're using and in new to do component on the div also
add a class here with the class name prop of form dash control and with that added in to do list of
course import that dot slash to do list C is as follows.
And with that once you did that you should have something that looks like this.
And there we can now add finish the course finish it in one month.
It does looks a bit nicer I'd say we all have the working buttons of course still and that's our finished
application here.