So in this module we had a look at react and TypeScript and as you see typescript here again can add
a lot of nice extra features and checks that make sure that we write clear an error free code.
Now I did show you a couple of very important pattern stare and a couple of very important react features
like props and state and how to use them with typescript.
I also showed you how you should think about adding other functionalities like redux which we didn't
use in this module.
And as I also mentioned at the end of the last lecture don't forget about all the other things you learn
about in this course all the types you learn about and all the things you can do with typescript including
the configuration here everything you learned applies to this react plus types could project as well.
Just because we had a nice configuration out of the box here does not mean that you can't tweak it you
can tweak it and you can use everything you've learned in this course here in this project because after
all even though we're writing some reactive code and we can use J as X we're still writing javascript
or specifically typescript code and data for everything you'll learn from this course is valid here
as well.
It's easy to forget that so always keep it in mind.
And with that consider creating your next react project with typescript.
You know certainly know how to get started and how it works.