In this module let's dive into classes and interfaces.
Now the concept of classes might not totally be new to you.
Classes also exist in vanilla javascript in modern vanilla javascript at least.
But if you haven't really worked with modern javascript then you might not know classes or if you're
relatively new to jobs so you might also not know about them yet.
So I'll introduce you to classes in this module as well and entirely new in JavaScript world at least
our interfaces.
So in this module we'll explore what these things are and why we use them.
Then we'll have a detailed look at classes and they are all that our concept called inheritance and
add interfaces what they bring to the table how they're compile to JavaScript and why we might use these
features.