Now that's it for classes.
We learned about classes themselves.
We learned about their properties the Axis modifiers private for internal axis protected for internal
axis.
Also inheriting classes and public for axis from everywhere.
We also learned about methods which we can add about static methods and properties about abstract methods
and abstract classes which is important when we talk about another important concept.
The inheritance which we can use here we're inheriting from the apartment with the X tense keyword.
This allows us to share functionalities properties and methods from the Department class with this inheritance
class and add our own functionalities or override existing functionalities ever because we have to overwrite
as in the case of describe which is an abstract method or because we want to override like in the case
of an employee here in the accounting department.
That's not an abstract method.
In the base class.
But of course we still can override it if we want to.
We also learned about the Singleton pattern and private constructors which can also be useful sometimes.
And therefore overall you now hopefully have a good idea of classes and what you can do with them and
typescript in general of course you need to know what classes and objects and all to bid what prototypes
are about in vanilla javascript because that's generally not something introduced by a typescript but
of course something typescript is related to because typescript builds up on these default javascript
features and adds its own magic on top of these features.