Now instead of an interface you can also add the read only modifier.
You can not add public or private or anything like that.
This is not possible on an interface but you can at read only to make it clear that this property in
whatever object you built based on this interface must only be set once and is read only thereafter
so that it can't be changed off.
Do you object has been initialized.
This is also something if we use a type instead which you can use on a type if you want to though.
So again these two things are very similar here but it's more common or seen more often that if you
will really want to work with an object you use an interface for that and read only just one other thing
you can add there as an extra feature you can set up with read only added here by the way you see I
didn't added here in the class I didn't add read only here and still if I now go to User 1 and I try
to set name to something else I get an error here already because it's read only.
And of course I also get that if I save it and it tries to compile that so the interface is really having
an effect here once we implemented into our class even though I didn't add read only here the class
knows that it implements readable and it automatically assume state the property name which we have
here which we need to have because of the interface is read only because that is what we set up inside
of the interface.
And that's of course pretty convenient as well.