There was a lot of talking about interfaces and classes now.
Now let's look under the hood and see what javascript actually produces or offers as an alternative
to interface.
We learned that four class code Indiana depends on the word you were compiling for if you compile for
iOS 6 year in it he has conflict then our output would use the class keyword since we compile 4 is 5
here We instead see this work around using constructor functions in the end.
What however happens for interfaces.
Well let's have a look at the app J File and there you see nothing.
You'll not see any translations for our interfaces.
Add a friend named readable you don't find these things anywhere in app J.S. you just find our function
here you find our constructor function for the person object.
So basically that translation for the person class anti Abra code you find no reference at any interface
and there's a good reason for that.
There is no translation for interfaces javascript doesn't know about this feature.
It's a pure typescript feature only available during development and compilation so you can use it to
improve your code.
No output for that will end up in your javascript files though so therefore it's a pure development
feature helping you to write better code.
Clearly structured code following clear rules at runtime no trace will be left of these interfaces.
You'll not see anything related to the interfaces in your code only functions classes and all the other
code is compiled and output interfaces are simply dumped.
You could say they're used during compilation to check your code and then they're ignored.
There is nothing that would be output for them.