TypeScript 2.0 also gives us some nice new features regarding classes.
The first feature I want to show here is about private constructors,
now this certainly might sound strange,
let's have a look at it.
I added a class here and this class uses a static property instance here which is private, which is
the first thing which might look strange since
what's the sense of a static property which is private,
we can't access it from outside,
right?
The second and even more confusing thing is the constructor here,
it's also private
and now this really makes no sense at all because how can we use a class if we can't construct it, if
we can't create an instance of it
and we need a constructor for that. In all the code above when we use the new keyword like here,
we were using our class or/and the constructor
each class has to create a copy of that blueprint this class provides us. Well turns out here we're having
a pattern which is called a singleton class,
you could already create this before, without these private accessors, like that.
That was possible before
and this allows you to set up a class where you only want to have one instance during runtime.
This pattern is something you see in a lot of languages, it's nothing TypeScript specific,
a lot of or all object-oriented languages offer this pattern and it might be useful if you know
well I want to have an instance of this class and not a static class but I only need one instance because
I want to have, let's say an array of data in this class and this array has to be the same in my
whole application.
So that would be where you use such a singleton
and again, you could create this before but now since you can mark constructors as private,
you can force this class to only be used as a singleton, which means you can't instantiate this class
from outside anymore.
Indeed if I run tsc here, you'll see that I get an error that the constructor of class OnlyOne is
private and only accessible within the class declaration.
So this code here leads to an error,
the code I need to use to create an instance can be found inside of this class in this public static
method, getInstance, which I'm calling here.
So when I call this method here, I checked if I already have such an instance, so it that if it has been instantiated
this one time I want to instantiate it and if it has been instantiated, then I simply return this instance,
otherwise I create a new instance and thereafter, no more instances will be created and I can control
this since no instances can be created from outside too due to this private accessor here added to the
constructor.