In the example from the last video,
notice that I use these shortcuts to create a property, a public property named name which I instantly
initialized here in the constructor.
So what I can do is of course, I can simply log right name since this is a public property available
and right here refers to this single instance which was created.
Now what I also can do is I can set
right
name equal to something else because it is a public property,
therefore I can access it from outside
and that not only means reading, like I do here but also setting it.
Now what if I want to make sure that I only can set it in the constructor here but not at any other
place,
so not from outside? I want to make it readable though.
Well there are two ways to achieve this,
one would be using a getter. We already learned about getters before, here.
If you don't specify a setter but only a getter,
so if we would remove this part here, then we would make this property readonly.
Well if that is our goal, we can take a shorter route and simply add readonly in front of it.
Now my IDE doesn't recognize this but this is valid code as you see if I compile this. If I do compile it,
I get an error that in line 112 which is here,
I want to assign something to a readonly property.
Now if you want to avoid nasty IDE errors like these, you can also simply take the long form of setting
this up,
so by adding it up, public name which is a string like this and then simply assigning this name equals
name here
and now if you add readonly here,
well at least my IDE doesn't complain anymore
but again, the first code also worked
and as you can see we get the same error here that we can't assign a value in this line because we're
having a readonly property.
So that's another neat addition with TypeScript 2.0.