Time for some exercises again.
Now these exercises look very complex but I think they're all very doable.
The first exercise here is about the basic class object,
nothing special about it.
The goal is to take this vanilla Javascript constructor function here which we used in vanilla
Javascript to create objects based on a blueprint and we create it in TypeScript with the class keyword.
Now I created solutions TypeScript file
and I wanted to show one possible solution to this,
so Exercise 1 - Class. Well I create the car object because we create a car object here too
and provide some or car class here and provide some information about this class.
We want to have a string or a name which is a string and we have the acceleration which should be a
number and equals zero
and of course this type definition here wouldn't be needed,
Typescript can infer the type because we set it here.
So that's the acceleration,
then we have the constructor where we pass this name
and yes, I confuse the shorter way of initializing and creating this name property.
So I set name equal to name here,
then we have the honk method
where I can hit the honk, toooooot, like that
and then I have the accelerate method where I pass a certain speed by which I want to accelerate and
then I set this acceleration equal to this acceleration
plus speed, like this,
not sped, speed.
OK,
so that's my class
and then I can simply create a new object based on this class, pass a name to it, like BMW which
yes the brand, not the name of a car
but you get my point and then, I may honk, I could also simply then log my current acceleration level,
duplicate this but before calling it a second time, I will call the accelerate method here and pass an
acceleration of 20. With all that in place, I can compile this file by typing tsc solution.ts and
have a look at the running browser where I change the import in the index.html file to solutions
Javascript and well, clear this, reload, we see toooooot, then the initial acceleration of 0 and then 20
and that is how you use all the knowledge from the previous module to create a new class with some public
properties, some public methods and a constructor with the longer way of initializing my property here
and then use all these features to create a new object, call the methods or access some properties.
So that was very basic,
just a quick refresher on how to use the class keyword,
the most important thing if you have an ES6 background there of course was that you can create your
properties directly in the class body and don't have to create them in the constructor.
Now back to the exercises,
let's have a look at the second exercise which looks rather short but is more difficult than the first
one but should be doable too,
the goal was to extend or to implement inheritance. In vanilla Javascript,
there are a couple of ways to do this because there is is rather strange concept of inheritance using
prototypes,
not really strange but less intuitive than the extends keyword in TypeScript probably.
So one way to implement inheritance in vanilla Javascript was to have the space object, then create
a new object with object create which will set base object as the prototype of this object
here, therefore I have access to width and length on this object as it is based on this object and I can
extend it by adding a new function like this here and then call this function which uses my properties
I got through extension.
So that's all nice but we can also write this in TypeScript,
so let me add Exercise 2 - Inheritance to the solution file. I want to create my base class here
or my base object, let's call it like it is,
which looks like this, has a width of zero and length
and I'm skipping the type declarations as TypeScript can infer the type. Then I'm creating my rectangle
class which should extend my base object, so the extends keyword here is key to make sure that this
rectangle class has access to width and length and it will always have access to these two properties unless
they are marked private.
It has access
if they are public or protected. So here, I then implement my new method, calcSize and all I want to
do here is I will return this width times
this length, like so. I can then create a new object based on the rectangle class, rectangle should be
new Rectangle
and I can then set the width to let's say 5 and I can set rectangle length to 10 maybe
and then I can log the rectangle or the result of the calcSize method.
So if I save this and recompile the solutions file, well we see 50 here and 50 of course makes sense
because 50 is what I log here with calcSize, since it is five times ten.
The last exercise shows how getters and setters could be implemented in vanilla Javascript even before
ES6 with the defined property method on the global object object. With defined property, we could add
new properties to an object, define the property name here and then configure the property in this Javascript
object passed as a second or
excuse me, as a third argument to the defined property method. There we could set up getters and setters
like this and actually, get and set then is not that different to the TypeScript implementation
but of course that's a very difficult way to write this and you will see that TypeScript offers a more
convenient way to set up setters and getters,
so Exercise 3 is about getters and setters.
So I'll create a new class, person here and I have this private property, _firstName which I don't want
to be able to access from outside,
this should be a string and by default, it's an empty string.
So I have the underscore here again because I'll implement a getter and a setter. The getter will control
how I can access this property
and I defined with the get keyword here, followed by the property I want to use from outside, firstName
and then followed by parentheses,
so like a method call.
But again, remember this from the module earlier or from the lecture earlier,
you don't call it like a method, you call it like a property,
it only looks like a method inside of this class here.
So here, I will simply return this firstName,
I could do more with that, I could check something, I could transform it but here I'll just return it
and then I will set up a setter with the set keyword and then also firstName, again will be accessed
like a property from outside
and of course has to match the name of the getter in this case and then I will get this value passed
to this automatically created method here kind of. Then I want to check if the length of value is
greater than 3,
if this is the case I will set this firstName equal to first name, not isFinit, to value excuse
me, otherwise because name is shorter than three characters,
yes that happens
but this person shouldn't have one.
So in this case, I would set this firstName equal to an empty string still, so basically it isn't
changed,
I could also just skip this else condition
but I want to show how you could set something in an else case. With that, I can create a new person
here, new
Person, like that and I can simply log person firstName for example,
then I can try to set the first name of that person to let's say Ma, then I'll log the first name again.
I'll also log it again but in between those logs, I'll set it again equal to Maximillian which is my full first
name.
Now if I save this and recompile this file,
I get this compilation error which is because when I compile a single file and I'm doing this with the tsc
solutions.ts command because I don't want to compile all the files which would give me other errors
because I have some duplicate names here in both files. If I only compile one single file, this
tsconfig.json does not really apply,
which generally isn't a problem but in this case, I want to make sure that I'm not compiling to the default
Javascript version which would be ES3 but instead, I want to compile to ES5 because ES5 will
support getters and setters, ES3 will not. I do this by adding the -t option and then simply the ES5,
like this,
capital E, capital S and 5. That will tell the TypeScript compiler that it should compile it
to ES5 Javascript code and not to ES3 Javascript code which therefore will work without any
errors.
We didn't have to do this earlier because if you just compile with just tsc, the tsconfig is used
in which the target is set to ES5
but for single files, we have to do this on our own here.
Well, let's have a look at the console now.
Remember this code here? Well we see this old code which is still from the acceleration and so on
and then we have nothing, empty string, empty string, Maximillian.
So the first empty string comes from this console log where I log the name
before doing anything with it and the default of course is an empty string.
So I'm accessing my getter here by calling firstName and not _firstName which wouldn't
work because it's a private property
and this just returns me the private property first name, so it works
and that is why we see this empty string.
Then I try to set a name, Ma and I'm calling firstName not _firstName
which leads me to this setter.
I pass the value, Ma and I don't make it through this check, which is why the first name still is empty
string.
And then, I set first name again or before doing that, I log it
which is why I again see an empty string,
then I set firstName again, this time to Maximillian which makes it through this check and therefore
the _firstName, this private property is set to Maximilian, which is after calling
it for the third time,
I see Maximillian here in the console.
So these were all the exercises concerning the classes here and I hope you feel comfortable using the
TypeScript class keywords and class concept by now.