So let's create a class,
we do this with the class keyword and then we can pick whatever name we want,
let's say person.
This will give us a person class
and if you are familiar with ES6 features, so far that's the same way how you create a class in ES6
and for this module of course, it really helps to know about object-oriented programming
and if you already know some other languages which use classes. I'm not going to dive super deep into
explaining what classes are and what you use them for,
basically they allow you to prepare some kind of blueprints for objects, so you can later on create objects
based on a class to then make sure that this object already has some properties or methods which again
you define in this class we're setting up here
but if that is all new to you, definitely check out some tutorials on object-oriented programming and
classes in general
and it probably is a good idea to also have a look at ES6 classes.
So enough of talking. I'm creating a class here to create such a blueprint and I could give this class
a property, name for example, which should be of type string and that already is one important difference
to ES6 classes.
You create properties just like that in TypeScript,
you don't have to set them up with the this keyword in the constructor of a class,
you assign them directly in the class body
as you might know it from other languages, like again C# or Java. You could prefix or prepend this
name property here with a public keyword and that would make this property available to
whoever wants to access it but I can leave it out since the default is public,
so this property will be public which means accessible from outside.
So I created the property on this class and I can add another one, let's say type but let's say that
I want type to be a private property, which means you can only access it from inside of this class
or later on whichever object you create
based on this class. So you can't set or read it from outside of this
and that also is a major addition because Javascript, no matter if we're talking about ES5 or ES6, doesn't
offer this kind of support or these kinds of properties,
it doesn't know private and public properties, everything is public there and you have to use some kind
of hacks or workarounds to create kind of private properties.
So here in TypeScript, I create a private property type like this and I assign a type of string to this
property.
I can also create a protected property
and what's different because protected and private? Private properties are only available or accessible
from the object you base or you create based on this person class,
so only within this object. Protected properties
also meet this definition
but additionally, they're also accessible from any objects or classes which inherit from this class.
So if we were to inherit from this person class and I will come back to inheritance later on, then
the child class which inherited from person would also have access to a protected property but not
to a private one,
so let's say we have the protected property age which should be a number here. That was quite a lot of
talk about properties but it is important to understand how you can modify them to make them available
only inside or outside of this class and it is important to understand that you set them up directly
in the class body and not in the constructor.
That being said, you can provide a constructor function which may take some arguments, like name and which
then allows you to assign this name to the name property,
so this name here refers to the property of this class, whereas this name refers to the argument passed
to the constructor. As a side note,
there is a quick shortcut TypeScript offers you for setting up a property which you also want to
set in the constructor.
Imagine we have something like a username, so we have this name and we also have a username,
then we could also say public username of type string.
Notice the public keyword here,
with that I'm telling TypeScript not only expect to get a username argument in the constructor function
but also automatically create a public property in this person class
and this could be private or protected too and assign the argument you get passed into the constructor
to this property.
So this expression here basically is a shortcut for creating a property up here, getting the argument
and then assigning the argument, put it in other words,
I could also write public name, rid of this, get rid of this and it will still work the same
but I will leave this kind of mixed set up to have a good example of both possible ways of creating
and assigning properties. Now before going more into detail,
let's use this class and I do use a class by instantiating it, which means I create an object based on
this class. I will store this object, make it a const, in this person constant here and I instantiate it
with the new keyword,
so I create a new person like this, new person.
Now of course the person here expects to get two arguments since the constructor expects to get two
arguments, as we call the constructor with this new person call here.
So I pass Max as my name and the username might be max with a lower case M,
very very creative here, I know.
So I created my person and I can then log this person to the console and I will save this and then
let's have a look at the console. You see my person here, it is of type person as you can see, it has the
username max with a lowercase m and the real name is Max with an uppercase M.
So as you can see, this uses the constructor function, it is able to assign the username here with
this shorter setup syntax as well as the name with the longer setup syntax here
and to prove this, I can also access name and username like this.
Notice that my IDE doesn't offer me type or age because both are private or protected, which means not
accessible from outside,
I can only use them inside of this person object,
I can't access them from outside like I'm doing with name or username. If I save
this, I see Max and max here because I access the name and the username
and this again proves that this shorter syntax here works too.