I already said that I can't access type and age from outside but what sense does this make to set up
properties like this then?
Well let's add a method to this person class because we can add methods too and let's say we have one
which is called printAge and this is how we set up a method, like a function without the function keyword
and printAge
should simply give me this age.
Now here, I can access age because I'm inside of this class or later on, inside of this object and private
means accessible from inside,
so I have no problem with accessing it. If I also want to set a protected or private property from outside,
I could create the setType method, of course
the name is up to you, pass a type which should be a string since the type property also is a string and
then set this type equal to type,
I can thereafter print this type to see that this worked. With these changes in place, I can call person
printAge and I can call console log person or no, I don't have to console log, I can just call person setType
cool guy because that's what I am.
So printAge and of course we would see undefined since age isn't set up, so I can initialize it up there,
that also works.
I can initialize properties right after or right when declaring them here,
I don't have to initialize them through the constructor,
I can do it up here
too. With that if I save this, it gets compiled automatically while you still see Max max, then you see my age,
so the initialization worked as did the try to access a private property inside of this class or object
and you see that setType also worked
since I see cool guy here and I printed this type after assigning it here in the setType method.
So this is how you initialize properties right
when declaring them, how you create methods which you may access from outside and how you can access
private properties inside your person class.
Now one important thing to know is that methods can also be private or protected
which serves the same purpose as private and protected properties serve.
You can't access them from outside but you can use them inside of your class.
So if you set setType to private for example, well then we could say that we want to access it whenever
we print the age and we want to set it to old guy. With that,
I of course have to remove or comment out this line here cause it won't work with private method and
if I save this, we now see Max max 27 and then old guy because I'm setting a type of old guy here and
I call this setType whenever I print the age. Also important, you have to use this if you want to access properties
or methods of an object when you are inside of it, like here in the constructor or here when we print the age or
here when we assign the type or here when we print the age.
That was a lot of talking about this relatively simple yet complex class keyword and how to create and
use classes. As you saw,
it really makes creating such blueprints of which you can create new object simple and with the
private and protected modifiers
here, you get powerful ways of controlling who is able to access your properties and methods in a class.
Another very important concept added with ES6 as well as with TypeScript is that your classes can also
inherit from each other, so you may extend classes and implement inheritance.
How?
Well, let's have a look.