So let's have a look at inheritance next. Let's say I have my person class and I want to create a specific
Max class of this person, just because well I like my name so much. So I create a class, Max
and you probably should read one matching your first name or whatever you like
and I want to use this person class,
I just want to fine tune it a little bit.
I want to have the printAge and the setType
method, I want to have all these properties but I want name to be Max by default.
Now rewriting this whole class would be not what I want because well I duplicate all the code and it
makes my code less reusable and so on,
so instead I extend the person class with extends keyword, I extend person, like this.
What this means is take this person class, use all of the code inside of it and now whatever I specify
in here gets either appended
if it isn't included in the person class or overwritten if it was included.
So if I were to say name should be equal to Max, then this will overwrite the name property in my person
class, which means that if I now create a new person or a new Max to be precise, a new Max, like this
and I print Max,
well then you see I would get an error because the constructor here still expects two arguments because
I'm still using this constructor. Again
Max, this class has all the content of the person class plus or overwritten, whatever I define here.
So I still have to use the constructor,
so let's actually see what happens if I pass
Anna here as a name and then lowercase max as a username,
let's see what happens.
You see the name is still Max, even though I passed Anna to the constructor which sets this name equal
to
Anna in this case, it gets overwritten by this property definition here in the Max class.
So the content defined in the main class here always overwrites the content of your superclass, of your
parent class,
so it doesn't matter that I pass Anna here. Nonetheless, I might have solved this issue by adding a constructor
here and I will come back to constructors in the next lecture.