So as I just said, I could add a constructor to this Max class here too
and I could do this to make sure that I don't have to pass a name here because the name is set in
stone anyways but I still need to pass the user class and somehow, my IDE is already giving me errors even
though I haven't written anything yet.
The reason is when extending a class, you always have to call super first which calls the constructor
of your parent class.
I didn't have to do that before because I didn't have a constructor
and in such a case, the parent's constructor will always be called
but if I define my own constructor, I have to call the constructor in the class
I am extending and I do this with the super keyword, super refers to the parent class by the way.
So with that, I call this constructor and I pass Max as a name here too, which of course allows me to comment
out this hard
overwriting here because I'm setting the name here anyway.
I still expect to get a username though, so I expect this input and I pass this to the super constructor.
I'm not adding the public keyword here because username already is set up as a property of the parent
class
and again, I do have access to all the properties of the parent class. So with that, I can get rid of this name
because now my constructor only expects one argument
and if I save this,
you still see my max object with the name Max, the username lowercase max and this age and this time,
I'm using my own constructor here, though I am calling the super constructor.