Now what if I wanted to change the age of my
person here?
Notice that age is protected, which means it's available in child classes too.
I wouldn't have access to type
but age is something I can access and I can access it with the this keyword and then set this equal to
31 for example. If I save this, we see that now my age is 31 because I can use age with the this keyword
as again all the content from here is also available on my Max class, though that is not true for the
type which is private, which means it doesn't get inherited,
it stays in the super, in the parent class.
So if I try to log this type here, you already see I get an error here
and I also get a compilation error here because type is private and only accessible within the class
person and not by any child classes.
So I get undefined here as an error because I don't have access to that, so definitely have to get
rid of that and here you see the difference between protected and private. I can access protected properties but
not private ones.
And of course, you can adjust this Max class to whatever you want,
you can add methods, properties, just always keep in mind you inherit everything from your base class
except for private name or methods and properties marked as private and then you can extend it by
writing your own logic or overwrite it if you happen to define a method called printAge
in this case here or a property called name as you saw earlier in this module.