Another cool feature you might know from other languages are getters and setters and vanilla
Javascript also has some ways to create getters and setters but TypeScript makes it really easy. I'll
create a new class for this,
it won't inherit from any class, it's a normal class here and I'll set up a private property called
_species which should be of type string.
Now generally, you shouldn't prefix your private properties with an underscore,
that's the style guide for TypeScript
but in this case I'll make an exception and you'll see why in a second because I don't want to be able
to access this species property from outside
but I want to offer a controlled access, which means through a getter or a setter which allow me to execute
some code before actually returning or setting the value.
So let's say whenever I try to set this value, I want to check if the string provided is longer than,
let's say at least three characters,
so I don't want to set species to anything which has only three characters or less.
So I can create a setter for that which allows me to execute some code whenever I try to set a value
and I do it with the set keyword and then species.
Now this name is up to you but this will be the property name accessible from outside later on.
I do add parentheses here but I will not call it like a method from outside,
that's important to understand,
I will call it like a property but I set it up like a method because again, I can execute some code
here, like a method which gets called. It will actually also get a parameter of type string and TypeScript
will pass this parameter for me kind of. In the end, it will be Javascript code which looks differently
anyways but you can think of this value being passed to this kind of only theoretically existent method
here automatically.
So again, I will and you will see this, only call this like a property
but behind the scenes it will give me the value I want to assign as an argument to this method that
it will execute automatically.
So here, I then want to check if the length of value is greater than 3, if that is the case,
I want to assign this species to this value, otherwise I will assign this species to default, something
like that
and I can also set it to this value up here, default value.
So that is why I have this underscore because I want to use this species name and therefore, I have
to make sure we have a different name for my private property.
Now that allows me to set it
but I also want to be able to read it.
For this, I'll set up a getter, so I'll use the get keyword with species here, again like method here
but with this time without an argument and then here, I decide what I want to return.
I do have to return something because I try to get something in the end but I could also return hello
and then I would always see hello when I try to access species, that would work fine but I can also return
this species or transform it before showing it, whatever I want to do. With that,
I set up some getters and setters and then I can create a new plant based on that and I can first log
plant.species, notice how I act species without the underscore, that refers to this
species property here which is called like a property, not like a function.
If I save this, it gets compiled and we see default here, which makes sense because we have default
as a default value. Next, if I try to set species to let's say AB,
so only two characters and then I log plant.species again,
well let's see what we now see in the console.
Well we see default twice,
so the first default here of course stems from this console log but the second default comes from this
console log.
So species wasn't set to AB because it didn't make it through this validation here,
therefore we set it to default and we did not set the value.
Now if I copy that code and set species to green plant and I save this,
well let's have a look at the console now,
now we see green plant being printed because it makes it through this check here
and therefore we assigned this species the new value which would be green plant in this case.
So that is a convenient way to use getters and setters to control access to your properties and make
sure that certain criteria are met before assigning a value or returning a value.