Typescript also allows you to define static properties or methods in a class,
so static properties and methods and I will show this here. I'll create a new class which I'll name helpers
and this class should bundle some helper properties or methods I can use throughout my application for
example.
Let's say I want to get access to pi,
so this mathematical symbol to calculate the diameter for example.
Now actually, the built-in math object already offers such a property we can access
but let's say that would not be there. Then I could create a new property called pi and this would be
of type number of course and it's something like 3.14 and so on.
Now if I defined it like this, the only way I can access it is by instantiating this helper,
however I don't always want to instantiate it.
Consider I have this calculation where I just want to calculate two times pi,
now I couldn't access helpers.pi,
that does not work because helpers is the class and not an instance of that class.
So that is annoying,
that won't work,
so that is a non-working code here.
I can make this pi property here accessible outside of this class without needing others to instantiate
the class by adding the static keyword.
That means you may always use this property, even if you don't instantiate this helper class and helper
classes actually are a good example for use cases where you would use the static keyword.
Of course, I can also provide a static method,
so we use the static keyword and then let's say I have the calcCircumference
method here which gives me the circumference of a circle.
I pass the diameter as an argument which should be a number
and of course I return a number here and in here, I return this pi, accessing this pi property here
of course,
times diamter. With this, I can do two things,
first I can call helpers.pi
if I just need pi or I could also log
helpers.calcCircumference and then pass some arbitrary diameter. Both will work as you will see if I save
this and have a look at the console,
you see 6.28 for this first console log where I simply double pi and then you see 25.12 for this calculation
here where I pass 8 as the diameter.
So that is how you create static methods and properties
and again, mostly useful for some helper classes which bundles some helper tools you want to create
for your application or any other application which uses this.