I'll conclude this class module with a look at abstract classes.
Now what are abstract classes? Abstract
classes are marked with the abstract keyword, so thereafter we have this normal class declaration and
abstract classes cannot be instantiated directly.
So what is the sense of abstract classes then?
Well, we have to inherit from them, always,
they're basically just there to be inherited from.
And why would you want to create a class which you can't instantiate, which needs to be extended?
Well maybe because this class never needs to be instantiated but only provide some basic setup other
more specialized classes which then will be instantiated need.
So let's say we have this project abstract class,
it might have a project name which is of type string,
it might have a budget which is a number and you may even assign values,
so project name might be default, something like that by default. You can also add some methods like
calcBudget which does whatever it needs to do,
let's say here it simply returns this budget times two and you can also create abstract methods, like
so, abstract keyword in front of the method name, changeName which then also may take an argument but and
that's important, here we don't have the curly braces,
we then don't have the function body, we just say what it should return,
so we only define how the function should look like, how the function type should look like
but we're not implementing any logic.
That's the difference to calcBudget for example where we do implement the logic.
So abstract on a class means this class needs to be extended and abstract on a method
then means
well once we extended this class, we need to implement a changeName method, we are required to do
so but we will have to write the logic which is executed by changeName in the child class.
So that's the difference to calcBudget which will also be available in the child class of course but
which doesn't need to be overwritten,
changeName needs to be overwritten or implemented in the first place.
So that's my abstract class
and with that, I can create a more specialized class,
let's say ITProject. An ITProject extends project,
project needs to be extended after all, it's abstract
and then here I get an error by my IDE.
The reason is this right now, I don't implement changeName,
you get the same error if you try to compile your code.
You'll see that your non-abstract class ITProject does not implement the inherit abstract member changeName,
so that's a pretty clear error message,
we need to implement changeName.
So I will add the changeName method and of course, I have to use the function type setup here, so it
will receive a name of type string and shouldn't return anything, so what it will do is it will set
this project name equal to name and of course, you would have been able to set this up in your base
class here already but I want to show how to create abstract members as well.
With that, my ITProject is set up and I can create a new project, which is a new, well project wouldn't
work,
ITProject because again, project can't be instantiated and if you try to do so and then try to compile,
you also get the error, cannot create an instance of the abstract class project.
So we have to instead instantiate ITProject and then we can log the console or use console log
new project to have a look at it,
then we can call new project changeName and change it to Super IT Project and
then we can simply log new project again.
Well let's have a look at all of that. As you see, the first console log which is here right after instantiating
it gives me a project name of default and that's the only property this project has,
right.
If I were to initialize budget up here to let's say 1000 and rerun this, then you see we now also have
budget,
we didn't see it before because it wasn't initialized yet.
Now the second thing we see in the console of course comes from this console log which is called after
calling changeName, which is why the name changed to Super IT Project,
the budget still is untouched, it's still 1000.
So again, an abstract class needs to be inherited,
it provides a base class in cases where you know that you will need such a general blueprint but that you
will never use this blueprint on its own, that you instead need some specialized versions of that blueprint
but that you want you bundle some general functionality or logic in this abstract base class.