With interfaces and generics, we had a look at two new features introduced by TypeScript.
TypeScript actually has a couple of new features,
one of them being decorators,
that is what we're going to have a look at it in this module. Basically decorators are functions you
can attach to classes, to methods, to properties and then work with these classes,
methods, properties or transform them.
So it's kind of a bit of metaprogramming and you will see how all of that works throughout this module.
Decorators basically gave you the chance of extending a class, of adding an extra functionality simply
by adding a little thing which you will see in this module to it and then all of a sudden, introducing
a whole lot of new functionality to a class for example or to a property simply by adding this
thing, this decorator.
Well let's leave the world of theory here and see it in action in the next lectures.