So that were decorators.
Decorators are really an interesting feature and they're in development, so we may see some additions
or changes to them in the future,
something of course I will inform you about in this course.
Basically, decorators give you the ability to transform certain classes or add new data to it or add
new information to it
as you saw in this course or in this module. Decorators may also be used in conjunction with metadata
and now metadata is something not really related to TypeScript, not introduced by TypeScript which is
why I don't cover it specifically here but if you want to learn more about metadata and decorators
and how you may use them together, definitely have a look at the official TypeScript webpage,
typescriptlang.org
and there under documentation, handbook
and here the decorators part. At the very bottom, you will learn more about how to add metadata with
a decorator which might be interesting to you in your project too, just as what you could do next
otherwise.
Well with that,
let's have a look at the next module in this course.