So as always, back I am in my editor here in the app.ts file, got my TypeScript compiler running and my
little server which doesn't log too much right now
and in this chapter, we'll have a look at decorators, so at functions we can add to methods or to
classes and yes, let's have a look at these decorators.
I'll start with a decorator which gets added to a class. So I might have class person here
and all I want to do basically is add a decorator which logs information about this class or as a
class decorator does about the constructor of this class.
So I'll explain it in a more detailed way in a second,
let me first create the decorator. A decorator is basically just a function you create,
so like this, name it logged for example. Now then it depends on where you want to append this decorator,
the arguments depend on that.
So I know that this will be a decorator attached to a class and decorators attached to a class will
get one argument by TypeScript.
Keep in mind, decorators are a TypeScript feature, so TypeScript manages which arguments will be passed
to a decorator depending on to what this decorator is attached to.
So I will specify this one argument which is the constructor of a class,
that's just what TypeScript passes to a decorator,
that's all that's to it.
You can't change this if you attach a decorator to a class,
it will get one argument and this one argument is the constructor function of this class. So constructor
function is what I could name it,
it will be of type function and then I can do whatever I want to do with or inside of the decorator.
So here, I simply want to log this constructor function so that we start simple and can see what happens.
Now I said I want to attach this decorator to this class
and how do I attach a decorator?
We do attach decorators by adding the @ sign and then the name of this function,
keep in mind again a decorator is just a function,
there is nothing special about this function which makes it a decorator,
it just becomes one when we append it or attach it with the @ sign. So I could attach any function
but then again keep in mind, it has to be a function which gets this single parameter if we want
to attach this decorator to a class because again, TypeScript only gives us this parameter when using
this function as a decorator on a class.
So with that,
notice that I am not adding the parentheses here,
I got my decorator set up, I can save this and if I then go to the console where we see function person
which is just the constructor function created by TypeScript,
so the constructor function of this class.
Now even though it worked fine,
what you should do because right now you can see we're getting an error here
that experimental support for decorators is a feature that is subject to change and that we
haven't set the experimental decorators option to remove this warning.
So in order to remove the warning, I can go to tsconfig and add another configuration here
where I say experimental decorators and set this to true,
which means yes I am aware that decorators is a feature which might change in the future but I want
to use it, don't warn me.
And with that, I set this up in a way that if I save this now,
well now I'm not getting this warning anymore.
Now clearly this class doesn't have a constructor but it does have an implicit constructor.
If we explicitly add one and then I just say console log
hi here, save this again and let's have a look at the console,
well then you see the console log hi here too
because again it prints the constructor of this class. So that's how you create a decorator or it's just
a normal function again
but how you make it a decorator by appending it with the @ sign and then again, it gets this constructor
function passed into this function by TypeScript because it is attached to a class and when attaching
a function to a class as a decorator, TypeScript gives you a reference to the constructor function.