So that's a decorator, it's a function attached to something with the @ sign and you can not only attach
a function like this,
you could also create something which is called a factory.
Now sounds difficult but it isn't. I'll create a new class which I'll name car and this class doesn't
have any implementation because I want to keep this simple
and now let's say you still want to add kind of this logged decorator but you want to be able to either decide
and or to decide if this should be logged or not.
So I want to pass
true or false like this, so
true false. True means print it to the console, false means don't print it.
So I can't do it up here because this log function only gets the constructor as a function and I can't
add
true or false but I can use a factory to get the behavior here.
I'll create a new function which I'll name logging,
again nothing special about this function,
it's a normal function.
It gets a value which is of type boolean,
that's something I decide, has nothing to do with TypeScript or where you attach this function,
this can be decided by you. Now
importantly, this function has to return a function which can be used as a decorator. So it returns depending
on if value is true or false,
if it is true, it returns the logged function, otherwise it returns null, so it returns nothing,
so nothing gets attached then.
Now I can attach this logging decorator here but now I'm calling it like a function with parentheses
and I pass true and that's important because in the end of course, I can only attach this function because
it gets the constructor,
logging is not really the decorator attached,
I am attaching the logging result since I'm executing the logging function here and the result or whatever
this function returns is the logged function which again is a valid function to be used as a class decorator
because it gets this constructor argument.
So if I save this, it compiles without an error and if I then have a look at the console, let's clear it,
reload, you see function car here gets logged but if I switch this to false here, save it again, reload,
you see now I'm only getting the log of function person which stems from this decorator here but I'm
not logging the car anymore because this is false,
therefore yes this function gets executed but it returns null,
so in the end nothing is attached to the class because again and I'm just stressing this because it is
so important,
keep this in mind, @logging means attach the result of this function for execution which is null
if we set it to false,
so then no metadata works, excuse me, no decorator is attached.
So changing this to true again to have the log and with that, you see how we can use decorators here.