Now we can also create a more useful decorator,
so I'm calling this in advanced. Let's create a new function which I want to use as a decorator and I'll
name it printable,
this will of course get my constructor function as an input since I want to pass it to or attach it
to a class and in here what I want to do is, I will take the prototype of the constructor function and
keep in mind then that's just the prototype of any object created based on this class or based on the
constructor function, in the
end that's just how Javascript script works,
print,
so add a new method to the prototype, function.
So with this, I can then console log this which should basically do the following,
each object created or instantiated based on a class which has the printable decorator will automatically
receive the print method
because I'm adding it to the prototype here and this print method allows this object to
print itself to the console,
so let's see it in action.
I'll create a new class, plant and here I'll set up a name which is just green plant by default, so a
name property and then I want to add my printable decorator without parentheses because here, I'm not
having a factory,
this is the decorator itself or the function which I want to use as a decorator.
So with printable in place, I can then create a new plant here, new plant and with this, I can call plant print.
Now unfortunately, I have to explicitly cast this to type any otherwise
TypeScript doesn't really recognize that this print function does exist even though it does,
so that's just a little bug as it seems.
But if I save this now, no errors and if I go to the console, you see plant, green plant at the bottom.
So this object here, this plant object which I created based on this plant class just printed itself and
again for that, it's important to keep in mind that the class or the decorator attached to the class
gets the constructor function which basically is this blueprint here.
That's just how Javascript works, the class is just syntactic sugar, we have a constructor function in the
background and then on the prototype of this constructor function,
so kind of the parent class of all objects, I add the print method which allows again this object to print
itself.
So with that, I add a little bit of more useful decorator to the class to show what you can do with decorators.