Now you can not only add one decorator, you can also add multiple.
So let's say I also want to log this class, so I could use my logging decorator I pass through for example
to then, as again this is a factory attach the logged function here as a decorator
in the end
and if I save this and reload my page,
well now you see that yes we have the plant being printed here by the printable function
but before that, we see the log logging the constructor function to the console and that stems from this
logging decorator here.
If I change this to false, the log decorator will not get attached
and therefore if I reload this, we only see the plant printing itself due to the printable decorator but
we don't see the constructor function being printed to the console before that
and that's just because the logged decorator is not attached here.