So that was a lot of talking about decorators and functions,
the key takeaway is a decorator is just a function, a normal function, any function could be a decorator
in theory but then it depends on where you want to attach this function as a decorator and what does
depend on that?
Well, which arguments can be used by this function.
Then you simply attach a decorator with the @ sign and you can either directly attach the kind of final
decorator you want to use by leaving out the parentheses,
in this case you have to make sure that the parameters passed to the functions match the parameters
TypeScript will give you for this type of decorators, so a class decorator in this case. The alternative
way is to use a factory which you have to execute by adding parentheses and any potential arguments
you specified, you're totally free about which arguments you expect here
and this factory has to return a function which can be used as a decorator, which means a function with
the right parameters
again. Now you rightfully would ask, how do I know which parameters a function should get for the different
types of decorators? And now we only saw class decorators
but I'll soon dive into other types of decorators too
and yes of course, I will tell you all the arguments expected by TypeScript but if you want to look
it up and not really watch all the videos, the place to go is the typescriptlang.org page,
the official webpage of TypeScript and then the documentation, here the handbook
and then you got decorators. Now on these decorators, you will see a very good explanation of decorators,
so something to look up if you in doubt
and also on all types of decorators, for example method decorators, something I'll come to
next, you'll see which arguments this decorator expects listed here.
So that's just as a fallback for you to know where to look.