So as already announced, now is the time to have a look at a different decorator,
the method decorator which, well you guessed it, allows us to decorate methods.
So I'll create a class for this again, I'll name it project and this class should have a project name which
is a string,
it should have a constructor where I can assign this name,
that's all I'm doing in here, so set this project name equal to the name passed to the constructor
and then as we're talking about method decorators, I want to have a method. I'll name it calcBudget, so
to calculate the budget of our project if you want to think of it like that
and all this should do is it basically console log let's say 1000.
So that's all this function does, not too fancy.
Now I want to write a decorator which allows me to make this method here editable or not editable because
right now what I can do and you can do that on all classes by default is of course I can instantiate it,
give it a name, Super Project for example and then I can call project,
no, calcBudget.
I can then after doing this also set calcBudget to a new function and change it to then print 2000
for example and if I then call it again,
well what will we see? And then reload
or it was already there but reload the page and we see 1000 and 2000 which makes sense because we're
overwriting the function here, right? Now that I want to add some metadata to this method here to make it
non-overwritable or editable.
So I will add a function at the top which will serve as my decorator or which I will attach to be precise
and I'll name it editable,
this will take a boolean value, so that will be a factory which I am creating which then returns me the
actual function which gets attached to the metadata and/or the method and this function takes different
arguments than the function here which was to be attached to the class took.
Remember the function we attach the class only took the constructor function as an input.
Now here, this metadata which will get added to a method takes a target of type any because that varies
on the question if we have a static class or a static method or instantiate one,
so if we're calling a static method, then this would resolve to the constructor function,
if we're using an instantiated one, target would be the prototype of that object. Then we have the name
of the property and then we have the descriptor
and that is a type property descriptor.
Now what is a descriptor? A descriptor is something we best look up here, it has nothing to do with TypeScript
or metadata, it has to do with plain old Javascript and it comes from this object defined property method
here which allows us to create new properties with vanilla Javascript.
Here we pass a descriptor as the third argument
and as you can learn in this article, a descriptor allows you to configure a property, make it
reconfigurable so that you can't change the configuration afterwards can make it a new variable, assign
a value,
make it writable and so on.
So that is what a property descriptor does
and with this metadata, we get access to the descriptor and we can't change it.
So since I want to control the edibility of this method, what I do as I access the descriptor and then
the writable property on the descriptor and I set this equal to value, so that the user can control with
the editable factory here
if the method should be editable or not.
With that, I can attach my metadata like this, add editable and pass
let's say false to block the editing of this method.
Now with this, if I save this, close that and reload my page, now you see we print 1000 twice because
we're preventing this method here from being edited.
So this overwriting attempt here doesn't work, it's going into the void,
it's not throwing an error but it's not working either,
so here we just fail.
So that's how you attach a decorator to a method,
you have these three properties or these three parameters passed to that function which you can then
use in the function. Important, the target depends the question whether you're having this method as a
static method in a static class or in an instantiated class or where you are using that.