Just like you can assign method decorators, you can also add property decorators and I'm just going to
bundle that together here.
Now a property decorator, as the name implies, can be added to a property.
You might think it looks pretty similar to a method decorator because there is not that
much difference between a method like this and a property like that,
unfortunately there is a difference because due to some technical reasons, TypeScript can't access properties
in the same way it can access methods.
Therefore, if we wanted to make this project name for example uneditable, we might get unexpected results
but see for yourself.
I can add another function and I'll name it overwritable to not reuse the editable name and this should
always be factory where the user decides if that should be the case or not
and then here we also return a function which will serve as the actual decorator or annotation to that
property where we are going to add it. Now this function also takes target as the input,
following the same logic as with the editable method here, so target is either the constructor function
in a static class or the prototype in an instantiated one,
then we have the property name which is a string and then that's it.
So we don't have the property descriptor unfortunately because TypeScript can't access it
but important to know, this function here can return the property descriptor, so we can set the descriptor
but we can't access the old one or the existing one.
So what we can do here is we can create a new descriptor, like so, of type property descriptor should
be an object then
and here we can set for example writable to value.
Now if we do this and then we have to return the new descriptor,
if we do that, we can of course go to the project name and assign overwritable and set this to false.
Now in order to see what this does,
I print the whole project here
so that we can have a look at that
and now here's something interesting, we get an empty project here.
Well the reason for this empty project is or this empty project we see here is that with our overwritable
metadata here, I'm setting writable to false
in this case and that prevents every writing access to this method or
excuse me, to this property including the one here in the constructor,
so no value get set at any point and that is why we get this undesired result of not seeing anything
here.
So by the way if you return the descriptor here, you should add any here to just let TypeScript know
that you're planning on returning something here
but again, this won't really change this. It's hard to use that descriptor, this property descriptor here
because of the fact that for example changing the writable state will pretty much lock up this property
for your whole code.
However of course, you could use some other logic here which might be more suitable
or you might want to change the enumerability or the configurability of that property, then this
might be fine, otherwise
this decorator on a property should mostly be used to read values and react based on that,
so as a listener kind of which then does things when you attach it to a property.
However I wanted to show this very important piece of information that you can return a new descriptor,
a new property descriptor, that you then should add the any return type,
otherwise return void
if you're not planning on returning something but that you have to be aware of the potential issues
we're facing with this and that simply as I said due to some technical limitations TypeScript faces here.