Now I want to conclude this module here with another type of decorator, a parameter decorator,
so decorators attached to parameters passed to methods.
So for that I'm creating yet another class here, I'll name it course, this should have a name,
it will get a constructor by me where this name is also passed to the constructor and yes, I could use
the shorter way of initialising this, I just like to be explicit here and then I'll have method,
printStudentsNumbers let's say where I have the printAll boolean to know if I should print all the students
and let's also add a mode property which is a string or a mode parameter, excuse me.
And then here, I'll totally ignore the mode,
you will soon see why I added it and then I'm going to just check if printAll,
so if we want to print all students in which case I'll log let's say 10000 and otherwise let's say
we're not printing all the students, so then I'll only print 2000.
Now I can simply instantiate this course,
so course equals new course
and then I can call course.printStudentsNumbers, mode is anything because I'm
ignoring it anyways,
anything here
and I set this to true and then do it just one more time, set this to false and of course, course should
have a name like this.
So saving this if I reload my page, we see 10000 and 2000 as expected.
Now I want to annotate this parameter here or I want to add a decorator to it and I just want to print
some information about this parameter for now.
So I'll name it printInfo and this will not be a factory,
it will be the decorator itself, though of course you can create a factory, that is true for all kinds
of decorators and here,
I'll have the target as a property, as a parameter I get passed to this function here and target as before
will either be the constructor of the class or the prototype, depending on whether it's a static class
or not,
then I have the name of the method on which this parameter or where this parameter is used, so not the
parameter name but the name of the method.
So I'll name it method name here
and then I have the param index,
so the index of the parameter or put in other words, which position this parameter has in the list
of arguments passed to this method here.
So this parameter here would have the position
whereas the second parameter but as this starts at 0
like in an array it has the position of one but you will see this in a second.
So in this function,
all I want to do is I want to print some info and of course, you cannot only print things there, you can
execute whatever logic you want to execute in this decorator,
I just want to show what we're getting here.
So I'll print the target like so, I'll then also print the method name here
and I will print the key index on the param,
so which position we indeed do have here,
so like this, the param index.
Now with that, I can go down to my printStudentsNumbers method here
and I want to attach it to printAll and I simply do it by adding @printInfo,
so the same syntax you already know.
Important, no parentheses,
this is no factory here,
that's the function I want to attach as a decorator itself.
So if I save this and reload my page here, you see the target,
then also the method name and the index of the parameter, 1
because as I said, it starts counting at zero,
so since this is the second argument, it has the index of one.