Now throughout this course, you learned a lot about the different types we can use in TypeScript and how we can use
TypeScript to enhance our projects in general.
Now there certainly are projects though where you use some third-party libraries which don't use TypeScript
which are not written in TypeScript,
so how can you now use such normal Javascript libraries in your TypeScript project and still take advantage
of all these type definitions and the enhanced IDE support and so on?
Now this is what we'll have a look at in this module and now just to avoid confusion,
I'm using a new editor here because this section here was basically recorded after I initially recorded
the course, it's an updated section and therefore here, I am using Visual Studio Code,
it's a normal code editor, normal IDE,
here I got an open empty folder
and this is where I will work in,
you can use any IDE to follow along of course.
And now with that let's dive in and let's see an example of when we might have an issue when we use a normal
Javascript library and how we can then fix this issue.