Now with JQuery installed, I can go into my index.html or where I'm already at and here I want to add a
little div with an ID of app which I want to change through JQuery.
So here, just enter change it with JQuery so that we can see something on the screen
and then in my app.ts file, I want to use my JQuery code, like we know to use it with the dollar sign
and I'll ignore that my IDE marks it as red for now,
then I select the element with the app ID,
so basic JQuery here
and then I want to change the CSS styles.
So here, I'll pass a Javascript object and I want to change the background color to let's say green, of course
choose anything you like here.
Now what this should do is that as soon as I compile my code with tsc, it should allow me to see my application
with this changed background color.
Now right away we see that we get an error here, that the dollar sign isn't found
and how would we find it, TypeScript has
no chance of knowing what the dollar sign should refer to.
Well let's give it a try anyways and simply run our lite-server, npm start and see what we can find on
the web page,
well I only see change it with JQuery but no color.
Well it's not that surprising because first, we're not recognizing the dollar sign but we're not even
trying to import JQuery here,
we installed it in the node_modules folder but that doesn't mean that it automatically gets added to our
application.
We don't have a script import here in the index.html file
and we could add one but to stay in the TypeScript world, let's instead use import statement here
and let's try importing JQuery, something like that,
maybe this works.
So let me open up a new terminal here and run tsc again,
of course we still get the error,
maybe it changed though.
No, not really.
Well let's see if we get some errors here in the console and we do, that our SystemJS module loader
has problems loading the Javascript file, the JQuery Javascript file.
As you can see here, it's looking for JQuery.js in our root directory
and the reason why it's looking there is that we're importing just JQuery here which of course refers
to JQuery.js then and to our root folder, though both isn't true.
Let's first see where JQuery actually lives,
in the node_modules file, let's locate it here,
so that's the JQuery folder we downloaded.
Now in here, we get this dist folder which probably holds the files we should import and there, we get the
jquery.min.js file where which looks like the bundle version we might want.
So it's in node_modules/jquery/dist/jquery.min.js,
that would be the path we can throw into our index.html file
but again, I want to use SystemJS here to manage all my dependencies and files and therefore here,
I can simply add a new config,
I can add the map configuration.
Now of course, this is no SystemJS course and if you want to learn more about SystemJS and
the available configurations, check out the official documentation.
What map allows you is to use any of your imports like JQuery here and map it against a real path.
If you don't have map, then it will try to resolve it on its own which as you saw before doesn't work
in this case.
So here, what I have to enter on my map key is a Javascript object where I then map JQuery and
this path or this part here, this key has to match whatever you're entering here in your import,
so you can name this whatever you want but then you have to match it here.
So this should match
and now here the path where to look for it.
Now the path will be node_modules
jquery/dist/
jquery.min.js, that's the path or the file
we just located. Now with that in place, if we have a look at the server,
oh we see it's working,
so it is green,
we do find the file, though we still have the issue that if I run tsc, we're getting this
compilation error.
So somehow the code is working but we still have this error.
Now how does this make sense?