It makes sense if you keep in mind that TypeScript compiles your file anyways but gives you these errors
and then here, it still doesn't know about that
but it compiles it and says basically well, if you know what you're doing, maybe it works and it does
work but it would be nice to not get this error and to get TypeScript to know JQuery which would also
give us other advantages of not only less errors
and these can quite add up if you have multiple JQuery commands but also in our IDE, some support
and so on.
So how do we tell TypeScript about JQuery?
We have to create a definition file for it which is basically a bridge between Javascript packages and
TypeScript.
Pure Javascript packages of course don't have types, don't have many of the features TypeScript has but
you can create some translation files which don't hold any TypeScript code which gets executed but just
some translations from Javascript to TypeScript and TypeScript can read those files to then learn
what the Javascript package would look like if it were written in TypeScript. Such a definition
file has the ending, .d.ts and on the official TypeScript manual, under handbook,
you can read more about it in the writing declaration files section.
This explains how to write such a file and how it works and basically as I just said, you use multiple
TypeScript constructs there but only kind of create the types,
you don't write any functions which would get executed or something like that,
you only declare which type a variable has, how an interface should look like,
which classes these
Javascript package you would use if it were written in TypeScript and so on.
As you can imagine, that's quite a lot of work for a big library like JQuery and I certainly don't want
to do this on my own.
So let's look for some alternatives.