A great alternative
and actually the way to do it is that there are people who already wrote such libraries and you can
find those libraries on definitelytyped.
So simply search for definitelytyped and you should find this Github repository which is named
definitelytyped.
There you will find thousands of Javascript packages which were kind of converted to TypeScript
in a sense of the translation file was written.
Now here you could basically scroll until you find JQuery but that is probably not the
way you want to do it,
a better way is simply to search for
definitelytyped and then JQuery and then you should find the respective page on this Github repository.
Now here, we have such a jquery.d.ts file which is the translation I was talking about.
If we have a look at it, we see how the creators of this file tried or did actually recreate JQuery or
create a translation for JQuery,
how it would look like in TypeScript.
Now what we can do is we can access the raw file here,
copy all of that, go back to our project and create a new file here
and let's name it jquery.d.ts, like so.
And in this file, I'll simply paste into it
the code I just copied from the definitelytyped repository.
Now with this pasted into here, let's try it again and run tsc
and as you see, the error is gone.
Notice, I didn't add any import,
I still only have my JQuery import here, so TypeScript is clever enough to automatically find
this file and then read it and learn how JQuery works which also gives me the advantage
that now, I get support by my IDE here which of course depends on your IDE
if you got this or not.
So that's the quick way to get in such a JQuery definition file or any definition file in general.
Now let's see which alternatives we have.