If you create a project with loads of Javascript libraries, you probably don't want to copy and paste
all these definition files by hand,
also if you share it, you have to share all these files
and it's not doing the best or most convenient way.
So let's have a look at a great alternative to this approach.
There is actually a third-party package which you can install globally on your machine which handles
all these file downloading and creation for you,
it's named typings and you can install it by installing it globally on your machine with npm install
-g typings, on Mac
you will need to add a sudo in front of it.
Now here, I'll quickly enter my password and then this will download this typings package for me which is
a package manager allowing me to download various typings or definition files as we just did it
manually,
let's see how it works.
So I'll first get rid of this jquery.d.ts file here as I don't need it anymore
and next, I want to use typings to get it back.
So I run typings
since I installed it globally and then I have to run install and now JQuery because that is what
this is named, though that won't work,
we have to fetch it from the definitelytyped repository and therefore we have to write dt~jquery,
just keep that in mind.
If you want to download a file from the definitelytyped repository and that is the biggest repository
for definitely or for type definition files I know,
then you have to use this dt~ part in front of the name of the package you want to download.
Now with that, I'll add the --global flag to make it available globally in this project, this does
not mean that it gets installed globally on your machine, only that every file in your project will have
access to it and then --save to create a JSON file which holds a reference to this package,
so that if we share this project, we only have to share this JSON file and everyone else is then
able to just run typings install to install all the dependencies mentioned in this file, just like you
have package.json file for your project dependencies.
So let's hit enter and it's done,
it created this typings folder and this typings.json folder.
Now as I mentioned this JSON folder or this JSON file here excuse me simply holds a reference to this
JQuery dependency or this JQuery file and in the typings file folder,
we actually got this JQuery file added to it.
So this is the same file we manually downloaded in the last lecture.
Now with this installed, if I recompile my project, the error is gone too.
So here again we don't have to add any import,
it works automatically on its own simply by adding this typings.json file or this typings folder
then specifically automatically through the typings tool.
So that is the alternative to the other approach which is extremely convenient especially if you've
got multiple dependencies or multiple Javascript packages you're using.