With TypeScript 2.0, a nice alternative to using the typings package was added.
You can still use it as you learned it but TypeScript 2.0 now has a built-in typings manager which is
an awesome new feature to be honest.
So what you can do here is you can simply get rid of the typings.json file, also of the typings folder
if you already installed your typings, here I just start a new project which is why you would see
this folder
and now of course we encountered the issue that if we compile this, we're not aware of dollar sign,
we don't know what JQuery is.
Now all we have to do with the built-in typings manager is we have to run npm install,
so we use npm now to manage our typings, like we use it to manage all other packages which is the great
thing about this, --save development as we want to add them as a development dependency
and then this is important, @types, this is kind of the overall package used by the TypeScript company
or compiler here to manage all the times or get access to all the types and then the name of the types
package.
Now here's an important thing,
we're still using definitelytyped which you saw in the other videos,
so this big Github repository.
We're still talking about the community managed types here,
these are no type packages or declarations managed by the TypeScript team,
instead they just provide us an easier access to this big Github repository.
Therefore the names after the slash here stay the same, though we don't have to use
dt~ anymore,
we can just use types
and then in this case, JQuery. Now this will pull down JQuery type declaration files and add them to our
package.json as well and of course is the more important part to our node_modules which we can
check here,
here we see the types folder and we see the JQuery type here.
Now the great thing is, again this is managed here in our package, in our package.json file to
be precise,
here you can see this new entry which allows us to quickly reinstall it if we share our project here
without the node_modules folder or what you typically do. Now with this
if I run tsc again, you see the error is gone and now we recognize the dollar sign because the cool
thing is that the TypeScript compiler is aware of this new mechanism,
so it will automatically search for imports like this one which it doesn't know or for types it doesn't know
in the node_modules @types folder.
So all this is done automatically,
we don't have to do anything here
and with that, we don't have to use another package like the typings package anymore,
we can use npm only. Of course
and this is important,
you may still use typings,
there's nothing wrong with it but this is the faster way and it uses the same repository.