So as I mentioned in the last lecture, here I'm in the empty folder opened in Visual
Studio Code, my IDE
and now let's say here we have a normal project with an index.html file with a normal HTML5 skeleton,
TypeScript and third-party libraries and
now in here,
let's say I want to use the JQuery library.
So on jquery.com, what I normally would do when I want to use it, I click on download
and now we can download it and add it to our project or we use one of the CDN links to basically pull
it in from a server, from another server where it's hosted and here I'll just take the minified version
of the latest JQuery version and at this point of time, copy that script tag and add this in the body section
here of my index.html file.
So now I'm importing this JQuery script and of course this is Javascript, this is not in TypeScript
format.
Now let's say of course we also write our own app logic and we do this here in the app.ts file or whatever
you want to call it, here I will be using TypeScript
and here I will simply import that
but of course there I will also import app.js
because the goal is to compile that.
Now let's create a very simple application here with a button which says Click Me and my simple goal
is to now select this button with the help of JQuery and then do something, throw an alert whenever
we click this button.
Now with JQuery, with normal JQuery what we can do is we can add this, now just temporarily,
add a Javascript script here,
in this case I'm doing this inline in the index.html file, I'll change this later
and then I will just use this dollar sign which is made available by JQuery,
this is just a function.
We pass a CSS selector like the button selector and JQuery then gives us the click method
we can call to define a function that should be executed
when a click on this button occurs and there I can throw an alert, button was clicked.
Now this is not using TypeScript here of course, this is just Javascript but with that, I can now double-click
that index.html file to run this and on the running page if I click this button, I see this alert,
so this works but this is as I mentioned normal Javascript. When I copy that code and I move that into
my app.ts file here
and then here I'm using the terminal integrated into my IDE,
I simply run tsc --init to turn this into a TypeScript project with a tsconfig and
now what we will see if I add the no emit on error key here in the tsconfig and set this to
true so that we don't generate a Javascript file,
we have an error
and I already see it in my IDE too that it complains
but now if I were to run tsc in this project folder, I indeed get an error here that this dollar sign
thing is basically not known or that it can't find this. And this makes sense because we never defined
dollar sign as a method,
we have no method in here that would tell TypeScript what this is all about and therefore it complains,
even though we know that this code would run but TypeScript doesn't know that.