So TypeScript doesn't understand this dollar sign method here is made available globally because we
added our JQuery import here. Now
to inform TypeScript that this is available,
we've got a couple of ways of doing so.
The easiest fix which you can always use if you have a global method or variable of which you know
that it exists but TypeScript doesn't know it, you can use the declare keyword in your TypeScript file
where you will use that unknown function or variable, then var and then the name of that function or
variable,
no matter what it is, you always use declare var and then you simply give this a type of any, that is the
simplest way of making this work.
As you see, the error is now gone
and now when I run tsc again, it compiled successfully and it gives us this app.js file.
Now this is a cheap way of making this work but it is a way you can definitely use if you have no other
way
or if you just want to get it to work quickly. But it's not an ideal way because with this line here,
we almost pass no information at all to TypeScript about this dollar sign variable,
it doesn't even know whether it's a function or not, leave alone that it would know what we can do
with the result of this function.
So for example here, that we can call click on the result of this function call, TypeScript doesn't know
that because we only tell it
this can be anything
and therefore here I get no IDE support at all,
we get no warnings and we get no help because we don't give any useful information to TypeScript.
So this is an approach we can use if we got no other alternative but there are better ways of solving
this.