And one better way to solve this which my IDE even suggests here is to install a so-called type definitions.
Type definitions is a feature TypeScript offers and you can learn more about that in the official documentation
under declaration files.
You can basically add your own declaration files which hold no script logic but which hold type and
function and so on definitions which TypeScript automatically considers when compiling your code.
So for example here, we could add a jquery.d.ts file and it has to be a .d.ts file for declaration
TypeScript file, TypeScript will look for files ending with .d.ts and in that file, you could
repeat that declare var dollar sign anything and what you will notice is that the error is now gone
in app.ts,
even though I commented it out here but implicitly, TypeScript automatically includes all .d.ts
file in its compilation step and therefore when I run tsc again here, it still works because it automatically
considers that file.
Now of course, we didn't add more than we had before, we just outsourced this line here into its own separate
file
but it's important to know that TypeScript considers such files because of course, you can define more
complex statements than just a single line
and actually, this is an advanced feature which you mostly only need when you create libraries you want
to share with other people on your own but you can write quite advanced type definitions and you'll learn
more about that here in the official docs where you learn how you can declare that something is not
just anything but a number
or that it is a function
and what this function would return and so on and other people already did that for JQuery
and a lot of other popular Javascript libraries. If you search for definitelytyped JQuery and you can
plugin any library name you're looking for,
you should find this definitelytyped Github repository here and in there if you click on that, you find
type definitions for JQuery
and if you click on that jquery.d.ts file here and it's actually also used in conjunction with a couple
of other files,
there you see an interface is defined and you see a lot of example code in there
but if you would go through and it's quite a long file,
you'll see that for example that an add method is defined and so on and you will also find that click method definition
in there if you search through that file.
There are a lot of examples but eventually you'll also find the function definition of click in there.
So in the end, this file adds all the logic, here it is by the way, adds all the logic you need to add
to make TypeScript fully aware of what's behind that dollar sign variable and behind the object this
function we can call there returns for example
and therefore I can now remove that jquery.d.ts file
and now we can simply install these type definitions with the help of npm and for that, I'll quickly
run npm init to turn this into a project that has a package.json file and where we can use npm,
this Node Package Manager to install third-party packages
and for this to work by the way, you need to have NodeJS installed in its latest version,
not because we'll write NodeJS code but because we'll use the Node Package Manager that ships together
with Node.
Now let's do that in the next lecture.