So you learned about these declaration files which you could write on your own
but of course we don't want to write them on our own,
instead we can install the ones which were written by the community where you can contribute
but which you can also just consume. And for that, we'll need npm,
so make sure you install NodeJS to have that npm, that Node Package Management tool installed too
and then in the project folder, run npm init and answer all these questions with the default value. Then
you'll get this package.json
file and now you can install other packages with the npm install command.
And there I will install with --save-dev to mark it as a development-only dependency, the @types
and then the name of the library name,
so here, JQuery. So with npm install --save-dev @types/jquery,
I installed a type definition in the latest version for that JQuery package
and here we see an entry in the dev dependencies of the package.json file.
The cool thing is that the TypeScript compiler will automatically without any extra configuration
consider all these @types, so everything in the types folder, in the node_modules folder and will include
them. So it will automatically dive into that JQuery folder and include the type definition files in
there without us telling it to the compiler and therefore now if I repeat
tsc, this still compiles but now with these detailed type definitions installed. We don't just have the compilation
work again, which we had before too
but you can see in the IDE here,
I get way better support now,
I get autocompletion because now my IDE fully understands what's behind that dollar sign function because
TypeScript now fully understands it. And this is the way to go
and this is what I strongly recommend doing when you use third-party libraries which are not written
in TypeScript.
You should then install the respective type definitions which are available for basically every library
that is at least a bit more important and popular. JQuery has it and a lot of other popular Javascript
libraries also have their own type definitions.