Well we already covered a lot of features and how to use them in TypeScript.
Now often times, you won't have a pure TypeScript project simply because you're not only writing your
own code but you may use a third-party package,
let's say JQuery.
Now these packages tend to be written in Javascript, not in TypeScript
which means if you import them, well all of a sudden you lose the typings and so on for a big chunk
of your project, namely for all the JQuery related code in this example.
Now to reintroduce these features, to make sure you're using the right types in conjunction with JQuery
or whatever your package is, we would need some way to get that information. Throughout this module,
you will learn how to combine your Javascript packages or third-party libraries with TypeScript and
create a nice translation for the TypeScript compiler to use to know which types
for example JQuery would use if it were written in TypeScript.
Now that's an amazing feature enabling you to have all the power of TypeScript available even when working
with non-TypeScript libraries.
Let's see how that works in this module.