Now as mentioned, sometimes you want to add your own packages to your TypeScript
projects and these packages may only be available as JavaScript. In this module,
I'll have the example of JQuery, let's say in our TypeScript project which is not very awesome since
we don't have a single line of code but let's say here we want to use JQuery, we want to use it to do
something with the DOM and stuff you do with
JQuery.
The first step of course is to install JQuery,
so I'll go down to my console here and I'll do that.
Now important to recognize this in my base project here,
I already got a package.json file,
I got my tsconfig file and all of these are very simple.
Here I only have the lite-server and SystemJS which is responsible for loading my modules even
though I don't have modules here
but you'll see why er'll use it here later on because we'll need to import JQuery then basically
but before importing, let's install it. Now since I already got my package.json, I can use npm install
and then --save to install it as a production dependency and then JQuery. This will
download JQuery and install it into my node_modules folder.