Alright now we're
ready to write our first JavaScript code. In order to write JavaScript code
here, we need a script element. There are two places
where we can add a script element. We can add that here
in a head section, or in the body section.
The best practice is to put the script element at the end
of the body section after all the existing elements.
So here after h1 I'm going to type script
and press tab. This is our script element. Now why did I
say that as a best practice we should put the script element here?
Well, there are two reasons for that. One reason is
that the browser parses this file from top to bottom. So,
if you put the script element here in the head section.
You might have a lot of JavaScript code there, so your browser might
get busy parsing and executing that JavaScript code, and it's one
thing to be able to render the content of the page.
So this will create a bad user experience. Your user looks at your web page
it's white or blank, while your browser is busy parsing
and executing your JavaScript code. So that's reason 1.
The second reason is that almost always the code that we have
in between script elements needs to talk to the
elements on this web page. For example, we may want to show or hide
some elements. So by adding the code here, at the end
of the body section, we'll be confident that all these elements
are rendered by the browser. Now there are exceptions to this rule,
sometimes you're using third part code that has to be placed
in the head section. But these are exceptions, as I told you before
as a best practice, you should add your JavaScript code at the end of the body section.
Now here, you're going to write the same code that
you wrote in the last lecture, console.log,
Hello World. But we're
going to talk about this in a little bit more detail, what we have here is a
statement. A statement is a piece of code that expresses
an action to be carried out. In this case, we want to log
a message on the console. All statements
in Javascript should be terminated by a semi colon.
What we have here in between single codes is called
a string. A string is a sequence of characters
Now in JavaScript we also have this notation, we can add
two slashes, and this represents a comment.
So here we can add some description to our code and this description
is ignored by the JavaScript engine, it's not executed.
It's purely for documenting the code, when you want to explain to other
developers why you have written this code this way.
You don't want to explain what the code does, because that should be clear in
itself. So here I don't want to write something like logging something
on the console. That's so obvious in the code, right? Instead we want to
explain why's and how's. So for this demo, I'm just going to add
a simple comment, this is my first JavaScript
code. Now save the changes,
back in the browser, we need to bring the console back
up, so right click somewhere, and click inspect, or
alternatively, you can use a short cut, that is alt, command,
and i, on Mac, or alt control I on Windows.
That brings up the console tab, if the console tab is not
immediately visible, make sure to select it here, and here you can see the Hello
World message.