In order to understand how the compiler works,
here's a very very very very basic code,
just two variables.
Let's compile them with tsc
and this creates this app.js file,
now let's have a look at this file.
Well it doesn't show anything you wouldn't know yet,
of course it converted the left keyword to var and it remove the types here since
Javascript does have types but no strong typings, no explicit types.
So this is what you already saw,
now let's get to the first interesting part.
If I try to set my name equal to 30, which clearly is wrong because my name should be a string and now I'm
setting it to a number, let's run tsc, we get an error here, type number is not assignable to type
string.
Let's have a look at the app.js file.
Now what we see here is that even though we got a compilation error, it was assigned here,
so why is it compiling
if we got an error? Simply because it's the default behavior. The TypeScript compiler warns you, it gives you an
error
but it compiles it nonetheless
to give you a chance to run your code nonetheless because maybe it was wrong, maybe there is something,
so an import or you have another dependency in the index.html file through another script import which TypeScript
is not able to know about but your code still works after it has been compiled.
So then you are still not writing a really TypeScript friendly application, as you're deliberately passing
on on some of the advantages it gives you but TypeScript won't keep you from executing your code, so that's
not actually a bad behavior.
You can suppress it though, the tsconfig.json file allows you to define some compiler app options
and we'll have a look at this file in the next lecture.