So in this tsconfig.json file, you can configure how your compiler should behave
and this is a default file as it gets created once you run tsc init,
what we did in the first module of this course.
Now let's have a look at the base options we see here
and let me also mention that in a later module of this course when we talk about the workflows, I'll also
come back to this file
but the base options are that we don't want to compile anything into node_modules folder because that
is not our code, that we want to resolve our modules to be CommonJS format
and I'll come back to this in the namespace in modules folder, that the target version to which we
want to compile is ES5
and you could change this to ES3 or ES6 but ES5 as the default as it runs in pretty much all
browsers
and then these two options. Now I'll come back to that,
these options in a second,
now let's first try to fix this behavior if we don't want it of TypeScript compiling code if it has
errors. We can add a new key here which is named noEmitOnError
and we can set this to true which is not the default, the default is false which is why it is not included
here.
So noEmitOnError is that
now we shouldn't get this app.js file if we have a compilation error.
So I just deleted it and now I try to run tsc again.
Now we get the error
as you can see, no js file to be found.
So if you want that behavior, that your file doesn't get created in case of any errors, you can force
it with this simple option here.
If you don't want this behavior, so if you want the default behavior of the Javascript file getting
created nonetheless, simply remove this option and you're back to the default where you get these
files and you have to handle these errors more like a it's a warning way.
It's no hard error preventing your project from running,
it's just a warning that there might be something which is wrong or that you might be making some mistake
.