Now as you might be able to imagine, there are a lot of options you can define here
and to be honest, a lot of them are options you'll rarely if never use. Two options you order to see here
which are created by default is the noImplicitAny option which is set to false and the sourceMap option, which is
also set to false.
Now the sourceMap option should be pretty clear, if you set that to true and then compile your project,
then you see that not only does the Javascript file get created, we also get this .map file which
is the sourceMap for this file.
Now what's the advantage of the sourceMap?
Let's have a look at our running application, so I'll quickly
start my live server and then let's head over there and of course we don't see anything but if we click
on sources here in the Chrome developer tools, we see the app.js file of course which gets imported
and we also see the app.ts file.
So even though we are running the Javascript file of course because that's the file we're importing
in the index.html file,
we got access to the ts file and we can even click into it,
set a breakpoint here in the developer tools and if I now reload this page,
we're actually pausing at that breakpoint
and then of course we can still continue code execution, so we can debug our TypeScript code directly
in the browser directly in the TypeScript file.
We don't have to debug in the Javascript file,
we can do this in the TypeScript file which of course is a great addition and a great and very important feature
which makes finding our errors much easier and that is achieved by setting this sorceMap option to true
which is not the default and I will turn it back to false here to have one less file being created
but if you are developing in a project, you probably might want to do this or might want to turn this
to true as it will give you source maps and make your production or your developer life really easier.