Now what's this noImplicitAny thing here?
Well you might be able to guess this, if I go back to the app.ts file and I create a new variable,
anything
and I set anything equal to 12, that is valid TypeScript code
and if I go to my console and I comment out the erroneous code here and I compile this, you'll see it
compiled without an error.
Now this of course is of type any but it's not of type any because we set it to type any but because
we didn't set anything,
so it was implicitly set to type any.
Now with that, it should be pretty clear what happens if I set noImplicitAny to true.
If I do this and run my compiler, now I get an error that the variable anything implicitly has an any
type
and this is simply again a warning or combined with the other option I showed you before, even a reason
why your code won't be compiled at all because you're using this implicitly.
So it's really a good warning which kind of reminds you, hey maybe you want to assign a type here,
no?
So it might get you to write better code
but of course you don't have to use it
and in a default tsconfig file, it is set to false but again, you may of course use it.
And keep in mind if you set it to true, you're still allowed to explicitly set this to any, with that
this code compiles without issues.
It's only this implicit any which is not allowed, so I'm going to set this to false.