With the release of TypeScript 2.0, the compiler also gets a little bit smarter,
let's consider the following example here.
I get a function, controlMe which takes a parameter, isTrue which is a boolean and then I have my results
which is a number, I check if isTrue is true, in which case I assign
result be 12 and then I return result.
If I compile this code here, we don't get an error
but actually this code does have a problem, result might not be initialized here when we return it but
it is implicitly null here because it should be of type number and if we never initialize it, well then
it is like null.
Now if we add the compiler option you saw at the end of last module, the strict
null checks and set this to true,
if I now compile the code,
you see we now get an error here
that result is used before it is signed because the TypeScript compiler now finds out that isTrue might
be false and therefore we never initialize this and therefore we never assign a value to result which
keep this in mind should be a number and not null or anything like that,
this is one of the things where the compiler got smarter.
It now analyzes the flow of your code better,
it analyzes which parts of your code you actually can reach and so on
and of course there would be other examples and it's not really something which you use but it is something
which provides an advantage to you because the compiler is smarter,
that should lead to less mistakes.
Now with TypeScript 2.0, there is another nice addition which allows you to create cleaner code
and that's a specific compiler option,
I will show you how it works.
Let me first add a new parameter to this function,
something else which should be a boolean.
Now I don't use this parameter anywhere here but if I compile my code, I don't get an error of course.
I added the result equals 33 here to get rid of the error from my function here, where I was
returning results even though it might not have been initialized,
so just that you're not wondering why this error is gone now.
So with a new option I can add, I can change the current behavior.
I can add no unused parameters here and by default if we don't add it,
this is false but if I do add it and set it to true,
if I now recompile my code, I suddenly get an error that something else is declared but never used
which is absolutely true.
I never use something else,
so by adding this no unused parameters option here, I can avoid having functions like this which
have parameters I don't need.
So if your goal is cleaner code, you might think about adding this new option which TypeScript 2 introduced.