Now did we have a good understanding of the basic types good features and what typescript adds.
And we also understand how to typescript compiler works.
Let's have a look at what else typescript has to offer specifically when it comes to modern javascript
syntax.
Now this is a difficult a pretty wake term but in the end what I mean by that are javascript features
which have been around for a few years by now and which are well-supported in modern browsers but which
don't necessarily run in all especially in older browsers and there especially in Internet Explorer.
I'm talking about things like let concert arrow functions D structuring syntax spread.
Operator and so on.
So if debt is something you absolutely know you can skip this module because it will also refresh the
knowledge on these topics but I'll also explain what typescript does with these things with this syntax.
Though the short story is typescript compiles it's such that it works nonetheless.
We'll take a look at that but you can skip this module if that's all stuff you already know.
You can just have a look at the curriculum and see if there is any lecture in this module which might
still be interesting to you.
Otherwise as you often does module if you're not sure about these features if you know javascript regarding
var and so on but you don't know what the LAT or con's keyword really means.
Then you should stick with me and dive into this module for that I got a brand new project set up you'll
find it attached and you always need to run npm install first in these projects don't forget this to
install all dependencies and thereafter always NPM start to start up that development server.
Now this is a project basically as we had it before.
At the end of last module is conflict file with a pretty strict configuration an apt yes file here and
that this folder will be generated automatically by the way.
Keep this development severe running of course as you did before and now we can always compile our code
with the T S C command here or.
And that's what I'll do here.
TSC dash W to enter watch mode and make sure we recompile whenever we change something.
So now that's our project setup and now we'll dive into some next gen Java's good features which types
of supports and what you should be aware of.