In the previous modules we worked on a project and dear we ever had all our code in one file which made
it hard to manage or we actually split it into multiple files either by using name spaces or by using
these iOS 6 modules.
But when using iOS 6 modules whilst our code was more manageable we actually had another disadvantage
into which I'll dive again in this module again in this module will not also have a look at that disadvantage
again.
More importantly we'll have a look at a solution Westpac.
So in this module you will learn what exactly web Peg is and of course stand we'll also use it to get
a set up a project setup which gives us the best of all worlds actually where we can write code split
up into multiple files without that disadvantage.
Add which will have a look at now.