So we added Webb pack a very important tool that allows us to bundle together our different files into
one bundle.
This really helps us decrease the amount of hp requests made and therefore can speed up our application.
If you find yourself working with a lot of individual files what you typically do in bigger projects
tools like pick are a must use and webpage is the most important and prominent tool that helps you with
that.
So therefore it's the tool I wanted to show here.
You see that webpage is highly configurable and as I mentioned multiple times the official docs of webpage
are the place to go to learn all about it about different loaders different other settings you can set
up and how it works in general.
So definitely dive into this documentation if you want to become a webpage monster and you want to have
a more elaborate setup.
Our basic set up here however already allows us to compile type files with the Web pack and then bundle
to gather all the output into one single bundle jazz file and we also set up a configuration for development
which makes debugging easier and gives us more helpful error messages and we get a production setup
which gives us a highly optimized code which we then could deploy to a server to ship as little code
as possible to it and that's it.
Web Peg really is a core tool and being able to use it and having a configuration that really just works
is super important.
So it is a must use in any modern project.
I would say and in this module you learned how you can get started with it in your types good projects.