So you have learned
how to declare and initialize a variable. Now you might be wondering
what are the kind of values that we can assign
to a variable? Well you seen strings, but we have more types.
Basically, in JavaScript we have two categories of types.
On one side, we have primitives, also called
value types. And the other types we have reference types.
In this lecture, we're going to focus on primitives, and you're going to learn about
reference types later in the course. Now in the category of
primitives, we have strings, numbers,
booleans, undefined, and null. Let's look at
each of these in action. So here we have a variable called
name which is set to a string, what we have here is
called a string literal.
That's just a fancy name for a string. Now let's declare a variable
and set it to a number. So let Age and set that to 30
and by the way I'm not 30 years old, but don't tell anyone, okay?
So this is what we call a number literal.
Now let's declare a boolean. A boolean can either be true
or false. So, let isApproved
to be true. This is what we call a
boolean Literal. And we use this in situations where we want to have
some logic. For example, if the order is approved,
then, it needs to be shipped. So the value of a boolean
variable can be true or false.
And by the way note that both true and false are reserved keywords,
so they cannot be variable names. Okay?
Now you have seen undefined before, so I can declare another
variable, firstName, if we don't initialize it, by default
it's value is undefined, but we can also explicitly
set this to undefined. But that's not very common,
in contrast, we have another keyword that is null.
So let me declare another variable, let's set this
to null. We use null in situations where we want
to explicitly clear the value of a variable.
For example, we may want to present the user with a list of colors.
If the user has no selection, you want to set
the selectedColor variable to null.
In the future, if user selects a color, then we are going to
reassign this variable to a color like red.
And then if they click red again, perhaps we want to remove the selection,
so we set this back to null. So we use
null in situations where we want to clear the value of a variable.
So these are the examples of primitives and value
types. We have strings, numbers, booleans,
undefined and null. Now in ES6 we have
another primitive that is symbol, and you're going to learn that later in the course.