One thing that separates JavaScript
from a lot of programming languages, is that JavaScript is a dynamic
language. What do I mean by dynamic? Well,
we have two types of programming languages. Static languages or
dynamic languages. In static languages, when we declare a
variable, the type of the variable is set and it cannot be changed
in the future. In a dynamic language like JavaScript,
the type of a variable can change at run time. Let's see this
in code. So back in the example from the last lecture we have declared
this name variable, and we have set that to a string, so
the type of name is currently a string, but it can change in the future.
Let's take a look. So here in the console, we can execute some JavaScript
code, we have this type of operator,
and with that we can check the type of a variable. So after that
we add the name of the variable. In this case the name variable
So note that the type of name is a string. So,
if you reassign name to a different value, like a number,
and check it's type,
look, the type is now changed to a number, this is what we call
a dynamic language, so unlike static languages the type of
these variables will be determined at runtime based on the values
that we assigned to them. Now, let's take a look at a few more examples of the type
of operator. And by the way, note that type of is
another reserved keyword, so we cannot have a variable called
type of. So, we can clear the console by
pressing control and L. So now let's take a look at
the type of age, it's a number. Now if we change
age to a floating point number, and I know it doesn't make sense, but
let's just stick to this for example, 30.1,
and then look at type of age, it's still a
number. So in JavaScript, unlike other programming languages
we don't have two kinds of numbers, we don't have floating point numbers
and integers, all numbers are of type number.
Now, let's look at the type of is approved, it's a
boolean as I told you before, what about the first name, let's have a
look. Type of, first name. It's undefined.
And that's funny, because the value of this variable is undefined
but it's type is also undefined. What does this mean?
Well, earlier I told you that we had two categories of types,
we have primitives or value types, and reference types.
In the primitive types category, we have strings, numbers,
booleans undefined and null. So undefined
is actually a type, but it's also a value.
In this example, because we have set first name,
to undefined as a value it's type is also
undefined, okay? But what about selected color.
Let's have a look, so type of selected color.
The type of this variable is an object.
What is an object? That's a topic for the next lecture.