Sometimes in your
applications, you might be dealing with a list of objects. For example,
the list of products in a shopping cart, or the
list of colors the user has selected, in situations like that,
you use an array to store that list. Let me show you how.
So here I'm going to declare another variable called
selected colors. Note that I'm using a meaningful
name, I don't have sc or some other weird name.
Selected colors. Now we can initialize this, and set
it to an empty array. So these square brackets
are what we call array literal, and they indicate an
empty array. Now we can initialize this array and add
a couple of items, like
red and blue. Let's log this on the console, so
console.log selected colors. Save the changes
so here's our array with two elements.
We can expand that, note that each element has an index,
and that determines that position of the element in that array. So,
the index of the first element is 0, and the index of the second
element is one. So if you want to access an element in the
array, we use this index. Here's how. For example, let's say
you want to display the first element in this array, we use these square
brackets, and then specify the index.
Save the changes, and now we have red. Now earlier, I told
you that JavaScript is a dynamic language. So the type of
variables can change at run time. The same principle applies
to our arrays. So the length of arrays as well as the type
of objects we have in an array are dynamic, they can change.
So, on line 2, we initialize this array with 2
elements, right? Now, on line 3 we can add
another element to this array, so the array will expand.
So, let's say selectedColorsof 2, that means
the third item in this array will also be green.
Now, let's display this array on
the console, so, we have an array with 3,
elements. So the length is dynamic, it can change, also
the type of objects we have in this array is dynamic,
so unlike other programming languages, where every item or
every object in the array, should have the same type, in JavaScript we can
store different types in an array. So, we can make the last
element a number. Save the changes, now we have
2 strings and a number. So the objects in the array as well as
the size of the array are dynamic. Now technically an array
is an object, so just like the person object we defined in the last lecture
it has a bunch of key value pairs, or properties that we can
access using the dot notation. Let me prove that to you. So here
on the console, let's look at the type of selected
Colors. So the type of this array is an
object. So an array is an object in JavaScript. So here on line
4, we can look at the properties of this array, or this
object, using the dot notation, look these are
all the properties defined in arrays in JavaScript, so,
every time we declare an array using square brackets, that array
will automatically receive these properties, we didn't explicitly
define them, they are just somehow magically inherited
from somewhere else. We're going to learn about that later when we talk about
prototypes. Now in this lecture, we're going to look at one of these properties.
That is the length property. This property returns
a number of items or elements in an array. So,
save the changes, you can see we have three elements in this array.
Now later in the course, we have a comprehensive section about arrays, you will
learn about all kinds of operations you can perform on arrays,
for now, all I want you to take away, is array, is a
data structure, that we use to represent a list of items.