With generics out of the way.
Let's dive into the next more advanced feature that would be decorators decorators are a feature which
can be very useful for met up programming.
Now what does up programming mean.
It means that you typically won't use tech writers that often to have a direct impact on the end users
of your page.
So off the users visiting your page but instead decorators are particularly well suited instrument for
writing code which is then easier to use by other developers.
Now that might sound strange but you'll see what I mean from this module.
In the end it all comes down to the fact that unlike with Abra code snippets let's say when we add an
event listener we can easily write code which have a direct impact on the users of our page.
If we register a listener on the button and we show an alert after the button gets clicked then the
user visiting our page immediately see something with decorators we don't typically work on that.
But instead we can for example guarantee that one of our classes gets used correctly or a method in
a class where we do some hidden transformation stuff like that.
So in detail in this module we'll see what exactly decorators are about and why we would use them.
We will of course use them and you will learn about the different types of decorators types supports
and we'll see a couple of examples that should make it clearer which role decorator is Phil and why
it can be useful.