We saw how we can build quite amazing things with decorators.
Decorator factories and then also by utilizing the return values of decorators which in the example
of a class decorator allows us to basically replace the class.
We added the decorator to with a class that is totally different that builds up on the existing class.
Like in our case and that therefore might add some functionalities.
Now you can return values in our decorators too but not all of them or not in all of them.
The return value is respected now decorators where you can return something are the decorators you add
two methods and the decorators you add to accessories.
So here on the center log two and log three on the method.
These two decorators lock to enlarge three.
These also could return something and typescript would use it d decorators on properties and on parameters
of course.
Also can return something but typescript will ignore it.
So return values are not support there or are not used to be precise.
Now what can you return on log free.
So on method decorators and on log to so on accessory decorators though you can return a brand new property
descriptor locked you in log free which are the two decorators I'm talking about right.
Lock to unlock free both get the descriptor off the property off the method.
You could say they are attached to because an accessories kind of like a method.
You have a function that gets executed there.
Now the property descriptor is a Java's good thing.
As you know if we have a look at this page again and we reloaded we see that for example for our excess
our decorator the property descriptor is this object here which has to configurable and enumerable and
get and set properties and forward a method decorator our descriptor is this object here which all day
has configurable innumerable value and Reidel and this is vanilla javascript you have property descriptors
in vanilla javascript as well they allow you to define property in more detail you can't of course assign
a value to a property and since we're talking about a method the value is a function in this case but
you can also control whether it's Reidel.
So if it can be changed after it has been created after the object has been created whether it's configurable
so if you can change this conflagration and if you can delete this property and if it's enumerable which
means if it shows up when you loop through your object for example and therefore a method for example
by default does a set to false so that if you use a for in loop on an object this method is not printed
as a property for an accessory also got configurable and enumerable but we gotta get to the set and
there you could of course also for example return a new descriptor which assigns a brand new set method
or which suddenly also adds a get functionality.
So here in lock to unlock for you can return a new descriptor object in the end and make that clear
to typescript that you will do so by returning or by setting the return type to property descriptor.
And there you can therefore also set the set keyword to get keyword there configurable already enumerable
property and change how this assessor or method is configured.
Now I don't want to do that here for the successor.
There's nothing interesting I could do with that and therefore I will not return a property descriptor
but I will actually show you an example with the method decorator where we will return something and
where we can build something interesting with the help of decorators.