So we can return something on method decorators and that something should be a descriptor which allows
us to change the method or change the configuration of the method.
And this is something I want to do here now for dead.
I will first of all go to index HQ file and there.
Let's add a button click me a very simple button in my apt yes file I now want to make sure that when
we click this button we execute a method on an object.
And for Dad I will simply add a new class here first of all printer and in there I want to have a property
message which is just this work.
So a simple string stored in there and then I want to have a show message method in there where I simply
console log this message.
So of course this is kind of a simple Dummy Class but nonetheless this allows to show you what I want
to show you.
Let's select a button in the dorm now with document query selector button and let's add an event listener
to it.
Now first of all I'll add my exclamation mark here to make it clear to typescript that this exists that
this will not be now.
And then I will add an event listener a click event listener and then I want to trigger does show message
method here for data will create a new printer here like this.
And then here pointed p dot show message.
That's my idea here.
Now if we save that and we go back to our page and they click on this button we get undefined here though
we don't get our message being shown.
And the reason for Dad is Dad with an event listener if we point at a function it should be executed.
The this keyword inside of that function will not have the same context or reference as it has if we
call just p dot show message.
In this case this would refer to the printer.
No.
In the scenario here where we use an event listener this will refer to the target of the event because
ad event listener in the end finds this in the function which is to be executed to the target of the
event.
And of course I don't want this.
Now a common work around here would be to use the bind method and bind show message to p or bind this
in show message to p so that when does executes this is not referring to what ad event listener wants
it to refer to but instead this instead of show message will refer to this P to this object here again
and it for now have a reload here and it clear us again.
Now we see this works.
Now that is all default javascript.
Now we'll build a decorator which we can add to this method which will automatically bind this to the
surrounding class.
So to the object this method belongs to every time it's called no matter where we call it.
So for dead above the printer I'll add a new function and it will name it all to bind because status
the and what we do and that will be my decorator order bind can all of course use a capital starting
character to stay in line with our other names but again you can use either of the two when you define
a decorator function.
Now this year will be my decorator already.
And in there we get a couple of arguments we get the target as you'll learn and that is any it is ever
the prototype of the object we're working with or it's the constructor function.
If we would be adding this to a static method but here it will be the prototype because we will add
it to instance method.
Then we have a method name or the property name but since we added to a method we can call this method
name makes more sense.
This is a string or a symbol or it could also be a number of course.
But here we know we will typically work with strings so we can't all just go with string here depending
on where you plan on adding this decorator and how generic it should be.
And last but not least we get the descriptor here which will be of type property descriptor as we learned.
So now we get these free arguments which we all used on log free which was our method decorator before
now.
In order bind I now want to make sure that we always set the this keyword to the object.
This method belongs to an yet.
Now how can we achieve this.
First of all I have to get access to the method which should be called and this will be possible with
the help of our descriptor because if you reload the app and you have a look at such a method descriptor
down there you see we get the value property in the descriptor and that points at the function because
the value of this property is a function in this case a method is just a property with a function as
a value.
So the value key holds the original function.
Therefore here we can extract the original method if we want to call it like this by accessing descriptor
dot value.
This will give us access to the well original method next.
I will set up a new adjusted descriptor.
This will in the end be what we return later.
Now this will be an object and it will be of type property descriptor.
Now in this object here we can add all the things we can't add to a property descriptor for example
can set this to configurable true set enumerable two false so that this doesn't show up in for in loops.
And now add a getter here that's new I added getter here which is a method or a property that holds
a function which is the same so that we can execute some extra logic when users try to access this property
so that we don't just directly execute the value of this properties.
So to function but that we can step in and do some extra work before we execute the function.
That's the idea here.
So I don't add a value property to this descriptor here.
I just have a getter and again the getter basically is like having a value property with extra logic
that runs before the value is returned.
Now in here I want to have my bound function where I can use the original method we extract up here
and we call bind and bind this and now the big question of course is what does this refer to in here.
Keep in mind it's instead of the scatter method.
So this will refer to whatever is responsible for triggering the scatter method and that's the trick.
Now the getter method will be triggered by the concrete object to which it belongs.
So this ends up off the getter method will always refer to the object on which we defined to gather.
This will not be overwritten by an event listener because the getter is like an extra layer between
our function that's being executed and the object to which it belongs and the event listener.
So therefore this in here will refer to the object on which we originally defined the method so we can
safely bind this for the original method and ensure that.
Now this inside of the original method will all the refer to the exact same object.
Now I will return a bone function year and thereafter outside of those adjusted descriptor returned
the adjusted descriptor.
So that's our decorator function returning a new descriptor object and therefore this descriptor object
will override the old descriptor.
That is what types will do with it types could will then replace the old methods descriptor so the old
methods configuration with this new configuration here which added this extra gather layer.
Now I'm not interested in target and method name here of course.
So to a wide area I will named as underscore in this your underscore to again just to tell typescript
dead.
I'm not interested in these values but I need to accept them.
And now let's add all of bind to show message here.
So here I will add at auto bind and make sure that you removed bind down there in the event listener
and safeties.
And now let's have a look at that.
Let's click click me and you should see this works.
If I reload this works because this is now bound correctly and just to verify that it's really our decorator
that makes a difference here.
If I would remove the binding here in my gat or any decorator and I save that you'll see that if it
does now reload and we click click me we see undefined again.
So it's really does extra gather layer which does its work here which ensures that this is always bound
correctly no matter how you call show message.
If we call it like this direct you on your object it will work.
If we call it here like this with an event listener it also works.
So you'll see this works here which in the end is coming from this show message call and then you also
see it works.
If I click on the button.
So this is one neat example of how you can utilize decorators to build a quite amazing functionality
and save you the hassle of manually calling bind everywhere.
Instead you just bind it like this.