So now that we saw another nice example for how we can work with decorators there is one last example
which I want to dive into and that is decorators for validation for that at the bottom of the file.
I will add yet another new class here and that could be a course now a course should have a title which
is a string and maybe a price which is a number and then here we have a constructor where we get both
values here and I'm deliberately not using the shortcut here so that I can easily add property decorators
and then I set this title equal to t and this price equal to P.
Now of course now when we want to instantiate this course we have to pass an invalid title and a valid
price.
But one common scenario you might encounter in some applications is that you fetch data let's say from
a web resource Ed you get data where you guess you have a couple of courses let's say but you don't
know for sure or another possible scenario you let users enter the data and you simply want to assign
that data and create a new course with the user enter data and you assume it's right but you are not
guaranteed that it's right and therefore you want to validate the input.
That's the scenario I want to fake here.
Let's say in our index age time I'll file we got a simple form here and I'll not style it.
So it will not be that beautiful but we have a simple formula with the input of type text in a place
holder of title scores title and an idea of let's say title and below that we have a number input where
to type is all the text but it's to cause Price sent the ideas price and then we have our button where
we submit this.
So the button is of type.
Submit.
So very simple form.
And as I said it's not that beautiful if we have a look at it here but it has everything we need.
Now let's hook up a listener to the forum here so here I got my cause form which I can get with.
Document query use selector form and I add the exclamation mark because I know it will get one.
So this will not be null.
And then on the form we can add an event listener the submit event listener and then we get the event
object passed into the function which I assign automatically there I want to call event prevent default
so that we don't submit the form and send no h he requests and then we want to extract the data for
the title and for the price.
So the title can be extracted by reaching out to document query selector or actually since we assign
an idea get element by Aidid
and we know that this will be an t input element so we can use typecasting to let typescript know about
this and the prize is document get element by I.D. prize and we can also convert this to an input element
and I actually do have for these are the elements so we'll renamed the to title L and price l it to
get the concrete title we can now go to title l access to value property and to get the prize we can
do the same for the price element and get the value there too.
And I want to have that as a number so I at the plus in front of it to convert it to a number.
Now that stat but now I want to create a new course with that information.
So here we have the created quarters where I can call new course and I pass in title and price.
Now typescript accepts this because title will be a string and since I convert this input to a number
price will be a number.
So if I then console lock de created course thereafter we can check if this works.
Let's save that reload maybe cleared a console so that we can clearly see the output and then add a
new course here javascript a complete guide cost one hundred ninety nine dollars.
And this seems to work now unfortunately does all the work still.
If I don't enter anything if I now click save we this cause is created.
Now this technically is a valid course but of course it's not really valid for our application.
We probably want to have a title which is not empty and a price which is greater than zero.
So we want to add validation.
Now of course we can simply add if check here and check if title trim length is greater than zero which
means it does not empty and where we also validate the price but that means that whenever we create
a new course we have to add the validation logic here before we added.
Wouldn't it be nice if the validation logic would be included in the course class with the help of decorators
maybe.
And that's exactly what I want to do here.
Now we'll only provide a basic idea of how we could implement this in the next module.
I will show you an example package which just is in a way more elaborate way and which we will then
also use there to play around with it a bit.
Now however here I want to implement this with my own decorators and it will add a decorator required
here and it will add another decorator function which I'll name positive number so I got two decorators
here and now my idea is that we can add them here to our properties for example required in front of
title and positive number in front of the prize and typescript kind of registers this somewhere and
then we got a third function validate to which we can parse object so any object and typescript then
has a look at that object finds any validation we've registered on this class for it as object earlier
and applies our validation logic.
That's the idea I have here.
So this could be part of a third party library we're exposing to you and then you just import required
positive number and validate to first set up the validators and then at some point call validate.
So for example here when we created the course we can call validate and pass in the created course.
And if this is not true so let's say this should return true or false if this is not true then we flow
an error or show an alert invalid input please try again and only otherwise we continue.
So that's my idea that we can call validate this returns to her false true if it's a valid false if
it's not valid and we can therefore use that result.
So therefore we get a couple of things to do we need to make sure that when we add a decorator here
this is somehow stored somewhere.
Again keep in mind this could be part of our own third party library.
So in there we could have some kind of storage that stores that for this class and for this title property
for example we want wanted to be required and invalidate we can then check if in this storage 40 object
we got for the class the object is based on we do have a validated registered for the title for the
price and so on and we then run our validation logic.
That's my idea here.