To implement this I will first of all trade interface validator config where I want to configure that
storage.
I have to work with my idea there is to have a couple of properties and hence I use this index type
notation here.
Which are basically strings where the value is yet another object.
Because this here would be basically the class name for which you want to register some validated properties
and then in the object which was stored there.
We have two concrete properties of the class that have validators attached to them.
So here we have the valid data bill property if you want to call it like this which also will be a String
key and then the value for that should be an array of strings where basically we have something like
required positive ends or something like that could be added here as a list of validators.
Now we can create our registered validators conflict here which should be of type validated conflict
which initially is an empty object because initially when the app starts when our third party library
gets loaded no validators have been registered yet well.
And then here in our decorators we want to add something to dead registry.
Now keep in mind that property decorator function gets two arguments the target which is the prototype
of the object the property sits on or the constructor function if it were a static property and the
property name.
These are the two arguments we get here we don't get the descriptor for properties.
Now we can go to our registered validators and dare I want to add a new entry for Target dot constructor
the prototype of the instance we're working with we'll have a constructor key which points at the constructor
function that was used to create our object and that day for will basically be something like course
here.
So the name of that constructor function and the end can be retrieved from the constructor because constructor
is a function we can use to name property which exists on any function in javascript to get the function
name.
And this then will be the course name here for example.
So now we were just had a class name as a key in registered validators and the value for that then should
be a number object so asset does equal to a number.
Object here and in that object I also have a dynamically assigned property where I use my prop name.
So the property for which I want to add a validator as a key and now the value here is an array of strings.
And here it will add required as a string.
Now of course this is a very naive validator.
If we had our validators registered for this property already I would now overwrite it here.
So it would be better to first retrieve any existing validators and then copy them into disarray and
only add required to that existing array again to save some time here and to just show me general idea.
I will have to more naive approach here was that we got the required annotation though let's now work
on the positive number annotation and of course that's basically the same.
I copy that code but I set this year to positive or whatever identifier you want to use.
And of course we have to make sure we accept the right arguments.
So with that alone with this what we added thus far we register these properties and they're validators
in our global conflict.
When this class is defined now we just need to work on the validate function the validate function should
go through all registered validators and then basically run different logic based on which validators
it finds.
So here first of all I want to retrieve the configuration for the concrete object we're dealing with.
For that we need to find out which constructor function the object is based on and then get D validation
configured a property validator mappings here which we set up for that object.
So you're all named as object validators or object validator conflict maybe and we reach out to the
registered validators here and access a property which should be object dot constructor dot name.
Same logic as before we access to constructor property which exists on the prototype of the object and
therefore we can access it directly on the object.
Thanks to our javascript works and thanks to the prototype chain we will then reach out to the prototype
if we can't find the constructor property on the object itself and that will work and therefore now
we got the constructor name and we find out that for example this course here is based on this course
class.
So we look up any validated configuration we have for the course class.
So now we're looking at this object basically.
This is now stored an object validator Conficker.
Now of course we might not find this if we're trying to validate the object for which nothing was registered.
So if we don't have any validated config if we don't find anything there I want to return true because
then this certainly is valid.
Right.
There is nothing to validate.
So the object certainly is valid.
Otherwise if we do find it I want to loop fruit is in your object here with a for in loop.
So with that I loop through my properties for which I registered validators with const prop in object
validator config.
This gives me access to all the property names for which we then might have validators.
So now of course I need to go through all the validators we might have for a property.
This always should be an array even if we only have one validator added so we can use a for off loop
here now and get the concrete validator which we have for the object validated conflict.
Ford is given property so now we're getting things like positive or required which are stored in the
validated constant then and then we could have a switch statement here.
Or of course call external functions based on which validated we find.
But here I'll go with a built in switch statement.
Switch on validator and then basically you have different cases.
For example the required case here was like this here I want to return True is our property which we're
looking at.
So this property on this object has a non empty value so I will return true if object prop is truly
and to convert this to a real true or false value we can use the double bang operator.
Now here types of complaints that it doesn't know whether object has this property.
So here we should actually change this to any to get this extra flexibility here.
Of course you could also work on the types here.
And for example also turn your identifiers here into clearly defined types where in comes you work with
and maybe all improved the typing here though to be honest since I want this to work with any object
it is hard to improve it in a way that types do will like it.
We could work with generic types.
But then again we would need to kind of restrict ourselves to which objects to generic types should
extend and accept them for.
So any might be our best option here to be really flexible and accept a lot of different objects in
this validate function.
Now back to the switch statement the required case is one possible case.
We also got the positive case which you want to handle and there are one to return true if the property
we're looking at is greater than zero.
So if object prop is greater than zero then does returns through.
Otherwise this will return false.
Now if we don't make it into this four block or if we somehow have a loop that doesn't loop through
anything because we haven't registered any validators we passed an empty array here or something.
So if we make it past this for loop I will return true as a default as well.
And now we return something in all circumstances and we can use validate with that.
Let's see whether it works.
If we now save this
and we reload our app here and I tried to submit this we get an error Invalid input please try again
if I enter some text here javascript that complete guide I still get this because my number is wrong.
If I enter minus one year we also get this because that's not positive.
If I enter a positive number however it works.
If I have a positive number.
But the first field is empty.
Then there's all the work.
So that's something we'll have to work on.
So let's find out what the problem is and to find out.
I actually will add a little console lock here and lock the property we're looking at.
We could of course all use breakpoints and the developer tools now click save.
Here you see the first thing which gets validated here is the price and thereafter we stop.
So the prize is the first property that gets validated and that's the interesting thing here.
The price is actually only property that matters here because we return invalidate.
That means the first time we find any validator that returns true or false we immediately return and
we don't care about the other validators.
Now in the false case this is OK because if one element is false if one properties falls is invalid
then we're fine not even looking at the others but for the true case it's a problem.
If we return true to first time one property meets our expectations we have a problem.
So we should enhanced this by having a is valid property here which initially is true is valid variable
I mean and then here we set is valid equal to is valid and this year and the same down deer set does
equal to this so that we don't return immediately.
Instead we just update is valid and we break their offer to not fall through the result of that is that
in the end after all these loops is valid evil is still is true but as soon as one of these checks here
is false thanks to our javascript works the overall is valid value will be false because true combined
with false will return false and then down there we should return is valid.
So now we ensure that all properties are checked and not just the first one.
JavaScript has a look at this however will not be our only problem.
We also have a problem here when we have a look at how we register our validate or logic.
I always overwrite the registered validators for a given class name with a new object.
Instead we should add any existing validators here.
So did we don't do that.
For example if the spread operator like that to take any existing key value pairs for that class name
only registered validators and add that first before we add our new one.
Also down there of course and now with that if we save this we go back to our application here.
If I have both empty we've failed.
If we enter a valid price but we have invalid title we fail.
If both is valid we succeed.
If we have a valid title but not price we fail also with the negative price and therefore it is not
looks good to me.
And this is now a first naive implementation of how such a validator could work with the help of typescript
decorators.
And keep in mind that all of that here all the decorators to validate function and the registry would
be hidden away from you.
That could be part of the third party library which you're working on of course in a more elaborate
way than probably which you share with your end users and you as an end user would just import these
things at these decorators and called validate and you would have a very convenient way of adding validation
to your class system.