Port hatched you find our good old starting Project.
I already started the server with NPM start and the hives go to watch process with TSC dash W and the
very first thing we need to configure there isn't a TSA conflict file.
Make sure your target is set to iOS 6 and then if you scroll down make sure that you add this experimental
decorators line here and add a comma in front of this and then you can auto format to format this all
correctly.
This is important.
Otherwise you won't be able to use decorators in your project.
So make sure you tweak your Ts config Jason File appropriately and with that we can dive right in and
to write our first decorator here in the apt yes file and I want to start with a decorator.
We can add to a class now decorators in general are all about classes but this is a decorator which
we will add to the class as a whole.
For now let's say we have a class person very trivial class where we have a name maybe with a value
of Max pre initialized here where we have a constructor function where I just log creating Person object.
So did we see that this is executed.
And then of course we can create a new person here with the new keyword like this.
And if you want to be kind of course locked is created person and this should hold no surprises if we
save all of that it compiled without errors.
And if we visit our page then on local host three thousand in the javascript console we see creating
Person object which is coming from that constructor and we of course also see the person itself here
now there.
In this example we got no decorators involved.
Let's change this at the top of the file let's add a decorator and a decorator and that's really important
to understand isn't the end just a function of function you apply to something for example to a class
in a certain way.
So let's create a function here with the function keyword and I will name it logger notice is a function
the only special thing here is that I start with a capital character.
This is not a must do by the way.
You don't have to use a capital starting character you can use a lowercase one as well you just see
a lot of decorators out there in libraries which you might use that use uppercase starting characters.
And therefore I'll do the same here.
So the logger function here is a function and we can apply is as a decorator as it will turn out.
Now let's add a console log in here.
Logging so that we can see when does function runs.
Because I will not call it directly.
Instead I want to add it as a decorator to this class.
And we do so by adding a at symbol here in front of the class.
And then our function here just like this no couple of special things here the at symbol here is a special
identifier typescript sees or recognizes.
And then the thing directly after the at symbol should point at a function not executed but point at
it which should be your decorator.
Now here you see that logger Dan accepts too few arguments to be used as a decorator here.
So the good thing is typescript understands that I want to use it as a decorator here.
The bad thing is we don't pass enough arguments and indeed decorators receive arguments how many arguments
depends on where you use the decorator here for decorator we add to a class we get one argument and
that's the target of this decorator so to say which is our constructor function so we can say we get
a function here as an argument in the end we could also name it constructor because in the end we will
get our constructor function of this class or whichever class we add this decorator to as our argument
lets all the console log that so that we can get some insight into this constructor argument here and
let's save this.
And as you see it compiles without errors.
And if we now have a look at our output we see the old code from before but we also see the logging
output and this constructor function being logged while we actually see the whole class here.
But classes in the end are just syntactical sugar over a constructor functions.
Please also note that our decorator output logging and this closet does constructor function log here
is printed first before we see creating Person object and our Person object because indeed decorators
and that's really important decorators execute when your class is defined not when it is instantiate
it you don't need to instantiate your class at all we could remove that code for instantiating the class
and we would still get death decorator output so the decorator runs when javascript finds your class
definition your constructor function definition not when you use that constructor function to instantiate
an object that's really important to understand.
So this is our first decorator it's not the only way of how we can create a decorator though.