Besides creating a decorator like this we can also define a decorator factory which basically returns
a decorator function but allows us to configure it when we assign it as a decorator to something to
show this.
Let's convert dysfunction here into a factory.
For that I will grab this constructor argument and remove it and instead in here it will return a new
anonymous function which takes that constructor argument which then holds this logic which I want to
execute inside of the decorator.
So I move that in there.
So now we have a function that returns a new function.
So now when we want to apply this decorator we have to execute it as a function here.
So did we execute does outer function.
And we attached a return value which is this inner function which is our valid decorator function as
a decorator to CLOs they offer.
Why would we do that.
Because now here for example we could except lock a string here which is a string.
Any argument of your choice and as many arguments as you want and pass a value for dead in logging person
and use that instead of our decorator function so that here instead of showing that standard logging
text we show our log string.
So now we can customize the values the decorator function uses when it executes with our factory function.
We now call our decorator here because we're not executing the decorator function but we're executing
a function that will return such a decorator function.
And the advantage just is that we now can pass in values which will be used by that inner returned decorator
function.
So if I now save that we see the old output but with our custom log string here.
So using decorator factories can give us some more power and more possibilities of configuring what
the decorator then does internally.