Now with the knowledge about factory functions or factory decorators we can do quite interesting stuff
we could create a new decorator factory with template.
For example and there I expect to get a template which should be some string and hook idea which should
all be a string.
And then here I return my anonymous function which is the actual decorator as you'll learned.
Because again I have a decorator factory in India.
I want to render some template which should be some H HTML code into some place in the DOM where I find
this hook idea.
So now we can go to index H Tim l. and add such a place so that we can see that this works can add a
div here with an idea of app maybe and then an apt yes instead of logger I add with template let's pass
an empty string as a first argument for now and app as a second argument.
So this idea I assigned to the div here and now inside of that inner function.
So our actual decorator inside of this decorator function I want to reach out to 2D element to the hook
element with document get element by ideas for the hook.
Ideas were getting here as argument and if hook L. is a thing that exists then I want Q access its inner
H Temple and set as equal to template.
Let's say a very simple setup of course but this should do the trick.
Now I'm not interested in the constructor and to tell typescript that I'm not interested here I can
add an underscore as a name which basically signals to typescript.
Yeah I know I get this argument but I don't need it.
I have to specify though.
So with this underscore I tell you that I'm aware of it but that I won't use it because all I want to
do for now is I want to render this here.
So now when we add with template here here we could add a h1 tag my person object like this all the
clothes it
and if we now save that it compiled without errors and indeed here you see this was rendered on the
screen.
And this hopefully shows you the the power you have with decorators you can build a really advanced
decorators like this one which all of a sudden does some magic behind the scenes and that is what I
mean with method programming.
We add some logic here which we could expose if this would be a third party library we share with our
users.
We could ex post as as part of the library and anyone who uses our library can import this decorator
function and add it to a class to then magically render some content all of a sudden.
And of course you're you're not even limited to that if you would want to output the name which is part
of the class when it gets instantiated you can do that as well.
We get our constructor function here after all.
Now what we can do with that is we can create a new person here by calling our constructor because that
is our constructor function here after all.
Let me convert it to any sort of typescript allows this and doesn't think it's a normal function.
And then we could go to our hook element and query for a h1 tag which we of course in practice will
not always have but for demo purposes I assume we will always have one here Whip's initial all the close
to H1 tacked on they are not as yet.
And then here with an exclamation mark.
Again assuming that we always find H one element we can set the text content equal to P dog name and
if I do that and safeties now I output the name which is part of the object here in the template.
So this is something you can do and of course you can write way more elaborate decorators than I'm doing
it here.
Consider angular a very popular framework that uses typescript they use decorators like this component
decorator to allow you to pass in an object where you specify things like the template for this component
and the selector in the DOM where this template should be rendered.
This is relatively close to what we defined here a template and then a place where it should be rendered.
Now needless to say the angular decorators are of course way more advanced and elaborate than our basic
decorator here.
Nonetheless the core idea is the same angular it gives you the decorators here so that you can specify
some HDL code which can be connected to your component class that will be rendered to the DOM when this
component gets rendered.
Now in case you don't know how angular works.
That's not a problem.
You just have to understand here that it works with classes and decorators and then it does.
Basically what we did here.
So that's one of the thing you can do with decorators or specifically here with decorator factories
because that allows us to pass in that extra corn flake which we need here.
And that's also what I meant with meta programming.
We're creating things we're creating decorator functions which you might say have some impact on the
end user.
In the end we do render something on the screen here but we do that with a tool which we expose to our
developers because this decorator is such a tool which our developers have to use by adding it to a
class in this example.
Otherwise this would do nothing.
So we provide extra utilities to developers which the other developers can use to for example conveniently
render something on the screen for a given class.
That's the same thing.
Angular does here in a more advanced way and it is something decorators are perfect for.