So we now saw a more useful decorator.
I want to conclude this very basic introduction to decorator with another important thing you should
know.
You can add more than one decorator to a clause or anywhere else where you can use a decorator.
So let's also add the logger decorator heater for example like this.
If we save that you see it compiles without errors and indeed we see the log message here as well.
This just leaves one important question in which order do these decorators execute.
Well for dad to find out let's for a log messages into both.
We do have a log message and a logger obviously.
Now let's go to the decorator function.
So to the inner function of with template and say rendering template for example.
And now let's see in which order these functions are executing and in which order these log statements
are printed and we see rendering template runs first and then we get the logger output.
Now what this tells us of course is that they execute bottom up the bottom most decorator first and
they're often the decorators above it with template runs first then logger executes an important.
I'm talking about the actual decorator functions.
The decorator factories here run earlier.
If we have logger factory here and we have the same log in the template factory.
So dare I say template factory in my log you will see that there actually the logger factory runs first
and then we got the template factory and that makes sense because in the end even though we get this
at symbol here here I'm executing a function and we're doing the same here.
And of course regular javascript rules apply here and dysfunction execution happens before dysfunction
execution which is why we see the logger factory before we see template factory.
So the creation of our actual decorator functions happens in the order in which we specify these factory
functions but the execution of the actual decorator functions then happens bottom up which means the
bottom most decorator executes first.
So this decorator function enter after the decorator above that executes it's just something you have
to know with that we got a solid base knowledge about decorators and you also saw a more advanced decorator
which hopefully also gives you a first impression of Y decorators can be useful especially if you also
think about frameworks like angular.
Now let's see to which other places besides clauses we can add decorators and what we might be able
to do their.