Now before we explore more useful use cases or scenarios for some decorators I want to briefly show
you all the other places where you can add decorators.
Well obviously we can add decorators to classes but there are more places where we can add them for
that.
I'll create a new class because we need a class for any decorator we want to use but we don't have to
add all decorators directly to the class.
Let's say we have a product class here and in the product class we have a title maybe which is a string
and we can assign a value here with the constructor.
Of course we could also use the shortcut and do it all in one step in a constructor.
As you learned earlier here will take the longer route.
We can have a method there get price with tax.
For Dad I expect to get a tax rate which is a number.
And for that to work we should also store a price here.
Price property which we also get as part of the constructor.
Again we could use a shortcut here but I'll do it like this.
And then in this method I will return this stock price times one plus tax so that we have this utility
method and we can also add a gather in the setter if you want to.
For example we can add a setter for the price here where we get the value which should be a number and
where we control that we can only set certain values.
Now to make this work I'll rename price up here to underscore price and make it private actually.
So we can't directly reach it.
And here I will set this underscore price and here I will use this underscore price.
And with these changes in the setter we can set this underscore price equal to the value we get.
But before we do so we can check if value is greater than zero.
So we don't accept negative prices.
So with Dad we only set the price if it's graded and zero.
Otherwise we don't do anything.
Indeed we could throw an error in the Abacus invalid price should be positive so that's something we
can do.
Now we have a class with two properties with an assessor and also with method here and this method has
a parameter now to all these things we can add decorators and let's start with a good old friend a log
decorator hero named Locke to not clash with logger up there because this log decorator will not be
added to a class and therefore it will get different arguments.
It will get arguments though and which arguments decorator gets depends on where you add it.
Which is why I can't reuse logger because Dad was fine tuned to only work with classes.
Now here I don't have a decorator factory actually I just have to decorator function like this but still.
Which arguments this decorator function gets depends on where we use it.
For example we can add a decorator to a property.
Here I can add log like this.
And if you add a decorator to a property the decorator receives two arguments.
The first argument is the target of the property.
And for instance property like this one which we call on for instance if we work with it this will be
the prototype of the object that was created if we had a static property here.
Target would refer to the constructor function instead.
So here I'll say any because I don't know exactly which structure does object will have the second argument
we get is the property name simply that could be a string here could of course also be a symbol.
We don't know what we use as a property identifier added here.
I will log property decorator so that we can see when does runs anyone a console log.
Target and also property names so that we see what's in these two values.
With that if we save that it compiles without errors and if we go to our server we see property decorator
gets printed down there and this is our output we get.
We see here that's the prototype of our object because we're not seeing title and price here but we
do see get price with tax and indeed methods are registered on the prototype of an object.
So that's the prototype of our object and we see title over here on the right that's the property name.
We're working with.
Now when exactly dust is logger execute though.
Well as you can tell since I never instantiate any product it executes basically when your class definition
is registered by javascript so it executes when you define this property basically to JavaScript as
part of your class here.
As part of this constructor function which is created here in the end this is when does property decorator
executes.