Now both sides properties.
You can also add decorators to accessories and there.
I will create a new decorator function because this will now receive free arguments.
Too.
It will also get the target which again is easier to prototype.
If we're dealing with instance excess or if we're dealing with a static one it will be the constructor
function.
So we don't know it will be of type any.
Then we'll have the name of the member we're dealing with so the name of the successor and the end end
will also have the property descriptor here.
Which will be of type property descriptor that subtype built into typescript.
So in there let's log accessed her decorator.
And then I will also console lock the target here.
Then maybe new lines to make that more readable in the output the name and also the descriptor.
Now let's add log to 2D setter here like this and let's see what we get if we save that you see down
there we get the successor decorator which executes here.
We got our prototype again the same as above for the property.
Then we got the name of our successor price.
In this case not underscore price.
So not the property with which it deals internally instead really the name of the accessory itself.
And we got a property descriptor here where we see that a setter function is defined for example a getter
function is not because for a price I only have a setter no getter.
And we see that it's not enumerable but that it is configurable so that we can change this definition
here for example that we can delete it and so on.
This all exists and this is how we can add add decorator to an accessory.
And what we then can access inside of this decorator now besides properties and accessories we also
got methods and we can add decorators to methods.
So here I'll add log free and add that to my method down there to get price with text.
And now the question of course is which arguments does such a method decorator receive a method decorator.
All the receives free arguments.
The target again which if it's the instance method is the prototype of the object.
If it's a static method the constructor function justice before then.
The name of the method here so string or symbol actually and also the descriptor at the end property
descriptor.
These are the free arguments we get here and you see these are the same arguments as in our assessor.
So indeed we could also reuse this but I will create a new one so that here I can print method decorator
knowing that if I save this does executes and you see here our method decorator executes and then here
we get our prototype same object as before we get the name of the method here and we get this descriptor
of this method here.
So the very same behavior as before basically just a descriptor is a little bit different since it's
a method descriptor and not an accessory descriptor.
We've got a value and a rival property here.
Previously on The successor descriptor we had get and set but that's just a javascript difference.
Nothing typescript specific.
So here we do have our third decorator function which we now added to a method the last decorator we
can add is to a parameter.
So let's do that now for that.
I'll create one more function here log for and then want to add log for two this one parameter I'm getting
here Tex.
And you could add one to every parameter you get of course.
You don't have to but you can add them independently to any parameter you want to add a decorator to.
Now what does a parameter decorator get as arguments.
Well it gets the target.
Same as before.
The next argument we get is the name and not the name of the parameter but the name of the method in
which we use this parameter.
So basically the same as in the method decorator thus far but the last argument is different.
This is now not the property descriptor but instead this is D position of his argument.
So the number of the argument here for example this would be the first argument.
So now again let's copy that here and put all of that into lock for parameter decorator and let's output
position here as well so that we can see what's in there.
We now save that we see our parameter decorator up there not the very lost output because execution
order is different but we see our parameter decorator here and then here we get the prototype as before
we get the name of the method where we use this parameter and then the index of that argument and that
starts at 0.
So the first argument has a number of 0 here an index of 0 and that's our parameter decorator.
So these are all the places where we can add decorators and TypeScript and we can do various things
with them.
Now I will show you a couple of examples in this module here and I'll also show you libraries or frameworks
that make heavy use of decorators and I'll show you what they do with decorators to give you an idea
of the power that decorators can have.