Before we dive into more examples let's understand the order in which decorators run though.
And here it's important to understand that first of all they're all running without us instantiating
this product or in other words if I create a product here with new product book for nineteen dollars
and x rated No product your book queue for twenty nine dollars.
This compiles without errors but my decorator code here doesn't run more often so it's not the instantiation
of this class that matters.
All these decorators no matter if it was a property decorator method decorator an excess or decorator
or a parameter decorator they all executed when you defined this class and that's important to understand.
These are not decorators that run at runtime when you call a method or when you work with a property.
This is not what they do.
Instead these decorators allow you to do additional behind the scenes setup work.
When a class is defined back to that meta programming concept I explained earlier.
Right.
That's the idea behind decorators or debts their core use case they're not event listeners you add to
something so that when you work with a property you can run some code.
You can make something like that work with decorators actually but by tweaking and editing something
behind the scenes.
But the decorator itself really is just a function that executes when your classes defined when your
method therefore is registered and so on and you can then use the decorator to do some behind the scenes
work to then set up some code that should run whatever it is called to add extra metadata or store some
data about a property somewhere else in your project or in your library which you're creating.
This is what you can use decorators for and that's all the pattern you'll kind of see when I now show
you these examples of what you could build with decorators.
They're adding extra functionality behind the scenes which then sometimes can execute when you do something
with your claws or with your method but which can also do totally different things.
That's all important for our person example from earlier with the with template decorator.
This does not add this template whenever we instantiate a person here.
It does added whenever we defined as class we would have to add extra logic instead of our decorator
function to change this behavior and to maybe just story this template in some other data structure
of our project which we then tap in to whenever we do create a new person here.
So we basically just set this up when we defined a class but we tend to store it behind the scenes internally
and we can then use it when we want to use it.
Right now we always rendered as when we defined as class not in view create a new instance.
This is how decorators execute and as I said Now I will show you a couple of examples where we take
advantage of decorators in general and off their execution time to do some nice things with them.