In order to do more advanced things with decorators you have to know that some decorators for example
class decorators.
But all the method decorators for example actually are also capable of returning something.
Now I'm not returning anything and any decorator.
I'm not talking about the decorator function which gets returned and the decorator factory.
I really mean a return value inside of the decorator function and we don't have any such value anywhere.
Now in this with template function in as with template decorator function I should say we could add
such a return value and what you can return and what typescript is able to use depends on which kind
of decorator you're working with.
Here we're working with a decorator that gets added to a class and in such a decorator function you
can return a new constructor function which will replace the old one so which will replace the class
to which you added the decorator you could say.
So here we can return a new function and you constructor function or simply return a new class in the
end because a class to class keyword allows us to use this syntactic sugar to create such a constructor
function and the class I created doesn't need to have a name but we can and we should extend the constructor
we're getting here.
So what I'm doing here now is in my decorator function here I'm returning a new class.
And again keep in mind that's just syntactic sugar for a constructor function.
So I'm returning a constructor function the end which is based on the original constructor function.
So did I keep all the properties of my original class of my original constructor function.
We don't necessarily have to do that but I don't want to lose my properties here so I will do it.
And then in here we can add new functionality for example and now we'll have to change some names here
I can add a new constructor function in there until wide confusion.
I'll rename the constructor I'm getting here so the class on which I added this decorator I'll name
this year.
Original constructor and copy that all over here and now instead of this constructor function here I
have to call super to call this original a constructor function from inside of it.
Because if you add a constructor function in a class that extends another class which is in the end
what we're doing here then you have to call super.
And now in here you can run any logic you want.
And for example here we could move this template rendering logic here out of our decorator function
into this new constructor function we're returning here.
So again really keep in mind that we're creating a class here which the end just creates a constructor
function with this logic in it.
So now what I'm trying to do is I tried to replace the class the constructor function to which we added
our decorator with a new class with a new constructor function where I still execute the old logic but
where I also add my own new logic and therefore now the template should actually only be rendered to
the DOM if I really instantiate my object here and not all the time when this decorator function is
executed which as you learned happens as soon as we defined a class.
Now a little tweak here I don't call my original constructor in here anymore.
Instead we can just access this start name to get the name property value off the instance we are creating.
Now we got a little complaint down there regarding the types not being correct to fix that though we
can turn our decorator function into a generic function where we get a type and set this as the type
of original constructor and now make clear that this will actually be basically a constructor function
and we can make that clear by assigning a special type an object type where we set a new property.
This is a reserved name of course but it tells typescript that in the end this will be an object which
can be nude.
So that will be a constructor function a function we can call with the new keyword to generate a new
object and this new function is new method which the object T is based on will have will get any amount
of arguments some using rest parameters here to accept as many arguments as you want so that we're really
flexible regarding the arguments that can be passed to the constructor of the class we're trying to
change and the new functional debt and yen return an object here.
Now I should also just copy that definition of the rest parameter to my constructor here so that this
constructor is also capable of accepting all the arguments we might be getting.
So we can basically instantiate person with any arguments you want to pass and you're with any arguments
we might also need here in the original constructor function.
And with that the only problem will face is that we don't know that such a name property exists.
And correct.
So we don't know to which class will add this with template decorator.
So we don't know if there will be a named property on the class we added to.
But we can fix this by simply telling typescript that the object T is based on.
So our original constructor function will not just produce any object but actually will produce an object
with a name property which will be of type String.
And that is correct.
Our with template decorator is added to a class which will have a name property.
If a would comment is out we would get an error because now we would try to add this decorator to a
class which does not fulfill this criterion.
But here this does fulfill it.
Now I get an error here when I tried to compile this because I'm not using args here.
We can change this to an underscore to tell typescript that we know we don't use it and that we want
to ignore this.
This is a valid parameter name.
It's just a special name which typescript takes as a I get it.
I need to accept it but I won't use it parameter and with that that all compiles and if we reload UC
we still see Max on the page here.
The interesting thing justice if we now remove that code very instantiate person.
If I comment this out so did I just to find a person class but I never instantiated anywhere you see
as it reloads.
We don't see Max on the screen all the decorators still execute but we don't render anything to the
screen anymore.
And the reason for that is that we now enhanced our decorator here even more by taking advantage of
its feature where we can return a new value.
Or in this case a new constructor function.
In the case of the class decorator This is a new constructor function or a new class which as I explained
is just syntactic sugar for the constructor function.
And this constructor function therefore replaces our original class our original constructor function
now since I call super in here.
We save dual original function we save the original class so everything we initialize here basically
still happens because I do that in my replacing constructor as well and I extend the original class
so we save everything that was in your original class.
You don't have to do that but I am doing it here because I don't want to lose that original data but
behind the scenes I replaced a class with my new custom class here and that allows us to add extra logic
that should run when the class is instantiated.
And now all of a sudden we are able to add logic that does not run when the class is defined.
But when the class is instantiated at this day offer should be a great first example of the full power
you can unleash.
With decorators if you really understand what you can do with them and you can not just to find them
as functions and you can not just to find them with factory functions in some decorator select the class
decorator you can always return something to replace the thing you add at the decorator to.
In our case to class with a new class that can implement the old class but also add its new custom logic
and with that if we comment this back in we again render Max to the screen with our own clause that
places or that extends and replaces the old class.