So earlier
in the section about control flow, you learned about various loops in
JavaScript. So in that section, you learned that if you want to iterate an array, you can
use the for of loop. So for, let,
number of numbers, now in each iteration
this number will be set to one of the elements in this array.
So, let's log that on the console.
We get 1, 2, and 3. There is
also another way to iterate an array, and you may see that approach in some
tutorials online. That is using the for each method. So
all these arrays have this for each method.
That takes a call back function. So we pass a function here,
this function takes a
parameter, in this case number, and in this function we can simply
log this number on the console.
So when we call the for each method, this function will
be executed for each element in the array.
Each element will be passed as an argument to this function.
So, save the changes, again we get 1, 2, 3. Now
as I told you before, we can use the arrow function syntax to simplify this code,
so we get rid of the function keyword, put
a fat arrow between the parameters and the body of the function,
and because we have a single parameter, we can remove the parenthesis,
and finally we need to remove this semi colon here because we don't have this
statement in a code block. So here's the end
result. Now which approach you choose is more of a
personal preference, there is really no significant difference between these
two ways of iterating an array. The only thing you need to know
is that this call back function, that we pass through the for each method, can
optionally take a separate parameter, and that's the index.
So here, I'm going to put number in parenthesis to add the
second parameter, that's index, now
when logging each number, or each element, we can also display it's
index. Save the changes,
and you can see the index of each element in front of it. We don't
get the index with the for of loop, but if you need that we can use the
for in loop. Again, its really a tiny issue, just be aware that we have
different ways to iterate an array.