Back to our
numbers array, in this lecture I'm going to change the order of these number so
they are not sorted, and then I will tell you how to sort them. So let's
change them to 2, 3, 1, and remove 1
now how can we sort this array? Very easy. You have this method called
sort and what this
method does is that it converts each element here to a
string and then sorts the elements in the array. So,
let's have a look, so console.log of numbers,
here's our numbers array sorted. Now another method sorted,
is often companion to the sort method is the reverse method.
And with this we can reverse the order or elements in an array.
So numbers.reverse
let's log it on the console one more time, now
we have 3, 2, 1. So this sort method is pretty useful.
It's very easy to use when you have numbers
and strings in an array. But when you have objects like
course objects, it doesn't work by default, you have to do some extra work.
So, let me delete this code here, and define another array.
Called courses, here I'm going to add two course objects
with id 1 and name, let's say
Node.js. And another course object
with id2, and name JavaScript.
Now let's say you want to sort this array by name
of courses. So JavaScript should come before
node.js. So look if I call courses.sort,
and then log it on the console,
nothing is going to happen. You can see Node
is still coming first. So how can we fix this problem? Very easy.
This sort method optionally takes an argument
and that's a function that is used for comparison. So what do we call
the sort method, this method gets two objects in this array,
let's say a and b, and compares them.
Now if they are in the right order, it will skip to the next few elements, otherwise it's going
to rearrange them. So here we need to pass a function,
for comparison, this function should take two parameters, we can
call them and a and b, or first and second, doesn't really
matter, because a and b is pretty self explanatory here.
Now, in this function, if a is less than b,
we should return minus 1, if a is greater
than b, we should return 1, and if they are equal,
if they are equal we should return 0. So to
implement this, you can write code like this. If a
.name, that's our first course is less than b.
name we're going to return minus 1, okay?
Now, the second condition. If a.name
is greater than b.name, we're going to return
1, otherwise we return 0. Now,
note that here I'm not using else if, because if the first
condition is true, this this return statement we're going to jump out
of this function. So the control will never move to this point.
So there's really no need to use the else keyword.
It's just adding extra noise in the code. So now, lets
run this code one more time, save the changes,
inspect this array, we can see that JavaScript is coming first. Beautiful.
However, if I change this j to a lower case
j, and save the changes, see what happens.
This time Node is coming first, so what's
going on here? Well, each character in a computer is
internally represented using a number. Let me show you.
So open up Google and search for
ascii table. That is asc with double
i. I remember when I was in university back in Iran, I had this lecturer
and he thought these double i's here, are two. So
he used to call this asc two. He had no idea that these i's
stand for information interchange. So ascii
is short for American standard code, for information interchange.
So that's ascii table, not asc two.
Now, take a look at the second link,
so on this table, you can see the numeric representaiton
of each character. So, we are looking at
lower case j, it's numeric representation is
106, and n which is used for our node course is
78. We can see 78 is less than 106, that's
why our Node course starting with capitol N came
first. Now to solve. this problem
we should exclude case sensitivity when comparing these names.
So, we can do something like this, you can declare two constants,
let's say nameA, and set it to A.name.
toUpperCase. So whatever the name of the first course is,
we're going to convert it to uppercase, and we're going to do the same
with the second course. Is I'm going to call the second constant,
nameE, and set it to b.name.
toUpperCase. Now we have toUpperCase keys, we can compare them.
Also, take into account that here we could call two lowercase
instead of two uppercase. That's perfectly valid, but what is important
is that both these names should be either
lower case or uppercase. Now finally we need to replace
the instances of a.name, with name a.
So I'm going to do multi cursor editing. I've selected a.name,
and I'm going to press command and d on Mac, or control d on
Windows. We have this second cursor here, as you can see,
Now we can delete this and replace it with nameA. Escape,
Finished. One more time I'm going to replace b.name
command and d, with name e,
and escape. Now save the changes
now our sort algorithm should work properly.
So JavaScript came first.