In this lecture,
I'm going to show you how to filter an array based on a search criteria.
So back to our numbers array, let's say you want to return only the
positive numbers. So, we can use the filter method,
like this. Filter. Once again we need to pass
a callback function, this function has three parameters,
value index and array. So
out of these we only care about value, we don't care about the index
because I just want to see if the number of the value is positive.
So function value,
now here we can write a simple expression like this,
if value is greater than or equal to 0. So when we call
the filter method, this method will loop through this array,
and execute this callback function for each number.
For each element, now if the element matches this criteria,
it will add this element to a new array, and finally
we can get the new array here. So filtered.
Let's take a look at the result, filtered,
so in our filtered array, we only have 1, 2,
and 3. Now earlier you learned about arrow functions, so this is a
good case where you would use an arrow function. You have a single line of code,
in this function, and we're simply returning a value. So,
we get rid of the function keyword, put a fat
arrow between the parameter and the body of this function. We don't
need the parenthesis because we have a single parameter, and because we're simply
returning a value, we can also exclude the return keyword,
as well as the curly braces and then
put everything on the same line like this. Now we can make
this code a little bit shorter, so in this case we can use an abbreviation
like v for value, or n
for number. Because it's obvious that we're working with the numbers
array. So we filter, and we get numbers where
number is greater than or equal to zero.
Now here we're dealing with an array of numbers, in a real world application, you will be
using an array of objects. For example,
here on the yelp website, you can click this button to
find only the restaurants that are open now.
So this is one kind of filtering. So if you want to implement something
like this, instead of an array of numbers you would have an array
of restaurants, and each restaurants has opening hours
so you could filter restaurants that are currently open
and return them.