Another
very useful and powerful method we have in JavaScript is
the map method. With this method we can map
each item in the array to something else. So
following from the example in the last lecture, we have an array of positive
numbers let's say we want to construct some HTML markup,
using the elements in this array. So we call filtered
.map and once again we need to pass
a callback function here. This function just like the function that we passed
to the filter method can have three parameters. Value, index,
and array. So in this case, again, we're going to work only with the value
so we can pass a function or an arrow function.
So we get a number
some html markup. So we can add a string,
with an opening list item element.
Then we add the number, then finally the closing
list item element. So with this markup, we can display each number
using a bullet point. Of course we need to put these inside
of a ul element, and I'm going to show you that in a second. So,
let's see the result of the map method. I'm going to store the
result in a constant called items, and
now, let's display this on the console. So,
you can see each number is now mapped to a string, that's
our list item. So now we have an array of strings, we can use
the joint method that you learned about earlier to join the elements of this
array and create a string. So, constant,
html, we set it to items.join and
then, display this on the console. Now instead of
an array we have a string. Notice that by default comma is
used as the separator, we don't want to have comma in our html markup,
we just want to combine these using an empty
character like this. Save the changes,
now comma is gone, the only bit that is remaining is the ul
element. So the very simple
implementation would be like this, you add ul
then concatenate it with all these items
and finally another ul.
Save the changes, and here's our
html markup to display all these numbers using bullet points.
Now later in the course I will show you a more elegant way to implement
the same thing, all I want you to take away from this lecture is that we can
use the map method to map each element in an array,
into something else. Now in this example, you are mapping these numbers to
strings, but you can also map them to objects, let me
show you another example. So I'm going to delete this html,
let's expand this a little bit more,
instead of mapping a number to a string, let's say you want to map them
to an object. So here I'm going to define an object
in this object we want to have a value property
and set that to this number. And finally you want to return
this object. Let's look at the result.
Oops, I made a mistake, I deleted the html
constant and that's why we get this error. Html is not defined.
So, let's display the items constant.
Now here's the result of our map.
We've mapped each number to an object with a value property.
Okay? So very useful when building real world applications.
Now let me show you something tricky here, in our callback function
we are declaring this constant and then returning it. Technically
we don't need to declare this as a separate constant, we can simply
put the return keyword here and return this object.
Because we are not working with that constant, with that object
constant, okay? So, save the changes, you still get
the same result, now earlier I told you that in your arrow function
if you have a single line of code and you're returning an value
you can exclude the return keyword as well as the curly braces.
So let's do that and see what happens. So remove the return key
word, and the curly braces and put
everything on one line like this.
Now, if we save the changes, we don't get the same result.
We get an array of 3 undefined elements.
The reason for this is by default these curly braces in
an arrow function, represent a code block. So when the JavaScript
engine tries to parse this arrow function it
thinks here we are defining a code block as opposed to an object
to return. So if you're returning an object
you need to put that object in parenthesis.
Like this. So, we put this object in parenthesis.
And with this our JavaScript engine will not look at this as a code block.
Now save the changes, now once again you get
3 objects. And one last thing before
we finish this lecture. So you have noticed that both the filter
and the map method return a new array, they
don't modify the original array,
these methods are chainable which means we can call them one after another
in a chain, so in this case,
this filtered constant is only used here. We haven't used this
anywhere else in the code. So we don't have to explicitly store the
result of this statement inside
a separate constant. We can get rid of this,
we call the filter method, now we don't want to have a semi colon here because
we are not going to terminate this statement. Instead we're going to
immediately call the map method on the result
that is returned from this statement. So,
I'm going to copy our map method here.
This is what we call chaining.
So we're calling 1 method, that method returns some
result, now we're immediately calling the map method on that result.
Now, when chaining multiple methods, by convention we put
each method call on a separate line, and this makes our code cleaner.
Have a look. So, numbers.
filter and then.map and
so on. And finally we store the result in the items.
That's a better and cleaner code.
Save the changes, we still get the same result.
Great, now note that here because the map method is
retuning a new array, again we can call the filter or the map method
on that array. So here we can call the
filter one more time, we get an object, and maybe we want to get objects
with value greater than 1. See what
happens? Now in the result we have only 1 of 2 objects
in our array, objects with value 2 and 3, and again we can
call the map method and maybe map each object
to a number. So to read the value property
and return it, save the changes, now we have an array of
2 numbers. So this is the power of
chaining these methods.