Once
again with our array of numbers, let's say we want to calculate the
sum of all these numbers in this array. This will be similar to calculating
the total cost of all the items in a shopping cart. So each
numbers here should represent the price of an item in a shopping cart,
of course we wouldn't have a negative number there, but you get the point.
So here's a very simple algorithm for calculating the sum of all the
numbers in this array. You start by declaring a variable
called sum and we initialize it to 0. Next we
loop over the array, get each element for each number
and add it to sum. Something like this.
for let n of numbers, now we want
to add n to sum. So we can write an expression like this. Sum
= sum + n, or a better way is to
use the addition assignment operator. So we can
exclude the second sum, so this is exactly
like the statement we had before, and finally we
display sum on the console. So,
we get 5. Now there is a cleaner and
more elegant way to write the same code using the reduce method in arrays.
So all these arrays have this reduce method,
and with this method we can reduce all these elements in an array
into a single value. That single value can be a number,
it can be a string, it can be an object, it can be anything. In this example,
we want to reduce all these elements into a single
number, that is the sum of all the numbers in this array.
So let's see how we can use the reduce method. This method takes
a callback function with two parameters.
Accumulator and current value.
So here I'm using an arrow function. Like
this. This accumulator parameter here is exactly
like this sum we have here. It's something that we initialize
and this callback function is executed multiple times,
each time this currentValue will be set to one element
in this array. So in each call, we want to get this current
value and add it to accumulator. So we simply return
the sum of accumulator plus
currentValue. Now internally, this reduced
method will get this result and store it in the accumulator
you will see that in a second. And one last thing here,
is to initialize this accumulator to 0. So,
as the second argument to the reduce method, we pass
0. Note that this reduce method has two arguments, the
first argument is a callback function, and the second argument is
the initial value for the accumulator. Finally
we get the result as a single value.
In this case, sum. Now we don't need this code anymore
and finally let's bring
this console.log here.
Save the changes, you can see we get the same result
5, but let's see what exactly is happening here.
So, initially we set accumulator to 0,
so I'm going to set a=0. In the first round,
current value will be set to the first number. So,
c=1. Now we add this together,
so we get 1 and a will be set to 1 after
this call back function is executed. So,
as a result a will be 1. Now in a second
round, a is 1, current value will be set
to the second number in this array. So, minus 1.
Now once again we add them together, now a
will be 0 after the second call. Now the third call
so a is 0, the current value is going to be
set to the third element in this array. So 2
and as a result a will be 2, and finally
in the last call, we start with a set to 2,
and current value will be 3. So,
the result will be 5, and that's why we saw
5 on the console. So essentially with this reduced method,
we start with an accumulator, then we loop through this array,
and convert all these elements into a single value, which
is in this case accumulator, or the sum of all the numbers
in this array. Now we can make this code even shorter. We can
exclude the initialization of the accumulator,
and with this, accumulator will be set to the first element.
So let me show you what will happen. A will initially
be set to 1. And current value will be set to -1.
That is exactly like our second call here.
Right? So as a result, a will be set to 0,
now in our second round a will be 0,
and current value will be 2, because in the previous
call, current value was here, so now we are here. So current value will be
2, and as a result a will be 2, and
finally, in the last call, a will be 2, and current value will be
3. The last element in this array
and once again we get 5. So if we supply
an initial value we'll have one more call, if we don't
the first element in this array will be used as the initial value.
So this is how the reduce method works. And finally, to make this
code a little bit shorter, we can get rid of this return keyword,
because we have a single line, but we are simply reducing a value.
Remove the return, the semi colon and the curly braces
put everything on a single line,
like this. So with this single line of code, we
reduce the numbers array and this is how our reduction
algorithm works. We simply get the current value and add it to our
accumulator. This is far cleaner and more elegant then
declaring a sum and then looping
over this array like let n of numbers and then
add n to the sum, that's a very
old way of writing code.