Alright now
our second exercise. So here we have an array of numbers, you have seen
includes method before. So console.log
numbers.includes. With this method we can check to see
if a given element exists in the array. Now,
your exercise is to write a function like
the includes method. So imagine we don't have this method in arrays, your
job is to implement this method yourself. So, I want you to
create a function called includes
that takes an array and a search element.
If we have the search element in the array we should return true, otherwise we should
return false. So, pause the video, do the exercise,
and when you're done come back and continue watching.
Alright so here we need to iterate over
this array. If you find an element that equals the search
Element we're going to return true, otherwise we're going to return false.
Very very easy. So, for, we're going to use the
for of loop. So for let element of
array, now if element
= the searchElement,
we're going to return true, so we don't need to search
the rest of this array, we immediately returned true. Otherwise we get
to this point that means we didn't find this element in the array, so,
we return false. Now let's test this.
So, I'm going to call the includes function,
pass our numbers array, as the first argument.
And 1 as the second argument. Obviously we have these numbers
so we get true, but if we pass -1 we get
false.