Alright this
exercise is a little bit tricky, but trust me it's absolutely
worth spending time on it, because it trains your programming brain.
So we have this function called move, and we use that to move
an element in an array. So this is how it works, we give it an array
the index of the element we want to move
and an offset. So in this case, I want to move the first
element in this array that is 1. Now I'll pass 0 as the
offset, so with this nothing is going to change, we're going to get the same array.
However, if I pass 1 as the offset,
see what happens here. So 1 moves 1 position to the right.
If I pass two as the offset, 1,
ends up here, if I pass 3, it ends up being at the end of the array,
if I pass anything more than the length of the array, that is for,
I get this error, invalid offset. Now to display
errors like this. I should use another method called console
.error. So you seem to pass this string,
and that will end up as a red message on the console.
Now also note that this offset can be a
negative number. So let's say we want to move this second element
1 position to the left. So we set index to 1,
and offset to -1.
So 2 moves to the beginning of the array, if I pass
-2 as the offset, because it can't jump out of the array,
once again, we are going to get this error, invalid offset.
Also note that in all these examples the original array
is unaffected, so we get a new array with items
reordered. So, spend 10-15 minutes on this exercise,
and when you're done come back and continue watching.
Alright so I've reset these numbers
to 0 and 1, so we want to move the first element in this array,
1 position to the right. The first thing we want to do is copy this
array, because we don't want to modify it. So, that's where we use the
spread operator. I'm going to define a constant,
called output. Set it to a new array, and then
I'm going to spread the original array,
so this will be a clone of the original array, okay? Now,
as part of moving an element, first, we need to remove it from the array,
and then we need to place it back at the right position.
To remove an element from an array, we use the splice method, you have seen
that before. Splice. So we get
the given index and delete 1 item.
Now look at the return value of this method. It returns
an array. So the items that are removed will be returned as an
array. In this case, we're removing 1 item so we can access
the first element in that array, and that would return the element
that we just deleted. So let's store that in a separate constant
the reason I'm storing it here is because next we need to
add this back to the array. Now we want to add this
at a specific position. Once again you need to use the splice method.
So output.splice
now where are we going to place this. We want to go to index plus
offset. Now we don't want to delete any
of the items here, so we pass 0, and finally we pass
this element that we want to place in the array. And
finally, we return the output. Let's test this
so if you move the first element 1 position
to the right, we get the right result, beautiful, if you move it
2 positions to the right, it ends up here, if you pass 3,
it ends up being at the end of the array. If you pass 4,
we don't get the error that I told you you should produce, but the output
is still the same. Now to solve this issue we need to come back here and do some
basic validation before running this algorithm
for moving an item. So we can do something like this, we define a
constant call it position, that is the new position
and that's going to be index + offset, exactly the
same value we have used here. So we can express this expression with position,
now we have position, we can check to see if
position is greater than or equal to
array.length. So in this case our array has 4 elements
if you pass 4 or a greater value, we should see the error
on the console. So here we add the code block, console.
error invalid offset.
And finally we return, so the rest of this function is not
executed. The other option would be to take an else block here.
But that means you have to put this
code inside this block, there's going to be a bit of indentation,
this is really unnecessary, because if we return here, none of the
code here will be executed. So we can get rid of the else keyword instead of the
code block and extra indentation.
So, if you pass for, you should get
error beautiful. Now, let's pass 0,
so we're not going to move this element, we get the original array, beautiful,
if you pass -1, we get some weird results.
In this case one should not jump out of the array, so
we need to change our validation logic here to something like
this. So if position is greater than or equal to the lengths
of the array, or position is a negative
number. Then, we should display the error, save the changes,
beautiful, then let's test this with another
value. So I'm going to work on the second element here. So let's change
0 to 1. We're going to move this 1 position to the left
save the changes, 2 comes here, beautiful, if you pass
-2, again we should get the error, here's the error, perfect,
now let's change this back to 0, so we get the original
array, if we pass 1, 2 moves here, if we pass
2, 2 moves to the end of the array, if you pass 3, you should get
error. And here's the error, beautiful.