Alright now
I want you to create a function called count occurrences.
This function takes an array and search element
and turns the number of times that search element has occurred in this
array. For example, here in our numbers array, we have
a single instance of 1. So if you call this function and pass
1, we get 1, if I add another 1 here,
now, we can see we have two instances of
1. Or if we call this function with a number that does not exist
in the array we get 0. So,
start with the simplest implementation for this function, once you get that working
then to challenge yourself implement this function using
the reduce method in arrays. Because here essentially you're reducing this
entire array into a number, and that number
represents the number of times a given element has occurred in our
array. You will see my solution next.
Alright here's the basic
implementation. So we declare account variable, and initialize it
to 0. Now we need to iterate over this
array. And if you find this search element, we're going to increment
count. At the end of this function we'll return count, very easy.
So, for let
element of array, now if this element
= the search element,
we simply increment count. And finally
we return count. So that's the most basic
implementation. Now let's see how we can use the reduce method to achieve the
same thing with less code. So instead of this implementation,
we are going to use array.
reduce, here we need to pass a callback function with two parameters.
Accumulator, and current.
And this goes to this code block.
So this accumulator represents the number of
times the search element has occurred in our array. So I'm going to initialize
this to 0, like this,
now, every time this callback function is called, you want to
compare this current value with search element. If they are
equal, we should return accumulator plus 1, otherwise we should return
accumulator. So we can do something like this.
We can find a constant called occurrence. Now
if current equals searchElement,
okay I'm going to use the conditional operator, so
if they're equal, I'm going to add 1 to accumulator, otherwise I'm going to add
0 to accumulator. And finally, you're going to return
accumulator plus occurrence. Now
let me show you how this works. So let's do a console
.log, you're going to log 3 values, one is our
accumulator, and the other 2 are current as well as
the searchElement. And one last thing we need to
do here is to actually return this value.
So, let's inspect this program, here
in the console you can see this callback function has been called
5 times. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and here's the result.
Because we don't have -1 in this array. Now let me change
this to a value that we have so you can see exactly what is happening under
the hood. So I'm going to change -1 to 1, save the changes,
now let's see what's happening. So, in the first round, our
accumulator is 0. Current is 1, so is
searchElement, so accumulator is incremented by 1.
So in the second round accumulator is 1, current is 2, and our
searchElement as you can see is always 1. So as you can see, these two numbers,
are not equal, so accumulator is not changed. So we simply return
accumulator plus 0. We want to make sure
we keep this number as we go through this array. Now finally
in the last call, you can see accumulator is still 1 and
in this case the current value and the search element are equal, so
accumulator is incremented by 1, and that's what we get out of this
reduced method.