Alright here's
another exercise, in this exercise I want you to create this function
getMax, we give it an array and it returns the largest
number in that array. So if we give it this array of
numbers. It returns 4.
If we give it an empty array, it returns
undefined because we don't have anything in this array. So we cannot return 0 or
a negative number because none of these values exist in this array.
So go ahead, do this exercise, start with a simple implementation
once that implementation is working, then to challenge yourself,
implement this function using the reduce method in arrays.
You will see my solution next.
Alright so let's start with a simplest
implementation. First we want to check to see if this array is
empty or not. If it's empty, we're going to return undefined.
So, if array.length equals
0, you're going to return undefined.
Also, note that by convention, sometimes if you have
an if statement with only 1 line after, some
developers prefer to put that line right next to the if statement.
Some developers format it like this. It's more of a personal
preference. There's really no right or wrong. So I'm going to put this on the same line,
now otherwise we have at least 1 element
in this array. So I'm going to declare a variable, call
it max and set it to the first element in this
array. So we want to assume that the first element is the largest
number, next, we will iterate this array, and if we find a number that is
larger, then we're going to reset this max variable.
So, let's do a for loop, let
i, we start from the second element in this array, and run this
loop as long as i is less than the length of the array.
Then we increment I, now we need to check to
see if the current number is larger than max. So if
array of i, is greater than
max, then we're going to set max to this current
value. Okay? Finally after this loop,
we want to return max. So that's the simplest implementation,
if you're on this code, and pass an empty array here we
get undefined beautiful. If you pass an array with only 1 number
we get that number, if we add two numbers here,
2 is the largest number, let's add
a few more values here, now we should get 3, beautiful,
so our basic implementation is working, now let's reimplement this method
using the reduce method. So we want to keep the first
line as is, so if you don't have anything in this array we want to return
undefined. Otherwise let me
comment out this code, so we can compare them side by side.
So, we use array
.reduce. We pass an
arrow function with two parameters, accumulator,
and current. And that goes to
this code block here.
So you know that if we don't pass an initial value,
for the accumulator, by default it will be set to the first
element in the array. That is exactly like what we have on line
11. So in the body of this arrow function,
you want to check to see if the current value is greater than
what we have in accumulator, exactly like what we have here. If it is,
then we want to return the current value, otherwise we want to return
accumulator. So, we can right
code like this. If current is greater. than accumulator,
we want to return current. Otherwise we return
accumulator. Now we can rewrite
this using a conditional operator. So let me
expand this. So instead of these two lines,
we can do something like this. Return, we add our condition,
which is current greater than accumulator, if that's the
case, we want to return currents, otherwise we return
accumulator. That is cleaner, right? Now we
can make this code even cleaner by renaming these two
parameters to something like a and
b. So basically we're reducing this array, we get
2 elements at a time, if b is greater than a, we're going to return
b, otherwise we're going to return a. Actually, I personally
prefer change the order of these operands
so I would like to say if a is greater than b,
then I want to return a, otherwise I want to return b.
That is very easy to understand. Also, because we have a single line of
code here, we're simply returning a value, we can get rid of the return
keyword, as well as the curly braces, bring everything
on one line,
and here's the end result. So basically
you can see this line of code is equivalent to all these lines here.
That is the beauty of the reduce method. So this
is what I want you to take away from this exercise. Any time you have an
array of values and you want to get a single value as a result
of iterating that array, think of the reduce method. In this
case, we're finding the largest value in this array, so we're reducing this array
into a single value. Alright now
finally, we need to return whatever we're getting from the reduce method.
Now, let's test this and make sure every
thing is working. So, I'm going to save the changes, we still get 3,
if I pass an empty array, we get undefined
beautiful.