Alright now
let's see how we can find elements in an array. Finding elements really
depends on if you're storing primitive or reference types
in an array. So I'm going to start with primitives because they're easier.
And then I will show you how to find reference types in an array. So,
let's say we have an array of numbers,
with 4 elements. 1, 2, 3, 4.
Here we have a method called
index of, we pass the element
we are looking for, and if that element exists in the array,
this method will return the index of this element in the array.
If it doesn't exist, it will return minus 1. Let me show you a
few different examples. So first I'm going to pass the character a,
obviously we don't have this element so the result that we'll see
will be minus 1.
Look, so index of returns the index of the
given element in this array. However, if I change this to
1, we get 0, because the index
of this element is 0, note that the type of this
element matters, so if I pass 1, as a string here,
again we get minus 1, because we don't have 1 as a string
in this array, we have it as a number. Okay? Now similar
to index of, we have another method called last index
of. And that will return the last index of the given element
or minus 1 if it doesn't exist. So to demonstrate this,
I'm going to add another 1 here, now,
let's do another console.log, numbers
.lastIndexof 1.
Save the changes. So the last index of is 3,
because it's here, and the index of this element is 3.
Okay? So basically to see if a given element
exists in an array we can do something like this. Console
.log numbers.indexOf
1 is not minus 1.
If this expression returns true that means
this element exists in the array. Let's have a look, save the
changes, we've got true here. But this is a little bit ugly,
we have a new method in JavaScript for achieving the same thing.
So, console.log numbers.
includes 1. This simply
returns true if the given element exists in the array. Let's have a
look, so save the changes and we get true here.
Now, all thee methods have a second parameter which is optional.
And that is the starting index. For example,
with index of let's change this to 1 as
a number, so save the changes, you can see the index of 1 is
0. Because it's here, right? However, I can
pass a second argument here, that second argument is
from index. And that's the index from which the search
will begin. So I can pass 2 here, so that is
0, 1, 2, our search will begin here, let's see what we get. Save the changes,
so we get 3 which is the index of
the second one in this array.