In the last lecture
I told you that finding primitives is different than finding
reference types. So let's see why. I'm going to start by declaring
a new array called courses, and in this array we're going to
have a couple of course objects. So
here's the first one with two properties, id and name
the name doesn't really matter, now we can duplicate this line,
by holding down shift, alt, and the down arrow.
So, let's change these values,
id2, and name b, and don't forget the semi colon here.
so we have two course objects here, let's see if we have
a course with the name a in this array, the includes method
that you learned in the last lecture will not help us here. Now, let me show you.
So courses.includes
here we pass the object that we're looking for. So,
course with id 1, and name a.
Now, let's log this on the console. Console.log
save the changes, we get false,
the reason for this is because these two objects.
That is the object that you are passing to the includes method, and the
object that we have in the courses array, these are two different
objects. They have two different references, they're in two different
locations and memory. And in the last section, you learned that objects
are reference types so when we check them for their equality, the references
are checked. In this case, there are two different references, that's why we get
false. So if you have an array with reference types, you need
to use the find method. Let me show you. So I'm going to delete
this line, courses.find.
Now look at the parameter of this method. What we see is
way to complicated. So, whenever you want to learn about
an object or a function in JavaScript, simply search for that.
javascript array find
Here the first link is from developer.
mozilla.org. So, that's a good reference,
here we can find a good description of what this method does and
a very simple example of using that method. So here we have
an array with a few numbers. We're calling the find method
note that as an argument to this method we have to pass a function.
We call this function a predicate, and we use that to
determine if the given element exists in an array
or not. So, this function takes a parameter, that's an
element in this array. And in the body of this function,
we should return a boolean. So here we have a simple expression
if this element is greater than 10, we'll return true
otherwise we'll return false. So this is what happens when we call
the find method and pass this function. This function is
executed once for the first element in this array. So
in this case 5 will be passed here. 5 is not greater than 10
so we'll return false, and the search will continue. Now this
function will be called for the second element in this array. So,
12 will be passed as an argument to this function, and because it's
greater than 10, we'll return true and the search will stop here.
So now, what we'll get here as a result of calling the
find method is the first element that matches this
criteria. So if you log this found variable on the console,
we'll get 12. Now in contrast, if there are
no elements in this array that matches this criteria, we'll get
undefined. Let me show you. So,
back to our example, let's say we want to see if we have a course with the name
a in this array. So we pass a function.
Here, we call this a predicate or a callback
function, because the function is called back as part of
finding an element in this array. So here we should have a parameter,
we can call that element, or course, because
each element in this array is a course object, so it's better to be
more explicit, that makes our code more readable and understandable.
So, what is our criteria? We're
looking for a course with the name equal to a.
So, we simply return this and
let's store the result in a constant called
course. And finally let's log this on the console.
Here's the course object, save the changes,
and that's the course with the name a. We get the complete course object
that we have in this array. Now if I
change the search criteria to something like this. xyz,
obviously we don't have a course with this name, so when we save the changes,
we get undefined. So here's our find method, it returns
the first element that matches this criteria. We have a
similar method called find index, it works exactly the same
but instead of returning the actual object, like the course object, it will
return it's index. Let me show you. So I want to change this to find
index, in this case we don't have a course with this name,
so, when I save the changes, we should see minus 1 on the console.
Here it is. Now if I change this back to
a and save the changes, we get 0, because the index
of the first element that matched this criteria is 0.