In the last
lecture you learned about this predicate function that we passed
on the find method. In ES6 there is a shorter
cleaner way to write the same code using arrow functions.
So whenever you want to pass a function, as a callback function or as an
argument for a different method, you can use the arrow function syntax.
Let's see how that works. So,
you remove the function keyboard, and to separate the parameters
of this function from it's body with a fat arrow,
in between them. This is what we call an arrow function.
Now if your function has a single parameter, we can also get rid of
the parenthesis, and this makes your code cleaner, you're removing the
noise in the code. If you don't have any parameters, you have to
pass an empty parenthesis. In this case we have a single parameter
so I'm going to bring that back, and finally
if you're function is a single line of code and is returning
a value, we can male this code even shorter. First
you get rid of the return keyword, and then you remove
the curly braces, like this. And finally you can put everything
on one line. So here's the end result.
You read this expression as course goes to
course.name equals a. So basically we are
finding a course with the name equal to a.