Alright now
let's see how we can remove elements from an array. So,
start by declaring a new array, numbers, and we
set this to 1, 2, 3, 4. Earlier
in this section you learned about 3 methods to add new
elements to an array. You learned about the push method,
which we use to add something at the end of an array.
You learned about the unshift method that we use
for adding elements at the beginning of an array, and the splice method
that we use for adding an element somewhere in the middle. Now,
when it comes to removing an element, again we can remove an element from
the End, from the beginning and
from the middle. Middle. But instead of
the push method, we use the pop method. This will remove the
last element in this array and return it. So let's
store that in a constant called last. And
here I'm going to do a console.log of numbers, so you can
see the array after we've popped the last element. And also I'm going to show you
this last element. Save the changes. So,
here's our array, 1, 2, 3, and you can see the last element is
4. Now, if you want to remove an element from the
beginning you use the shift method. Similar to the
pop method this will return the element that was removed.
So, we can store that in first, and
let's have a look here, save the changes.
So the first element is 1, now if we log numbers
we only have 2 and 3. Pretty easy. And finally
the splice method you learned about earlier, so
if you want to remove an element somewhere in the middle
you pass the index of that element. So let's say we want to
remove these three here. The index of this element is
2, so we pass 2 here, and as the second argument,
we pass the number of elements we want to delete.
We can remove 1 element, and then
let's log this on the console, numbers, save the changes
actually the result is confusing, so I'm going to comment out,
these two lines so we work with our original array,
let's have a look, so let's note that three is removed
we have 1, 2 , and 4. Now if you want to delete multiple
elements, you pass a value greater than 1. So you can delete
2 elements, starting from index 2.
Save the changes, so 3 and 4 are removed and we only have
1 and 2. So, to recap, use the
pop method to remove the last element, use the shift method to remove the first
element, and the splice element to remove an element somewhere in the
middle of an array.