In this exercise
I want you to create a function called countTruthy which
takes an array and returns a number of truthy elements in this array.
Now what are these truthy or false values, let me
quickly refresh your memory. Sometimes when we have an if
statement, we might pass a boolean true or false
as the condition here, for example we might have a constant called
isActive, we set this to true, and when we use
this constant as the condition here, we get
this Hello message on the console. Because this
is a boolean true. But sometimes what we have
in our if statement is not necessarily a boolean value, it could
be a string, it could be a number, it could be an object, so the JavaScript number
engine tries to convert that value to something that is like a boolean
but is not a boolean. Here's an example, let's say I have a constant,
called name, I set this to a string, Mosh.
Now if I pass name here, obviously name is
a string, it's not a boolean true or false, so the JavaScript engine
tries to interpret this as truthy or falsey
so when we run this code you can see we still see the hello
message, because we are dealing with a string of characters.
So this is what we call a truthy value. It's
not the boolean true, it's truthy. In contrast,
if we had an empty string, JavaScript engine would
save this as falsey. Again, it's not the boolean
false. It's falsey. Now when we run this code,
you no longer see the Hello message. So that's all about truthy and falsey
values. Now let's quickly review the list of falsey
values in JavaScript. So undefined
null. Empty string. The boolean
false. 0 and not a number.
You learned about this value in an earlier exercise, that's something that I forgot
to mention when I talked about all the falsey values in JavaScript, but
this is the complete list of falsey values in JavaScript.
So now, your job is to create a function called
truthy that gets an array, and returns the number of
truthy values in this array. So here's an example, if I declare
this array, and set it to 123,
so here we have 3 truthy values. We call
countTruthy, pass the array, and immediately
send the result to console.log. Save the changes
so we get 3 here. Now if we add
0 here, because 0 here is a falsey value,
we still get 3. If you add null, undefined and empty string,
we still get 3. If I remove 1 of these numbers, let's say
1, we get 2. So
go ahead, do this exercise. And when you're done, come back and continue watching.
Alright, to count the
number of truthy values, first I'm going to declare a variable
called count, and initialize it to 0. Now
we need to use a for of loop to iterate this array,
and for each element we need to check to see if that element is truthy
or not. If it's truthy, we're going to implement count.
So, for let value of
array. Now, if this value
is truthy we simply increment
count. And finally we return this count.
That's all the code you had to write. So note right here I'm not comparing this
value with all those false values. In other words,
I didn't write code like this, if value is not
false, or value is not undefined
this is a very pour way of writing this code.
We don't want to have 5 conditions here for every
false value. Simply pass this value here, now that value
might be a boolean, or a non boolean, if it's not a boolean,
the JavaScript engine tries to interpret it as truthy
or falsey, so if the result is truthy, then
the count will be incremented earlier than that. A simple as that.