This exercise
is a very popular exercise for junior programmers. So,
we have this function, show stars, with a parameter called
rows. So when we call this function and pass 5, see
what we get on the console. We get 5 rows,
in each row we have a star, and the number of
stars in that row, depends on the row we are in. So in the first row we
have one star, in the second row we have 2 stars, and so on.
If you call this function pass 1, get only a single star,
if we pass 2, we get 2 rows, if we pass 10,
you got the point. So go ahead and spend 5-10
minutes on this exercise, when you're done, come back and continue watching.
Alright, here we need to start
with a for loop, so for let row
we set this to 1, as long as row is less than or
equal to the number of rows, we want to increment row.
Now in each row, depending on the number of
row, we need to display one or more stars.
So here I'm going to declare a variable, it's called a pattern,
we set it to an empty string. Now depending on the value
of the row, we need to add one or more stars to this
pattern. So here we need another for loop, or
let, let's call this i, set it to 0,
as long as i is less than row, increment i
and here we add a star to the
pattern, so plus equals star. So if you're
on row 5, this loop will execute 5 times, because
we've started from 0, and we run this while i is
less than row, so this will execute 5 times,
and each time we'll append one star to our empty string.
So we'll end up with 5 stars. And finally, when we are done,
with this loop, we do a console.log of pattern,
that's all we have to do. Now on the top I'm going to
change this to 5, save the changes, the algorithm works
beautiful if you pass 1, if we pass 2 stars, you get
2, we get 2 stars. So what we have here is what we call
a nest.loop. So we have a loop inside of
another loop. And you may see this pattern inside a lot of algorithms.