Alright, now let's take
a look at switch and case. So let's start by declaring
a variable called roll. Let's imagine this represents
the role of the current user. Now we want to see
is a guest, or a moderator or an admin. We can
easily implement this logic, using a bunch of if and else statements.
But there is another way, using switch and case. So let's
take a look. We start with this switch statement, we add
parenthesis, but instead of adding a condition here,
we add a variable, in this case we're going to add the role
variable. Now we add curly braces,
then we add one or more case statements, each case statement
is used to compare the value of this variable with something.
So, here's our first case. If
this role equals guest, so I'm comparing the
value of role with guest, now we add colon,
and then after that we add one or more statements. So,
we can do a console.log guest user.
Like this. Now here we need to add a
break statement. So we jump out of this switch block.
Otherwise the other statements here will be executed, let me show you.
So, we need to add another case statement. If
this user is a moderator, we want to display
console.log Moderator
user once again we need to add the break, so
in this case, if I don't add this break statement here,
and the role equals guest, both
these console.log statements will be executed. That's why we need to
add a break to jump out of this switch block, right?
Now, we can have as many case statements here
there is no limitation. Optionally, if none of these
cases are matched, we can have a default
statement and execute 1 or more
statements so console.log, Unknown,
User. Or more accurately, unknown role.
Now here for the default statement we don't need a break, because
at this point the control will automatically get out of this switch block.
Alright, so, let's save the changes and see what we get on the console.
Save. We get unknown user, because I have
that initialized role, so it's default value is undefined and it doesn't
match any of these case statements. Now if I change
this to guest save the changes,
we get guest user, and similarly if I change moderator
we get the moderator user message. So here's the takeaway.
With switch and case, we can compare the value of a variable,
against a bunch of other values. Now they don't have
to be string, they can be numbers or even booleans. But using booleans here
is less common. Because if you want to compare the value of a variable with true
or false, it makes more sense to use an if statement.
Now just to let you know we can implement this exact logic
using if and else statements. Let me show you.
So, if role equals
guest, note that I'm using strip equality here, so
triple equal signs, and that means we're checking the type and value
of this variable against what we have on the right side.
So, if role is guest we want to do a console.log of
guest or guest user. Else if
role equals moderator then then we're going to do
a console.log of moderator
finally else if the role is something else
we want to display unknown
user. Now compare these two implementations
you can see implement in this logic with if and else
is cleaner and shorter, we don't have all these break statements or
default, or these curly braces, these are extra
noise in the code. So it doesn't mean you should never use switch and case,
well it depends who you ask. I personally tend to use if and else more often,
switch and case are kind of outdated, they look a little bit ugly, in my
personal opinion. But there is nothing terribly wrong with them, sometimes they are more
explicit. It comes back to your personal preference.