And finally
your last exercise for this section. I want you to create this function,
showPrimes, that takes a limit, and shows
all the prime numbers up to this limit. So here are the prime numbers
that we have, up to 20, we got 2, 3, 5,
7 and so on. In case you don't know what's a prime number, let me give you a brief
explanation. So in mathematics, numbers can be prime,
or composite. A prime number is 1
whose factors are only 1 and itself.
So it cannot be divided evenly into another
number. Let me give you another example, think of 12.
What are the factors of 12? Well 1, 2,
3, 4, 6, and 12. These are
the factors of 12. So when we divided 12 by these numbers,
we won't get any remainder. The remainder will be 0, so
we say 12, can be divided evenly
by its factors. Now 12 is a composite number,
because it has many factors, a prime
number in contrast has only 2 factors, it's 1
and itself. Here's an example. So we've got 11 here
the factors of 11 are 1 and 11 itself.
The same is true for 13. It can only be divided
evenly by 1 and 13. So go ahead and create this
function. You will see my solution next.
To implement this function,
we need a for loop that starts from 2 up to this
limit. Because the first prime number is 2. So,
4, let i, we set it to 2, as long as
i is less than or equal to limit, i++,
now for each number, we need to check to see
if this number is prime or not. So we need another loop here,
that starts from 2 all the way to the current number.
That is i. With this nested loop, we can see if
i has a factor other than 1 and itself.
So, let's define another for loop.
Now what should we call this other loop variable? We cannot call this i, because
we have already defined i here. So one way is to
call this j, but someone reading this code, they don't know what is i, what is j,
it's confusing! So always pay great attention
to the name of your variables. What i is essentially
representing here is a number. So the outer loop
is for iterating number for 2, up to this limit.
So let's call i number. We press f to here,
and rename it to number. Now what is this inner loop for?
That is for finding the factors of that number, so
instead of calling the loop variable j, we can call it factor. So
factor, we set it to 2, as long as factor is
less than this number. We want to do factor plus
plus.
Let me expand this a little bit so you can see.
Alright, now if this number can be evenly
divided by it's factor. So if number module is
factor equals 0, that means
this number has a factor other than 1 and itself. That's why
I have not included 1 in this loop, because of course every
number can be divided by 1, for the same reason I have not included
the number itself in this loop because again we know
that each number can be divided by itself evenly. So in this
inner loop, we want to see if we have a factor other than
1 and the number itself. So if we do, that means this
number is not a prime number. So basically what we can do here
is declare a variable, call it isPrime,
we can assume that this number is a prime number, but
if this condition is true, than we need to set isPrime to
false. Also, if we get to this point, there is really no
need to continue this loop, because let's imagine you want to display
all the prime numbers from 1 to billion. Now in this
inner loop, as long as we find a factor for this number, that means
this number is not a prime number, so there's really no need
to continue running this loop. Because this is just wasting our computers
processing power. So, here we can add a code block
for this prime here, if
we get to this point, we can use the break keyword to jump
out of this loop. Okay? Now,
when we get to this point, isPrime is either true or false.
If it is true, we log
this number on the console.
Save the changes we get this result, beautiful,
if we pass 10 here, we get all the prime numbers from
2 to 10. Now here's another challenge for you. Earlier I
told you about the single responsibility principle. We want to have small
functions, each function responsible for a single task.
So I want you to modify this code, extract a new function,
make sure each function is small, and responsible for
a single task. So pause the video, when you're done, come back and continue watching.
So if you look at the lines 7-11,
all we are doing here is checking to see if a number is prime
or not. This logic does not necessarily have to be
part of our show primes function. We can have a separate
function, function, called
isPrime, that takes a number, and simply tells us
if this number is prime or not. Then we can use this function
inside of show prime's function, or somewhere else.
So it's a reusable function, it's a reusable piece of code.
So, I'm going to extract all these lines, pull them,
to our new function. Now we can make this code
cleaner and more elegant. So if we get to this point.
Instead of breaking the loop, you can simply return
false. In other words, there is no need to break
and then return isPrime. You can do a short cut here,
so, if we get to this point, we simply return
false, that means we don't need to set isPrime to false,
we don't even need to declare isPrime. So,
we run this loop, we try to find a factor for this number, if we find a
factor we immediately return false. Otherwise, we get to this point
that means we didn't find any factors for this number so we return
true. Also, we can get rid of all these curly braces.
Because our for statement, our for loop has a single statement
and our if statement also has a single statement.
So let's get rid of all these extra curly braces,
getting in the way, annoying me, okay,
that is better. Now finally, in show Primes
so, here we have only a single loop, we are iterating the numbers
from 2 to this limit, we simply call
isPrime function and pass our number,
if the number is prime we log it on the console. This
also means we don't need these curly braces. And
here's the end result. With these changes, now we
have two very simple functions. If you give this function to the
dumbest person in the world they will understand it. Also we don't have
nested loops, generally speaking nested loops are a bit hard to understand.
So whenever you have a nested loop, that's probably an indication
that you can extract the logic in the inner loop and put it
somewhere else in a different function. So that brings us to the end of this function,
I hope you enjoyed the materials and thank you for watching.