Sometimes we
want to repeat an action a number of times. For example, let's imagine
we want to display hello world 5 times on the console.
The pour way of doing that is like this. So console.log
hello world, and then repeat it
five times. This code is ugly, there is a better way
to achieve the same result, and that's where we use loops.
In JavaScript we have various kinds of loops, and all these loops essentially
do the same thing. They repeat an action a number of times. We have
For loops, while loops, do while loops, for
in loops, and for on loops. All these loops
essentially do the same thing. But there is a subtle difference between how they
start and end. Let's start by looking at the for loop.
So, back to this code, this is how we write a for loop,
so for we add parenthesis, and here we need
3 statements. The first statement is what we call
initialExpression. And here we declare an initialized
variable. So, we use let to declare a
variable like i and set it to 0. Now i is short for
index and is a common convention to use in for loops. This is
what we call the loop variable. So we initialize it to 0,
then we terminate this statement with a semi-colon,
and the second part of the for loop is what we call a condition.
so here we want to add a condition and compare the value
of i with something else. This loop will run
as long as this condition evaluates to true. So
if you want this loop to run 5 times, we compare
i with 5. So as long as i is less than 5,
this loop will execute. You will see that in a second. Once again,
we terminate this statement with a semi colon, and finally the third part.
This is what we call incrementExpression,
and quite often what we have here is something like this.
So, we use the increment operator to increment the value of
i with 1. Now, after this for statement
we can add 1 or more statements, just like the if statements
if you have multiple statements here, you need to put them in
code block. Like this. Now here we want to display hello
world on the console. So our statement is console
.log Hello World.
So instead of repeating this line 5 times, we put it in a
for loop, and this loop will run 5 times. Now, save the
changes, so we get 5 Hello World messages,
on the console. Alright now that you have seen a for loop reaction,
let's see exactly how this loop works. So earlier I told you
this is what we call an initial expression, here we're initializing
i to 0, now this loop will execute
as long as this condition is true. So as long as i is
less than 5, the statements we have here will be executed. Now,
after the first iteration, i is
incremented by 1. Then this condition is evaluated
again, so 2 is less than 5, so one more time, this
loop is executed so we have the second iteration
now after the second iteration once again, i is iterated by 1,
so now we are in the third iteration. Again, this
condition is evaluated, and because it is true, the loop is executed.
To show you this in action, I'm going to output i on the
console. So, save the changes,
this is what we get. So note that in the first iteration i is
0, then is incremented by 1 until it
reaches 4. So at the end of the 5th iteration i will be
4, and when we increment that by 1, it will be 5,
so this condition will evaluate to false. So
essentially there are two ways to repeat an action a number of times
using the for loop. Let's say we want to repeat something 5 times, we can
initialize i to 0, and check to see if it's
less than 5. Alternatively, we can initialize this to
1, and check to see if it's less than or equal to 5/
Now, if you save the changes, you can see i starts from
1, and finishes at 5. Now we can make this programming
more interesting. Let's say we want to display the odd numbers
between 1 to 5. So instead of logging Hello World
in the console, we can have an if statement
and check the remainder of the division of i by 2.
So, if the remainder of division of i by
2 is not 0, that means i
is an odd number. So we can display it
on the console. Save the changes, so here are the
odd numbers between one and five. There is also another way
to write this loop. Instead if starting from 1 and going all the way to
5, we can start from 5 and go back to 1. So,
we change the initial expression, set i to 5,
as long as i is greater than or equal to
1, now we want to increment i.
Save the changes. Now we get the odd numbers in the
reverse order. It's more common to use the previous form, so
we initialize i to 0 or 1 and increment it in every
iteration. But in certain problems, you want to use the for loop in
reverse order.