In the last lecture,
we wrote this for loop to display all the odd numbers
between 0 and 5. And in this lecture, I'm going to show you how to
implement the same logic by using a while loop. Now one
key difference between a y loop and a for loop is that in for loops
the loop variable is part of the loop variable itself.
But in y loops, you have to declare this y variable externally. Let me show
you what I mean. So we start with declaring
a variable like i and set it to 0. Note that this
i we have here is different from the i we have in this for loop,
because this variable is only meaningful and accessible
inside of this for loop. This is called scope, and I'm going to talk about
it later in the course, all I want you to know is that these two
variables are completely different, even though their names are the same.
Now, we have our loop variable initialized to 0.
Next we add a while statement,
in parenthesis we need to add our condition. What is the condition
here? That is i less than or equal
to 5. So I'm going to add that here. Next,
we need to add our statements. So what is the statement that
we want to repeat, here's the statement, we want to display
the odd numbers, so we add that here as well,
and finally, at the end of this while block we need
to increment i. So this is a direct translation
of this for loop into a y loop.
So this is what happens when we execute this code. Initially I
is 0, now in the y loop, first this condition
is evaluated, if this condition is true, then the
body of the y loop will be executed. Again, in the next iteration
the condition is evaluated again, if it's true, the
statements in the y block will be executed, otherwise the while block
will terminate. In the next lecture we're going to look at another kind of
loops in JavaScript.