When writing loops
something that you need to be aware of is what we call an infinite loop.
So an infinite loop as the name implies, executes
infinitely or forever. So if you accidentally create one of these
loops, you're going to crash your browser or your computer. Let me show you an example.
So here I'm going to declare a variable, set it
to 0, put it in a while loop, so as long as
i is less than 5, we're going to do a console.log,
of i, now here technically we should increment
i, but if you forget to do so, you end up creating an
infinite loop, because in the first iteration, i is 0.
And it's less than 5, so we'll display an i on the console.
Now, in the second iteration i is still 0, and less than 5.
So this loop could run forever. So I'm going to save the changes,
now on the console, this number you see before 0
is the number of times you're displaying 0 on the console,
so you can see this number is increasing rapidly
so far we have displayed 0, more than 35 hundred times.
And if you look at the browser, you can see this spinner going forever.
So the only way to get rid of this is to close this window,
or if this doesn't work, you'll have to force quit
Chrome. So this is
1 example of an infinite loop. Here's another example
while true. Again, this loop is going to run forever.
So it's an infinite loop. And by the way, infinite loops are not
limited to while loops, we can create an infinite
do while loop, so do while
true. Or similar to the last example, maybe we'll
create a loop variable like 0 and then
have a condition like x is less than 5, but we forget to
increment x here. We can also create
an infinite for loop. So, for
let i equal to 0, as long as i is greater than
0, i ++, again with the condition that we have
placed here this loop is going run forever, or maybe we
have the right condition, like i is less than 10, but we forget
to add the third part. So we don't increment i, and this is
exactly like this while loop that we had earlier.
Without incrementing i. So be aware of the infinite loops,
avoid them, because they can crash your browser or your computer.