So far you have
learned about 3 kinds of loops in JavaScript. 4 loops,
while loops and do-while loops.
With all these loops we can repeat an action a number of times.
But we have two more kinds of loops in JavaScript and we use them
to iterate over the properties of an object or
elements in an array. Let me show you. In this lecture, we're going to look at
the for-in loop. So let's say we have an object like
person, with two properties name,
Mosh and age 30. Let's say
we want to display all the properties of this person object.
That's when we use the for in loop. So for,
now in parenthesis, unlike the for loop that we learned about earlier,
we don't have three parts, so we don't have that initial
expression followed by a semi colon, condition
followed by the increment part. It looks a little
but different, let me show you. So we have let
key in person. So in every iteration
this key variable in the loop will hold the
one of the properties in this person object, let me show you.
So here I'm going to do a simple console.log of key,
save the changes. So in the first iteration, key is
name, and the second iteration it is age. Now what if you
want to display the value of each property next to it. Well
earlier that there are two ways to access the
properties of an object. We can use the dot notation
which looks like this, person.name, or
we can use the bracket notation.
So person square brackets, the name of the target
property as a string. Earlier I told you, that we used
the bracket notation when we don't know ahead of time, at the time of writing
code, what property we're going to access. Perhaps the name
of the target property is calculated at run time. Here is
a real example. When we iterate over the properties
of the person object, in each iteration the
value key is going to be different. So here we can use the dot notation,
to display the value of this property, in other words,
we can't do something like this, because we don't have
a property called key in the person object. So that's
when we use the bracket notation. So we add square brackets,
and pass key as the name of the target property.
Now let me delete this stuff here. Save the changes
so you can see the value of name is Mosh and the value of age
is 30. So this is the for in loop. and we use it to
iterate over the properties of an object. We can also use these
to iterate over an array. But it's not an ideal way, in the next lecture
I'm going to show you a better way, but let's see how that works before we finish this
lecture. So I'm going to define an array called colors,
with three values, red, green,
and blue. Now we can use the for in
loop to iterate over this array. So for let
index in colors, note that I
named this loop variable index, because in each iteration,
this index variable will be set to the index
of one of the elements in this array. So it's going to be 0
1 and 2. Let's take a look. So console.log
index. Save the changes. So,
we get 0 1, and 2. Now if you want to get the elements
of a given index. Once again we use the square bracket notation.
So, comma, colors of
index. Save the changes, and now we can see each
element in our colors array. Now starting from
ecma script 6, or ES6, which is the modern
version of JavaScript we have a new kind of loop that is called
for of loop, and that is an ideal way to iterate
over arrays, and that's what you're going to learn in the next lecture.