So as I told you in the last
lecture, starting from ecma script 6, or ES6,
we have a new way to iterate over a raise and that is
using the for of loop. It's very similar to the
for in loop but instead of the in keyword we use the of keyword.
So here's an example, for let,
color of colors,
you can simply log this color on the console.
You can see with this new for loop, we don't have to deal with
this index. We don't have to access this element
at the given index. So in each iteration this
color which is our loop variable will hold one of the items in this array.
So when I save the changes you see red
green and blue. So I'm going to delete this for
in loop, bring the colors array down to
summarize everything. So we use the for in loop
to iterate over the properties of an object and
the for of loop to iterate over the elements or items
in an array.