For this attached you find this starting Project.
It's a good old starting Project.
We already know and they're in Apt.
Yes we can write some code and index H Tim L..
Well we got basically nothing.
Now my goal here is very simple.
I want to build a simple web application where we can enter and address.
Then I want to look up this address and convert it into a pair of coordinates and we'll do this with
help of Google with one of Google's API eyes.
And then I want to render these coordinates.
I want to show these coordinates on a map which we will also render with help of Google Maps or with
help of Google specifically with help of the Google Maps Javascript SDK.
So we'll be working with two third party libraries here.
This H to the PS sending library and the Google Maps library.
And with that I'd say let's get started and let's get started by building the very basic skeleton.
Now this is no H to mail and those styling cores so we'll keep this fairly simple.
All create a div here in index HDL which will get an idea of map.
My goal is to render the map in this div later.
Now in this div at the moment I'll add a paragraph where I say please enter an address so that we see
this paragraph whilst we haven't picked a place yet and below it is div.
I'll add a form without an action and without a method because I will handle it in typescript and in
this form I want to have a input of type text with an idea of address and below that a button of type
submit where I say search place or search address whatever you want to say.
And the goal is of course that when we submit this form we get the valued user entered here and then
we convert it into coordinates which we render here on the map.
Now let's add some styling because we need at least some basic styling and therefore I'll add a link
here and point at apt on CSX which is a file we have yet to add and then the C as this file I'll set
up some very simple styles for the map.
I'll give it the width of 90 percent and a height of let's say 20 REM so that we see something on the
screen a border of 1 pixel solid and a light grayish look a margin of 2 REM top and bottom and auto
left and right to center it and then it will use display flex and air to set up flex box where we can
use justified content center and a line items center to center does paragraph which is show initially
in the middle of this box I will also said text align to center so that the text in the paragraph also
is centered and with that forward of form we can also select this by the Forum tag here.
I also want to use text align center to center does all in the middle of the screen so to say give it
a margin of 2 REM and auto.
So to all have some spacing between the map and the form and Dad should be it on the page we should
now see something like this.
Now I want to change my my funds here.
So for the overall H H2 Mal selector I'll set the font family to sans serif but with that I'm good and
you can certainly style more.
You can certainly styled as input or add a button but I don't want to worry too much about the styling
part here instead I want to make sure that this works but feel free to of course improve the styling
here.
With that prepared however let's make sure that now we actually fetch whatever the user entered here
and looked it up with the help of Google.