So in our apt yes file we need to check for this form submission here for this year.
I will create a form constant and reach out to the forum with document query selector querying for the
forum tag and since we have only one form tag in the entire document will of course fetch that.
So this gives us access to the form on that form.
I will add an event listener
and I'll listen for the submit event notice form of course could be null as always.
But we know it won't be so we can add this good old exclamation mark thereafter to tell typescript that
this will not be null.
And then here we have the event listener and it will define a function which should be triggered and
that is d search address handler function let's say and this function should be triggered whenever this
form is submitted.
Now in this function will get the event object and other will first of all call event prevent default
here and also let's give typescript some hints here and let's inform it that this is an event so that
it knows that this prevent default command here will exist.
With that we prevent the form submission.
We ensure that no request gets sent but now I want to get access to the address the user entered.
Now that shouldn't be too hard.
We have one input here and it has an idea of address.
So at the end we want to get the value that was entered into this input and we can do this here by simply
defining a number constant address input which we get with document query selector or actually get the
element by I.D. and then the idea was addressed.
That was the idea assigned to this element and justice before we know it is will never be null.
So we can add this exclamation mark here and with that we got our entered address here by accessing
address input dot value.
Now why does types could not like value here because it doesn't noted what we fetch here is an H to
male input element.
So let's tell typescript Let's convert it to an h him l input element with the typecasting here.
Now typescript doesn't complain about that value axis here anymore and gives us the entered address
and now we need to send this to Google's API.
Let's do that with help of some other third party package in the next lecture.