You can search for a Google geo coding API and you will find the official geo coding API docs the geo
coding API is an open API which you can use to translate an address to a pair of coordinates or a pair
of coordinates to an address.
Now here we want to do a look up where we provide an address.
So does normal geo coding request here and get back coordinates.
Now for that we can send the request to this you are El but we need an API key to do that and we can
get one for free.
All you need for that is a Google account and also a credit card.
Unfortunately you need debt.
It will be free because there is a very generous free tier which you can use every month and we will
not exceed that free tier with what we are doing here.
But still you need a credit card to be able to use Google Maps features unfortunately if you don't have
such a credit card.
Unfortunately you can't use the API.
So create a Google account and then to get such an API key.
Click on get started here and get started we'll take you to a page where you can tell Google which features
you want and we want the Places feature because that includes the geo coding API.
But we also want the maps feature because that will include these Google Maps Javascript SDK which we
need a little bit later.
So check these two and then click continue.
Next you have to select a project for which you want to enable this and you can even create a new one
or pick an existing one once you do that.
You are for warded
and you should be asked whether you want to setup billing for this account simply confirmed as an after
a while of waiting and loading
you will be presented to your API key which you can use.
Side note You can also restrict the apps which are able to use that key in this Google developer console.
But here we can just copy that key and use it in our project so let's store that key maybe here in a
constant Google API key
and let's next focus on sending a request for that.
Let's again Google for Google geo coding API so that we get this you are El again here.
This year L is the U or L which we need to send the request and for that we need some way of sending
a request from inside our TypeScript and data for JavaScript code.