Now sending requests is possible without a third party package.
In modern JavaScript in modern browsers you have to fetch API.
This is built into browsers.
It's a globally available function and you can use it to send requests to you or else.
Now there's nothing that speaks against this API besides the fact that error handling can be a bit clunky
with it.
But I also want to practice the usage of third party libraries therefore we will use the very popular
access package.
This is a package you can use in JavaScript and therefore also in typescript to send H to repeated requests
so we just need to install access to start using it for this and our project where we can use NPM to
manage dependencies.
We can run npm install dash dash save access just like this and this will now install the access package
with this installed.
We can now import access here import access from axioms and you will see something interesting.
If I now start using this and I type a dot here I get auto completion and for example you have a get
method here which will send a get request to a U R L.
So here we actually got built in typescript support and if we go to node modules and we have a look
at the axial package here it is you will see that in there there is an indexed dot DTA s file so the
Axis library authors already bundled their library to gather with such a typescript translation package
in there everything is explained to typescript this package or this file here basically explains to
typescript what this javascript library is able to do and which types it uses.
Now some libraries do that and access is one of them.
You can tell pretty fast if a library does this or not.
If you start using it if you get no auto completion support and you've got a lot of compilation errors
you probably need to install extra types.
If you get good support like we do here and you will get no compilation errors thereafter well then
you already got a library with built in type translations and hence you don't need to install any extra
types.
Good to know.
And here we have a great example.
So since we have built in support we can start using axes right away and I want us send that age to
be a request to dis you are L now so let's copy this you are L and let's enter it here and I will enter
it between back takes to create a template literal so that I can easily swap parts of this string for
dynamic for Abbott values so let's paste in that string it is quite long and let's start by replacing
your API key at the end with our Google API key which we stored in this constant for this since this
is a template literal we can add dollar sign curly braces and then point at Google API key to use this
constant in addition let's swap this address.
Here we got a dummy address entered and of course there at 1 to use to address the user entered.
Now just one important note this address of course is exactly the text the user entered and they offer
it can contain special characters whitespace commas and much more.
And not all these characters and symbols are supported in you or else.
So we need to convert this entered string into a you are Al compatible string and thankfully TypeScript
and JavaScript specifically has a built in function that helps us with that DNA code.
You are.
I function we can call that and pass a string to it and this will convert this string to a you are Al
compatible string with Dad we got the finished you are ELT which we can send the request to get back
our coordinates now get.
Gives us a promise because of course sending such a request is an asynchronous task and there we have
a then lock if this succeeds or catch if we have a technical error or an error response code.
So here will console log any errors we might be getting at this point because normally we should succeed
and therefore here I will expect my response and to then block and I also want to log this response
then.
So now with that I'd say let's see what this gives us.
Let's rerun NPM start to bring up that webpage process again and start building this and let's go back
to our application and enter a place here like 6th Avenue.
If I hit search address you'll see after a while you get output here and there you should have a status
code of 200 which means that the requests exceed it and you have a data field which holds the day that
the server replied with that data field has a results field and in there we have an array as you can
tell in it array we got a couple of items.
The number varies and these are basically the results.
Google found and the first result is typically the best one.
So if we have a look at that we see for example the formatted address so the address which Google found
for this address we entered.
It's a bit more complete than what we entered and we get the geometry key here and if we expand this
we see dad in turn has a location key and this finally is an object with the coordinates we are interested
in.
A latitude and longitude.
So in the end we have to drill into data results and then they're the first result geometry location
and we will have an object with a latitude and longitude and we will be able to then render does latitude
and longitude on a map later.
So for now let's just extractors and let's get our coordinates by accessing response dot data dot results
and then they're the first result dot geometry dot location.
So really drilling into this now what you will notice of course is that whilst typescript does not complain
here we also got no good typescript support here.
Right.
If I type a dot here it's not suggesting that there is a results property and indeed I could try to
access anything here even something which does not exist on the response.
And that makes sense how would typescript know what will be in the response of any you are l I'm sending
a request to typescript does not go ahead and send the request during development to find out what's
in there.
Dad would also not be that good but we can tell typescript what we expect to be in the response because
this get method actually is a generic method and there is any thing here that is actually the type of
the response we expect to get.
So here I can add my response type and I can tell typescript that what I expect is an object which has
a results key which then in turn is an array full of objects where every object has a geometry key which
then in turn is an object which has a location key which then in turn is an object which has a latitude
which is a number and a long etude which is a number.
So definitely quite a complex type but with that if we type a dot here I get all the completion and
typescript understands what I'm accessing here and of course we can all do pull this type out of here
and create our own type alias maybe here Google geo coding response that would be my custom type here
and then I can tell typescript it here I expect to get that Google geo coding response.
Now of course actually the response contains more than just the results array it alls as a state code
and it also has multiple other fields in each item of the results array then the geometry.
Now of course you can simply add all these fields to your custom type here but here I really just want
to focus on the values I'm actively interested in and therefore there is actually one other field which
I will add and that is the status next to results.
So right here on the top level we got status and that will be a string which tells us whether Google
succeeded or not and state as will actually ever be OK or a couple of our values.
This is basically a status message.
Google responds with to tell us whether it succeeded fetching coordinates for this address or not.
And of course in the official box we can learn which kind of responses we might get back here if you
scroll down a little bit and click on understanding the response you learn what's inside the response
you get back and therefore click on geo coding responses and then on status codes we learn about the
available status codes and for example we also got zero results if nothing was found.
We got a couple of other codes as well but here I really only care about these two so I tell typescript
that here I get a status code which is one of these two values.
Now again it might have a number of value as well but this is good for me here.
As I said you can of course write does in a more complete way.
Now with that added down there and the then log we can check if response dot data dot status is not
OK which means something went wrong and in that case we can throw an error here and therefore we will
end up in a catch block where we could set up some error handling.
So here will throw an error could not fetch location and then here and the error handler to do something
we can throw an alert where we output the error message at least this is of course just some very basic
error handling.
Otherwise if we have a success response we fetch our coordinates here and now we can use these coordinates
to output them on a map.