Welcome to this module. You might have had the case that you had a Javascript project which really grew
quite big
and in the past already, we used some loaders, module loaders to modularize our Javascript projects and
split it up over multiple files.
Now turns out that TypeScript really supports modular code and it has two concepts it offers you to
manage your project and split it up into different files
but not only files but also logical modules, namespaces and modules,
it's just called modules.
So we will learn about both concepts in this section of the course as you went to use each and how they
work,
so let's dive into that.