With that, we can of course also add our rectangle file. Here
I first have to add the export keyword so that we're actually exporting something in this file and then
I can import from this file as well,
so from and then math and then rectangle and then here of course, I want to import the calculateRectangle
function.
Now I can comment out this console log statement here and actually calculate the rectangle of 20 and 50
let's say, save this, compile everything with the tsc command,
load our app and we see 1000 there at the bottom which of course is the result of this rectangle calculation.
So with that, we got all the imports and exports set up
and now regarding the styles of imports and exports or how you can use these imports and exports, pretty
much all the things you can learn about ES6 imports apply.
So to give some hints, since my circle class here or circle file has two exports, PI and calculateCircumference,
I could also use this syntax with a star to import everything and then assign it an alias,
so as circle for example
and then I can access it on circle.PI and circle.calculateCircumference.
So that would also work as you can see once I compile this, clear my console, reload the app,
it still works,
so that is one possible syntax. Since my rectangle file only exports one function,
it would make sense to make this the default export.
So by adding the default keyword, I'm telling TypeScript or the same is true for ES6 Javascript
then that this should be the default you import whenever you try to import this file.
So here, I can then and I have to get rid of this syntax with the curly braces,
instead I can choose whatever name I want to use because this file only exports one thing anyways,
so it's uniquely identified,
the name I specify here doesn't matter,
so I can just name this calc and then use calc here
and this will still refer to my calculateRectangle function here,
I'm just assigning a different name in the app.ts file.
So if I then compile this and reload my application, we still see everything is working fine.
So that's just a different syntax and just an alternative to the syntaxes you saw before.