Now there is another important thing I need to talk about when we're talking about modules and module
imports here, the way TypeScript resolves the files.
As I already said, we don't set the file extension as TypeScript will figure that out automatically
but actually, that is not all it will figure out automatically,
there are two other things
it will figure out for us.
One is that we can have different paths of imports here.
Notice that here, we're setting a relative path to ./math/circle,
well if you're coming from Angular 2 for example, you might know imports like this one, import component
from @angular/core.
Now of course that won't work here because I'm not importing Angular in this project but that would
be how this
imort looks in Angular 2.
Now you might notice that this clearly is no relative path because in your Angular 2 project, you wouldn't
have @angular in your root project folder.
So TypeScript is very clever when resolving imports, it sees if you're using a relative path or an
absolute path. The absolute path will always be locked up in the node_modules folder by default
or if you have an ambient typings definitions file, something to which I'll come back in a future module,
it will fetch it from there. Put in other maybe simpler words,
you can set up global exports which kind of are available in your whole project and which can be
imported like that or if you want to call it like that,
local exports which have a clear position like in this file which you import by pointing to that file.
And again, I'll come back to these type definition files which allow you to set up typings which are
applicable for your whole project in a future module which is dedicated to these files.
I just wanted to highlight that you have these two different import syntaxes and you don't really have
to worry about it,
Typescript will figure out everything for you but it is important to understand what's happening behind
the scenes.