So in this module, you learned what namespaces are, what modules are and how both work and how you
can make them work and how you write the code to use them.
Now I already also shortly explained what the differences are
but let me summarize this again.
Get namespaces and modules and namespaces are great as they allow us to organize our application with
Javascript objects in the end, with this namespace keyword.
We can split them up over multiple files and we don't need a module loader to then load everything
if we use the outFile flag on the compiler. A downside is that dependencies get difficult to manage in
bigger applications as it is not strictly declarative, so we don't necessarily know which file has which
dependencies, in the end it's only important to have the right order of files being imported
and we could do this without specifying any import statements at all, just by inserting the script tags
in the index.html on ourselves. When using modules, we organize our application with real modules,
so we're not proxying this behavior by sticking all our stuff into different Javascript objects but instead,
we have real modules with their own scope, possibly living in their own files if we want that,
so we can split up our application over multiple files here too
but we do need a module loader to load them since modules are not natively supported yet by all browsers
and some formats like CommonJS never works,
so there we always need a module loader.
But the big advantage is that we have an explicit dependency declaration,
so we clearly know which file has which dependencies
and we don't need to worry about making sure that we're importing all the files in the right order or
that we need to change something because we added a file and so on, we can be very explicit here
and that is a great advantage which makes them much more manageable and nicer to use in medium-sized
to big applications.