So I'm in a brand new project here again with the files you already know, app.ts, index.html,
package.json and so on and I want to start with namespaces.
Of course, it's also important to understand what the difference between modules and namespaces is
and I will come back to that question later on
but first, I want to start with showing what both do and how they work.
Well why could we need namespaces or why would we need to kind of structure our code or improve the
structure of our code?
Well let's consider this example,
we want to kind of build a couple of tools we can work with regarding mathematical operations.
So let's say we want to have a constant called PI which is 3.14 because we might use that
and then we have something like a function which is called calculateCircumference, like that
and here we then of course want to be able to calculate the circumference of a circle,
so here we would expect to get a diameter which is of type number and we would then simply return diameter
times PI, something like that.
Now since we not only want to be able to calculate this, we also want to have a function called calculateRectangle
as you would get a width and a length and I'm just making up some arbitrary mathematical or
geometrical functions here,
choose whatever you want,
it's not really about math here as you might be able to tell,
so then we would return that and so on.
So we have these things here, the two functions, the constants here and they all kind of belong to the
mathematical area or we can kind of group them mentally as having them all related to
math.
So we might want to create a namespace and
here we have the first of the two concepts we're talking about in this module where we want to group
all these mathematical things
because consider our application,
we then want to use all these things and we might want to create a new rectangle and then calculate
something or we might simply want to log calculateRectangle 10 and 20
and that can quickly get a bit too big and unstructured because consider we not only have two functions,
let's say width 10 and a couple of constants and then it can get quite messy to work with all these functions
here, recall them and make sure to not use duplicate names or something like that.
Therefore, we could then introduce a namespace and we use the namespace keyword for that, then we simply
give this namespace a name and we might name it
MyMath here to not interfere with the default math object
Javascript offers us and then we use curly braces.
So it is kind of a Javascript object we have here,
then we take all the things you want to have in this namespace and just put them in there.
Now as you already can see, my IDE turned this function call red because this function does no longer
exist,
it's no longer registered on the global scope
and that's exactly what the namespace is
there for, we don't want to pollute our global scope,
instead I would have to access it at MyMath namespace, like that with dot notation.
Now as you can see, it still wouldn't work because when we're using such a namespace here, we also have
to export the things, mark
the things we want to make available outside of the namespace.
So PI for example would still only be available within the namespace
but all the functions can be used from outside, which then allows me to log MyMath and
then also calculate the circumference, like that because PI will be accessible inside the namespace but
I can't access it from outside
but since this calculateCircumference function is accessible from outside,
this should work without any errors.
So with that, if I then run tsc to compile the file and go to my project here and in the console, you
see that we got 200
which clearly is the rectangle size
here, 10 times 20
and then we also see a result from the calculateCircumference method call here.
And that is how we reorganized our mathematical functions here and so on in its separate namespace and
make sure that we're not polluting the global namespace.
So of course, we would now be able to create another constant called PI and give it some other value
which clearly is wrong
and as you can see, I'm not getting any errors here
and if I do log this to the console and then of course I have to rerun the compilation step here on
TypeScript,
well if you go back to the console, you see we're logging 2.99, so our new PI constant
and we're not getting any errors because this PI constant here is registered on the global scope
whereas this constant here isn't, it's contained in this namespace which in the end is like a Javascript
object. And we can see this if we have a look at the compiled Javascript file, that indeed it is defined
as a variable,
MyMath and then we have this self-executing function
and there we register all these things which allows us to then use them on this MyMath object.
So that's the cool thing about namespaces,
we can split up our code
and of course we can have multiple namespaces and we can therefore restructure our code and make sure
that not everything is registered on our global scope which tends to get polluted pretty quickly on
Javascript since everything is registered there by default.