Now with our current set up, we still have the problem that all our logic lives in one single file
and while this is certainly fine for this little program here, consider your MyMath namespace
has many many functions,
imagine that you would have a much bigger MyMath namespace, then you might want to split it up.
You might even want to split up the namespace declaration because you might have some functions which
are related to circles and other functions which are related to rectangles. So let's simulate this, I'll
create a new file and this file will be the, let's call it
rectangleMath file, so rectangleMath.ts and then another file which is the circleMath.ts
file.
Now clearly we want to take this namespace here, cut it out of our app.ts file and put it into our
circleMath file
but of course the calculateRectangle function shouldn't be in there. Instead
that function will go into the rectangleMath.ts file
but here of course I also want to use the namespace, the MyMath namespace that is, like so and then put
it in here.
So now you can see I got namespace MyMath in the rectangleMath file and in the circleMath file and
we're referring to the same namespace here of course.
Now if I go back to my app.ts file and I run the compiler and then we go back to console, you see that
we get this error, that MyMath is not defined
and that makes sense because in our app.ts file, I no longer have access to MyMath, it's not
included in this file right
and yes all the files get compiled to Javascript
but if we have a look at our browser here, to the sources tab in the developer tools,
well we're only importing the app.js
file, all the other files are not imported
and why would they, because in the index.html, we are only importing app.js
and not the other files.
So we get two possible ways of solving this,
the first one is we can duplicate this import and also import circleMath.js though
and then the rectangleMath.js file
and if I save this, now you see it's working again, I'll just reload to show this clearly.
So now we get this working because now we're manually importing all the individually compiled files
and we do have our namespace in there, the namespaces are automatically combined since they share the
same name,
MyMath
but the downside of course is we have to import all these files and as you might imagine, that can get
very cumbersome if you have a lot of files and then we add a new one, you always have to think about
adding it here,
so that's not really the most convenient way when working with multiple files,
so let's see if we can improve that a little bit.
Well, the possible improvement is that TypeScript, the TypeScript compiler allows us to automatically bundle
all our files together into one single file if you want it to behave like that.
Now how do we bundle it all into one file?
Well going down to the console here, I can simply run the TypeScript compile command, tsc and then add the
outFile command,
this means create one single file,
then I specify the file name I want to create and I'll name it app.js since this is the file I'll import
in the index.html
and then I can specify all the files I want to bundle together and the order here is the order by which
they will be added into this bundle file.
So that might be important depending on how would your code interacts with each other and what
needs to get executed first.
So here, I'll implement the circleMath.ts file, then the rectangleMath.ts file and then
the app.ts file.
If I hit enter and then go back to the application and reload, you'll see it's now working again
even though I'm only importing the app.js
but in the browser if we have a look at this app.js,
we see that now all the code has been bundled together into this single file here
and that is exactly what outFile does, it bundles everything together.
So that certainly is an improvement,
we don't need to adjust our index.html file all the time
but the downside still is that we need to list all the files we want to bundle together in the
TypeScript compiler command here.
We certainly can improve that too, can't we?