Of course we can and the improvement actually is to go to the app.ts file again
and here, we can simply specify some imports
and now with imports, it's important to understand I'm not talking about imports like you might know
them from the ES6 syntax
if you already dived into that, so we won't import it with import from something but TypeScript has its
own import syntax for namespaces,
I'll come back to the other syntax when talking about modules,
remember we're talking about namespaces here. So namespaces are imported by using three forward
slashes,
so like a comment
but then one extra forward slash, then like an HTML tag reference,
so with smaller than sign at the beginning then a closing tag at the end, so forward slash and greater
than sign and then we also need to add the path attribute if you want to call it like that
and that points to the file we want to import here which holds the namespace we want to import here.
So that would be circleMath.ts
and I will duplicate that because I also want to implement or import rectangleMath.ts.
Now with these two imports in place here, I'm telling TypeScript please add these two files, circleMath
and rectangleMath in this order to this file.
So then, I can compile with just tsc or even just tsc and then app.ts again
and if I run this and we have a look at the resulting app.js file,
nothing changed.
Well we still have to add the outFile command,
so outFile and then the name of the file we want to create, app.js for example. If we now check app.js
again, we see that now everything has been added into the file again in the order by which we specify it
here with the reference paths
and therefore if we go back to the browser, clear the console and reload the page, you see it's working
again but now with the minimal possible amount of work necessary because we're specifying all our dependencies
up here, all our imports up here and then we just compile everything into one file with the outFile command.
And with that, we have a better structure we're structuring our code and we're making sure that everything
gets added into a single file in the order it needs to get added.