Now when working with namespaces, one important note I want to make this you can also have namespaces
in namespaces.
So here in MyMath, I could also have another namespace called circle, since this is the circle related
math,
then I put all my logic into this circle namespace,
I of course also need to export that namespace now
and with this set up, what I can do is I can go back to my app.ts file, that won't work anymore as my
IDE correctly shows me and I would have to access circle on that.
Now if I save this and compile again into one single file, clear the console and reload,
you'll see it's working again
but now we got some nested namespace as if you would need that.
But of course make sure to not overdo it because you want to keep it somehow manageable in the
end and not have 10 levels of namespace nesting,
at least I assume that's not what you're interested in.
If you then want to still access everything on MyMath in the app.ts file for example, one thing you
could do is you could add a special keyword, the import keyword that is, like so
and we're not using the ES6 syntax for importing here but what you can do here is you can simply say
CircleMath and set this equal to MyMath.Circle,
like that
and then you can simply say CircleMath on that,
compile everything here and it still works.
So with that, you're just setting up an alias here where you use the nested namespace and assign it to
one single
alias in the end which you then can use.
So that's just some advanced techniques on namespaces but that is in general how you use namespaces,
very important to make sure to bundle them into one single file or import all the files here with
script tags and also make sure to add the right order of imports here in your main file or manually add
all the files with the tsc command here when compiling it
but always make sure that you're not forgetting any necessary imports here.