And when we are at the disadvantage of namespaces. Now our little example here is quite manageable
right,
because here
we only get a couple of namespaces or a couple of files which we import here and which we then
use here
but we already have to watch out that we're not forgetting anything and that we're keeping the right
order.
The problem is that our modules if we want to call it like that, that our files are not very declarative
about what they need. Let's say our circleMath here would need another namespace, then we would need
to add the import either here or in the app.ts too
but since we can add it anywhere where we want as long as we make sure that everything gets bundled
into one file, it can be kind of hard to
clearly see which file has which dependencies
and it's not really that manageable for bigger projects.
It has some disadvantages compared to the ES6 modules which are very declarative about which file
or which module has which dependency and which also makes sure that each module, each ES6 module has
its own scope and doesn't pollute the global scope.
So whilst namespaces here are a great tool for smaller applications, you probably want to fallback
to ES6 modules or modules in general
when working on medium-sized to large projects.
So let's have a look at modules next.