So let's work with modules now and I will stick to a comparable example as I used with namespaces.
I will add a new folder to this project and I'll call this folder math and in this folder,
I'll add a new file called circle.ts
and I'll add another file which I'll call rectangle.ts. So I'll start with the rectangle file here
and in here, I'll again create my calculateRectangle function here and I want to have a width which is
a number and a length which is a number, so like before
very basic here of course, return the width times the length,
that's what I want to do here and in my circle, I'll again have PI which is 3.14 and then
I'll have my function, calcCircumference or let's name it calculateCircumference
where I then also of course will need to get my diameter number and then I want to return
diameter times PI, like so.
So far, that is pretty much the same we saw before,
now what I want to do here is, I want to kind of import that code into the app.ts again, so that I'm able
to console log
the circumference and the rectangle and maybe also PI.
So that would be the three things
I want to log here.
Now how can I import all that? Before we used namespaces and of course, I could use that again
but what I want to do is I want to use the modules TypeScript supports. Now modules are pretty
much the syntax you might know if you use ES6 or if you are into ES6 already. In a file, like my circle.ts
file here,
I can simply export a constant, a variable, a function, a class,
basically all the objects by adding the export keyword in front of it, the same therefore is true
for this function.
Now the constant here and the function in the circle.ts file are both made available outside of this
file,
I can therefore go to my app.ts file and import them.
Now the import syntax looks like that,
import from
and then I have to specify the path which is relative with ./ at the beginning,
then math and then circle.
Now here, you may leave out or you should leave out the .ts at the end,
Typescript will automatically resolve that, it will automatically look for .ts, .tsx or .dts
files
and I come back to
.tts
and TSX files in the future of this course.
But it will automatically look for this extension
and since we specify this relative path, it also knows where to look and it then is able to import
from this file.
Now here, what may we import?
Well we may import PI and we may import the calculateCircumference function here.
This allows me to log PI and that will just be constant or to log the result of calculateCircumference
where I need to pass a diameter of let's say 10.
Now if I comment out the last console log here and save this and then run tsc, well let's see what happens
if we go to the console, uncaught reference error,
Require is not defined.
What's happening here?