Well you might say of course this happens because we're not bundling it into one file, right,
so let's do this. Let's actually just compile the app.ts file, add the outFile and name it
app.js. Well with that,
if we reload the page, we're not getting the error anymore
but I'm not seeing anything either,
so let's have a look at the app.js file now.
Well the app.js file looks pretty empty to me to be honest,
no code inside of it
and that is clearly the app.js which was created here,
so it's ignoring all these things.
Now let's try out
what happens if we just use tsc and then outFile app.js.
Well now we get an error, that only amd and system modules are supported alongside outFile
and that refers to how TypeScript should compile this to Javascript because as you might be aware, native
Javascript doesn't support modules, native Javascript doesn't know the import export syntax. In native
Javascript,
well we can split our code over multiple files but we can't import Javascript files into Javascript
files, at least not without ES6 which is also native Javascript but not supported by all browsers yet.
So what we can do is we can go to our tsconfig here and currently, module is set to CommonJS,
that means it is compiled, your TypeScript imports here are compiled to meet the CommonJS module
standard.
What does that mean?
It does mean that it is trying to fulfill the CommonJS way of structuring your code,
that would be with the require keyword which is added as an import and we can see this if we just
ran tsc
without bundling,
now you see that in app.js we're trying to import these circle dependency with the require keyword.
If you are into NodeJS, that might look familiar and indeed that is the same syntax but that
syntax of course doesn't work in the browser, at least not without a module loader which is what we need
for that.
Now before I come to setting up a module loader, the error message before told that we can compile
everything into one file
if we set this to amd for example,
so let's set it to amd and then run this command again.
Now it worked
and now what happens if we reload our page here?
Well now define is not defined,
so the app.js file now also looks totally different but somehow we're not getting there.
Well the reason stays the same,
we need a module loader,
all these ways of bundling our files and loading these modules, there are several systems. This is
one system,
it allows us to bundle everything into one file but it still creates some modules Javascript doesn't
know with the unknown define keyword without bundling it into one file,
so with that command again, you see we have,
if I change this back to CommonJS here and compile again, the way we did before,
you see now we have this require keyword and while it might look strange that the code changes that
dramatically all the time,
in the end the only thing that changes is how TypeScript tries to transpile or translate this into Javascript
using different modules systems which have come up over the last couple of years.
In the end, it always comes down to the same thing,
we need a module loader though.
Now what is a module loader?
Well a popular module loader is SystemJS.
So if you google for SystemJS and go to a Github page, they will tell you that this is a universal dynamic
module loader which loads ES6 module, AMD, CommonJS and so on,
so basically it loads all kind of module formats which have come up over the last couple of years,
that of course is great because we can create all kinds of formats with TypeScript.
Now since this sounds pretty good, SystemJS might be what we need and actually SystemJS is such
a module loader.
Now what is a module loader?
It's Javascript itself but it adds the logic
our browser needs to be able to work with these commands
it doesn't know by default, like require for example.
So we have to install Node or SystemJS here, excuse me and then we can use it to load our files and
modules and make sure that everything runs fine in the browser.
So while this might look complicated, setting it up and using it is actually pretty simple,
so let's go through the steps we need to do. Back in the project,
the first thing I need to do is I need to install SystemJS and I'll use npm for that.
I'll add save to it because this will be a dependency
I will need at runtime in the production environment, not only in development environment too.
So that will pull down SystemJS and add it to my project,
I will therefore see it here as a dependency in the package.json file once it is finished
and with that, I'm ready to use SystemJS. Now in order to use it,
I'll go to my index.html file and now I'm getting rid of this import here of app.js, instead
here I want to import SystemJS which will be placed in the node_modules folder of course since
we just added it with the npm command, here we can access SystemJS and then here we want to access the dist
folder and in the dist folder, we can pull in SystemJS, like that.
Now with this, we get SystemJS
but now our own code is no longer available, right?
Well if we have a look at the documentation of SystemJS, it also shows us how to import our own
code, so I can just copy that snippet here,
we don't need the first line, that just import SystemJS,
we already did that, add the script here and now we need to fine tune it a little bit.
The
baseURL /js
is wrong,
our baseURL is just slash since all our files are placed in the root directory here and then
we want to import app.js which will be our main file. With that if I save this and now run the tsc
command again,
well let's go back to the browser and reload this page, would have been too nice to have it work right
now, right?
The issue is it's now not finding the /math/circle file
and the reason for that is of course that /circle doesn't have a file extension and it doesn't
have this file extension because here in our import in app.ts,
we're not using this file extension,
we're setting up this file without an extension, which is fine by TypeScript but not by SystemJS. With that
error back in the project, the way we can fix this is by going to our index.html file and we have to tell SystemJS
that our base extension is Javascript and in the SystemJS.config, we can easily fix this by adding
defaultJSExtensions and set this to true which means it will look or it will automatically add
a .js at the end. With that if I clear the console and reload this page, we now see the output
we expect, this is just a standard floating point error as introduced by Javascript, has nothing to do with
TypeScript and we can see that now we get the working modules
and while this was quite a lot of work, it's just some initial setup and to be honest, it weren't that
many steps,
it was just difficult to understand why we need this module loader and that it won't work without one because
the different module formats which you used over the last years are all not supported by native Javascript,
we need to have a module loader. And then it's totally up to you which module format you want to use,
if it is CommonJS as is the default here and as is regularly used or if you want to use one of the
other formats and which types are supported. Well the TypeScript handbook gives a good overview
but basically, all the major module types or module bundling ways are supported
but as I said, CommonJS is the default which you'll often see and which works fine, which is the one
I will use throughout this course when working with modules.