So after having a look at these types, let's have a look at more advanced types or questions,
let's have a look at functions and types.
Now functions can of course also take advantage of types, let's say I have the function returnMyName
here and with this function surprisingly, I want to returnMyName,
who would have guessed that?
Now if I call this function here and log it to the console, so console log returnMyName and I compile
this, we shouldn't get an error
and we should see Max here,
I'm just reloading and cleaning this so we can clearly see this,
here you see Max.
So this is what this function does, not really that surprising. What this function also does is, it gives
us back a string, so we can be explicit about this,
we can also add a colon after the function name and the parentheses here and then assign a type to it.
Now this type here always refers to the return value,
so not to the values of any possible arguments, I'll
come back to this soon but instead only to what the value of what the return should be.
So now that I stated this to be of type string,
if I instead use my age and try to compile this, I get an error that I can't use number here because
we're expecting to return a string,
so let me quickly change this back.
Now a special type regarding the return function or the return type here is the void type.
If I would have another function which simply is named sayHello and all it does is print hello to the
console,
well then this function doesn't return anything,
it doesn't have a return statement.
Now I can be explicit about this by adding a type here too and the type would be void which means nothing,
there
is nothing to be returned,
what this does is it gives me an error if I actually do try to return something.
So here again if I compile this, I get the error that string is not void,
so no I can't return something here.
So this is another useful type especially in conjunction with functions
where you want to be clear that this function should not return anything.
Now of course it's nice to know what a function returns but often times you'll have a function with some
arguments and you want to be sure that these arguments have specific type so that your function is
able to work correctly.
So we will have a look at argument types here.
Now argument types are really just the types of your function arguments guess what
but it looks like this.
If I have a function multiply and here let's say I have a value 1 and a value 2
and I know this should return a number and then here I simply return value 1 times value 2. If I
now console log
a function call to this function here,
multiply and I pass 2 and then Max,
now if I compile this,
what do you expect to see? We don't get an error
because this can be converted to a number but let's see which number.
If I reload this page, we see it's this number,
it's not a number which is a special type of Javascript to indicate
yes we were expecting a number but it isn't.
So we're performing our arithmetic calculation here but it doesn't give us back a number because we
can't multiply a string.
Now we could have avoided this problem if we knew that this function should only take numbers and hence
would get a warning at a time we tried to compile this code. So I can assign types to my arguments
here too,
again with colon and then the type, like number here.
Now with this if I try to compile it, I do get an error that now this doesn't work because the string
is not a number, it can't be used as such and therefore I am not able to call this function in this way,
it doesn't work.
This of course is great because it prevents me from doing this mistake and I can comment this out and
simply replace it with a function call which actually does work, like 10 times 2
which of course if I compile it now and run the code gives me 20 here at the very bottom.