Now here's an interesting thing,
functions are types on their own.
So we not only have the types we expect to get back or we expect our arguments to have, this whole function
here is a type and I'm going to show you,
so let's have a look at function types.
Let me create a new variable which I'll call myMultiply.
Now myMultiply should really just take the multiply function later on
but right now, I don't want to initialize it, which leads to the behavior that I can set myMultiply equal
to
sayHello and that I can set it equal to multiply, without parentheses all the time because I don't want
to set it equal to the return value of these functions but instead to the functions themselves.
So I can call myMultiply here and then I can also call it down here again
and if I compile all this code and then have a look at my console, clearing it to make it a bit better
to read,
we we see hello here and we don't see anything from this call here simply because you would have
to console log it
and then also pass some values like five and two, save it, compile it and then have a look at the new console
here, we see 10.
So this is how I can call these functions and how I can assign it
but it looks kind of wrong to be able to assign myMultiply to sayHello,
maybe it would be great if you could say this should only be able to take functions of this format or
type here and not of this type.
Now to get an idea of how we could tell it, let's see what makes up this function and what makes up this function.
Here
the specific characteristics are that we have no arguments and that we return nothing,
here we have two arguments where both arguments are numbers and we return a number.
So it would be great if we could set the type to be something like
yes please have two arguments which are both numbers and return a number,
turns out we can do this.
We can set a type here with colon and then to set a function type, we use parentheses, then the arrow to
follow the ES6 arrow function syntax
and then what this function should return.
So that's the general setup.
Now here in our case, we want to have a value which is a number and then another value which is also a
number and then we want to return a number
and this is a function type.
Important,
it's not a function,
you won't be able to execute this and we're assigning it as a type as you can see by the colon here
but it indicates which functions this variable will be able to hold.
Also notice that now we're getting an error here
and if I compile this, I do get the error here too, that type
no arguments return void is not assignable to type, two arguments both numbers return a number.
We don't get an argument for this assignment here,
so multiply seems to satisfy this type here, even though and that's important to note, here
I have val1 and val2 and here I have value and value2,
so the name of the arguments is totally ignored,
that could be a and b, the types here,
that is the important part
and of course that type here too.
So with this set up, we're able to define which types of functions very well may hold
and we're using these function types here.