Now with functions, we had one advanced type or topic,
now let's have a look at objects.
Objects are of course extremely important in the Javascript world
and so are they in TypeScript and throughout this course, you will learn about different ways of creating such
objects for example
but here, let's talk about objects and types.
I can create a new object holding some user data for example, like this. It might hold a name which since
I like my name is Max but of course you're totally free to use yours
and then it might hold my age,
so that could be my user data.
Now the issue with that is, of course the good thing is TypeScript infers,
now what does happen when I write this code?
Now you might say nothing because I'm not printing it or so but actually, something happens behind the
scenes. TypeScript infers the type
this variable should have, it infers the type to be an object with a name field which is of type string
and an age field which is of type 27,
I can prove this by trying to reassign user data to an empty object.
If I now run tsc, I get an error that the empty object is not assignable to the type as I just
said name, string and age should be a number,
so this whole object is turned into a type here and here, that's also important to note, the names of
the properties are important.
So if I create a new object here where I have a to be hello and b to be 22 and try to compile this,
I still get an error because yes the types do match,
we do have a string and a number but the names of the properties don't match.
So where the names didn't matter here in the function, only the types and the order of the types did matter,
here
the names do matter
and the reason for this is, in the function, the order is the important thing.
The first argument should be a number,
the second argument should be a number.
Now in an object, the order isn't clear, the order may change behind the scenes so we can't say the first
property should be a string,
the second property should be a number, instead
the names of the properties, so name and age are important to really identify the properties we're talking
about.
So this gives us an error,
this is not a valid type here.
Of course we can also be explicit about such an object type and we can assign it here, again with a colon.
Now how could such an object type look like? For functions we had
this syntax here,
for objects we use the
very object similar syntax with curly braces,
now this would mean should be an empty object.
So since we don't want that, the syntax will be or the type will be name and an age of course
but now what are the values of these property-like looking things here?
Well this certainly isn't Max because the type should not be that this is always Max,
instead this here is string and for the second property here, age, it is number.
Now with that, if I recompile this, it works because we do satisfy this type
but here's an important thing to understand.
In the value,
so the real object after the equal sign here, we do have key-value pairs where the key is the property
name and the value is the value of that property and they are separated by colons and not equal signs,
that's just how Javascript and also TypeScript works.
Now here before the equals sign
but after the colon after the variable name, we have the type definition,
this is not the value, it's the type.
Therefore here we also have key-value pairs but it's not really like properties and their values,
instead it's just properties and the types these properties should have.
That's just important to keep in mind,
that's kind of the blueprint,
that's kind of the plan for this object.
Right on the right side of this equals sign is the real object
and just because both use colons to separate properties and values doesn't mean that they do the same
thing.
Here we assign types, here we assign the values