We can take this a step further,
here's an advanced object.
While it might look extremely strange and dangerous but it's really just putting together all of the
things we saw thus far.
We have a variable named complex which should be an object as we can tell by the outer curly braces,
this one and this one. Now the object should have two properties, a data property and an output property.
The data property should be an array of numbers and the output property is actually a function as we
can tell by this type here.
It has a function where we only have one argument which has the argument all but again, the name is
not relevant but it should be of type boolean,
that's important and it should give us back a number
array, so an array of numbers. This would be using all the things we saw before and I'm throwing it into
here to show you how to combine these types and how to build more complex objects with them while to
be honest, it still stays really easy to read
once you're into it and it makes sure that we can't assign this to a simpler object, like for example
an empty one to go with that very basic example again.
So if I try to compile this, we of course get an error that this does not satisfy this more complex type.