Complex types like these lead us to an issue though. Imagine we would have another property or another
variable here,
complex2 and to keep it simple, complex2 should just be the same object here,
so I'm just copying it. Technically behind the scenes, it's of course a new object but yes, it has the
same content.
Now I would like to assign the same type, so I can assign,
I can copy the type here too. Do you see the problem?
I have to copy that.
Now suddenly I decide oh that should actually be a mixed array here with any and not just numbers
and I have to edit it in two places,
certainly not what I want.
So a better approach would be to kind of have a way to store this type here, to put it into one word
which you then can reuse.
Well of course later on in this course, we will learn about classes which allow us to create objects
or blueprints of which we can create objects but we can also use a type alias if we just want to store
a type.
How does a type alias look?
Well let's see. We create a type alias with the type keyword,
that's all, that basically tells TypeScript
create a new type and then we can give it any name of our choice,
for example complex and this is then assigned to the type we want to use.
So I'm just copying this, like that.
Now here's an important thing,
even though we're now on the right side of the equals sign and on the left one, this is a still type
creation and it's only like this because we have the type keyword in front,
otherwise in TypeScript and Javascript, the rule always is on the right side of this equal sign,
you defined type, you set the type of a variable, of a property, of whatever.
Now we're here, we're not creating a variable or a property,
we're creating a type and therefore on the right side, we set up this type.
Now with this complex type created, we can make it easier and simply set this to be of type complex.
Now it's still the same type as before but it's much more reusable, if we want to change it, we change
it in one place, if
we want to use it, we simply use complex here