We're nearing the end but there are two other important concepts about types which make your life really
easier.
Thus far, we always had the decision between
be explicit about the type,
use a number,
use a string or use any, well sometimes you need the in-between solution.
You know that your type could be a string or a number but it certainly will not be a boolean
and right now, you may think well then I have to use any
even though I know it will only be one of these two types and not any type.
Turns out TypeScript can help you with that
with union types. Coming back to the example I just talked about, let's say I want to redefine
myRealRealAge here and this should be either 27 or 27,
both works for example here. Now right now, I would have to use any to be able to be flexible about it
and then reassign this to be 27, right?
If I do this and compile this, we don't get an error.
Now it certainly can't be true though
and that would still work without giving us an error here which is kind of bad because that's not what
I want.
So what I can do is I can use a union type,
I can set this to be of type number and now comes the interesting part or that's a single pipe character,
string,
which means this may be either a number or a string but certainly not boolean whatever.
It's not like we're excluding types,
we're just being explicit about which types it may be,
so number or string.
So with that, that works
but trying to assign this to true will, as you see when I run tsc, result in an error here.
We can't assign this to be true,
it's not a boolean,
it may be a number or a string,
so let me comment this out.