The final thing I want to show you is how to check types. Earlier,
I already showed the typeOf command and we can use this.
Let's say we have some final value here
and finalValue is a string
as it turns out. Now I only want to execute some code if it is a string and not if it is, let's say a
number.
So I can use an if statement and say typeOf, this typeOf keyword here,
finalValue and then check which type it is.
I do this with the equal sign and now very important, not with equals string,
this does not work here,
instead it has to be in quotation marks string.
So you always use a string here, so quotation marks and then between quotation marks, you put the type.
The types then are the same as before - number, string, boolean and so on
but just between quotation marks in this case.
So if I check for this being a number and only in this case do I want to log finalValue is a number,
well if I compile this, we don't get an error and
if I then run my application, we don't see this output because of course it is no number,
it is a string.
So only once I change this to be any number and recompile my code and have a look at my application
again, we do see finalValue is a number.
So this is how we can check the type of a variable
in our code
and you would use this for example in let's say some function or some code where you're not really sure
what values you are getting
and you just want to do something upon certain types,
for example for a calculation, you only want to perform made when you're getting numbers
and with this check, you can make sure that the values you are using are indeed of type number