With the release of TypeScript 2.0, if you are using that, you got access to a couple of new types or
new things regarding types,
the first thing I want to show is the never type.
Now as the name suggests, this is kind of a strange type because when would you assign never as a type?
It kind of means it's never relevant.
Consider this function, never returns would be an appropriate name for example because what
this function does is it simply throws a new error with any error message.
Now you could assign never to this and this would also be the type the TypeScript compiler automatically
infers.
Now why is this never?
Because this function never finishes,
it doesn't return void,
don't mistake it for a function which returns void,
for example if you would simply console log something here but this function actually returns an error.
So it's not returning nothing, it's never returning anything,
that's the key difference to understand here,
this function has an error or throws an error and therefore never returns.
So this is where you could specify never to make your intention clear.
That being said, it is something you probably won't use all over the place but you might use it in functions
or in parts of your code where you know it should never be reached because it kind of then is stuck
and never returns
and as here when you throw an error,
well that probably is not the place where you want to get with your code in the first place.
Nonetheless, if you want to define such places in your application where you know oh
if I go there, then I never return,
well then this is the type you're going to use or TypeScript will automatically infer it anyways.