Probably a more interesting addition are non-nullable types, which means you shouldn't be able to assign
null to types except for if you explicitly state that you want to do this,
let's have a look at this. By default and this is still true for TypeScript 2.0, if we create a new variable,
let's say let canBeNull and set this to 12,
this is inferred to be a number
but in the very next step, we can set this to null, which means we kind of want to remove the value,
we want to clear this value. As a side note if we initialize a new variable, canAlsoBeNull and don't
assign a value,
it is of course of type any by default, we learned that
but it also has the value undefined.
So like we have the value 12 up here and null here, this variable by default is undefined,
that's just true for all uninitialized Javascript and therefore also TypeScript variables like this
one.
So both variables here, canBeNull and canAlsoBeNull are initialized with non-null values, 12 and
undefined
but we can assign null to them thereafter, like this. This is no problem,
this is something you might already use a lot in your code if you want to reset a value, if you want
to clear a value.
The issue with this is that this can also lead to problems because you might have null in a place where
you want to use this variable, do a calculation or imagine it's not a simple number but a more complex
object and you try to access a property on this object
and since it may be null, you may run into problems there because if it is null, you can't access
the property.
So you always have to check first if it is null or not
or find some other workaround. With TypeScript 2.0,
there is another way, you can also be explicit about which may be null and which should never be
null,
you can indeed force this behavior by going into the tsconfig and adding a new field to the compiler
option which is called strictNullChecks.
Now by default if it is not added, this is set to false, so that your code still works because
otherwise that would be a breaking change because you never before assigned a variable to be allowed
to be null,
all variables were allowed to be null,
so you may use them like this
but if we set this to true and now we execute our code here, let's see what happens. If I compile this
code
here, we see an error, type null is not assignable to type number,
it's referring to line 116 here.
So the issue here is since we just added this compiler flag here, this compiler option, now TypeScript gives
us an error because we try to assign null here, again prior to TypeScript 2.0,
this was perfectly fine,
this compiler option I just used didn't even exist.
Now it exists and if we add it, we can avoid this,
we can now make sure that we don't accidentally assign null somewhere in our code to a variable which
theoretically should only hold numbers.
Also notice that canAlsoBeNull doesn't give us an error because it is undefined by default
and this is kind of an exception,
if your variable is undefined, it may also be null since null and undefined are these two special values
in Javascript.
So only the first case or any case where we have a specific type other than undefined will not allow
us to assign null thereafter.
Now maybe we want this check,
we want this extra layer of protection but we still want to assign null to this specific property or
variable here, in such a case, you can simply use a union type here.
So when assigning types here, you could say of course it should be a number
or it should be null.
Now it is allowed to be null again and if I now recompile this, you see it finishes without an error
because now I made this type here nullable which means it can be null
but by default since I added this flag
here, types are not allowed to be null.
There is one other important takeaway,
if I create yet another variable, canThisBeAny and I set this to null initially which is perfectly fine,
if I now compile this code, you see that it compiles without an error because this is inferred
to be of type nullable since I assign null initially. Again, using null is not forbidden,
it's just a protection if I theoretically
want to use another type which will be pretty common.
But here, I assign null initially,
therefore this doesn't give us an error
though what do you think will now happen if I can set canThisBeAny to 12? If I now run the compiler,
you see we get an error, that number is not assignable to type null, the type is not widened
automatically. This here is not inferred to be of type any, it is inferred to be of type null since
we assign null initially,
so null got like it's own type now and since I set this to null, this can now only be null. Now of course this
may not be very useful and you may think about assigning null initially anyways because if you don't
want to initialize it, just leave it like this in which case it would be any
but if you set it equal to null initially, then it will be only of type null, at least if you have this
option turned on.
If this is set to false, then it would still be widened to any as it was before in TypeScript
1.8.
So that's something to be aware of,
if you initialize a value with null, it is not assumed to be of type any, you would have to overwrite this
like this
or of course set this to number or null again,
this would also work. All other things or all other code variations would give you errors.