So let's have a look at the feature which gives TypeScript its name, types.
Which types do we have,
how do we use them and what are their benefits?
You saw it in theory a bit, now it's time to have a look at it in practice. Types also exist in Javascript,
we do have strings and we do have numbers there.
The issue with Javascript simply is, we're not explicit about them,
when we create a variable, we're not explicit about the type
this variable could have, should have or may have. In TypeScript, we can be explicit,
so which types do we have in TypeScript
and also at least the basic types in Javascript? We do have strings. A string is simply some text between
quotation marks and you can of course assign this to a variable.
Now here I'm using let to create a variable,
let is just ES6 syntax to create variables and in the next module, we'll have a look at the ES6 syntax
supported by TypeScript,
here is a brief sneak peek
kind of. So let
and then let's say we want to assign it to a variable named myName and if I assign Max to this, then
this variable obviously holds a string but there is more than that happening behind the scenes, TypeScript
recognizes that I assign a string here and therefore automatically saves this information,
it keeps in mind that this variable here should be of type string.
So if I now try to reassign this variable to be a number and run my TypeScript compiler by running tsc
in the command line at the bottom here, you will see that my command line or the compiler gives me a number,
that type number is not assignable to type string.
So TypeScript recognized that this here should be a string because we assigned one initially and therefore,
we're not able to overwrite this with a number.
Now that's the big difference to Javascript. In Javascript, we won't be able to do this because Javascript
has dynamic types
and here, we do have kind of static types.
We define them once, either explicitly which you will see in a few seconds or like this implicitly, letting
TypeScript infer it,
so this gives us an error.