I hope you enjoyed the exercise.
Let's see if we have the same solution.
It's not that much code but there are quite a cool things you can do with it.
So we get this bank account optics here.
Let's start with that let's assign type for this object.
As I said you should be as explicit as possible.
So even though this is of course inferred by typescript we want to assign it explicitly here.
So obviously we have an object here as you can tell by.
Well the right side of the equal sign in this object we get two properties.
Money and deposit.
Now the first property to me looks like a number.
So we probably should make it type number.
The second property here is a function.
Remember a function type looks like this parentheses.
And then this arrow is function doesn't return anything.
So let's add word here.
And what it does though is it has one argument.
So it has the argument value.
I'll just name it.
Well here to demonstrate that the name doesn't have to be equal and Velle is property of type number
since we add something to the money.
Now since we defined it up here we should also add it here.
So this is of type number and it returns nothing.
So that looks a lot better to me now if that it looks like d bank account object is finished.
Let's move on to the second object myself.
Now my of course also as an object and it has free properties.
Name a bank account and hobby's So name is clearly a string.
So let's add a string here.
Now the bank account is interesting because the bank account is of course the bank account object from
up here.
So I can just use this type definition and paste it into here.
Well to me that doesn't look super readable.
It also has the disadvantage.
If I were to change this object up here I have to change just type definition and this one number you
what I want.
So I'll reword this instead.
Let's create our own type for this.
So up here I'll add a new type and I'll name it bank account.
The name is of course totally up to you.
And I'll set it equal cutis type definition I just copied.
Keep in mind since I'm creating a type here with the type keyword on the right side of the equals sign.
We don't have a value as a normal javascript but instead the value here is a type definition as we normally
only see it after a colon in when we create a variable here for example.
So there's this exception due to this type keyword with this type created.
I can now go to my bank account and of course set is equal to type bank account much shorter.
I can also copy this and set it equal here.
So now I'm reducing this type which makes it much more maintainable and saves me a lot of code.
Now to finish just myself object I have my hobbies aere and currently it's an array of strings.
Now it probably will never be anything else than that.
So it makes no sense to use any.
So I will keep it to a string array.
Now with that it looks like we're done here.
And this is the most explicit and structured way I can think of to assign types here and to use types
to make this code more readable and more safe to use as we're now not able to pass any invalid values
if you want to check this file compiled with TSC solution ts.
Otherwise you will get some strange error simply stemming from the fact that we're using the same names
here and that the exorcized Yes file