Speaking of numbers, that's of course another basic type we got available.
So if I were to save my age here and put this to 27, then this would be a number
and now of course, it would give me an error if I try to assign a string.
So this also doesn't work
and that's the other basic or one of the other basic types we have.
Important to know regarding numbers,
these can also be floating point numbers,
that's also a
valid number. TypeScript doesn't differ or doesn't care about the type of the number,
if it is an integer or a float, that is both type number, there is no differentiation between that,
that's important to understand and to keep in mind.
Now the third basic type we do have
in both TypeScript and Javascript is the boolean. A boolean is simply true or false,
so if we want to check if I do have some hobbies and surprisingly I do, well then I could set this to true,
if I were to change my mind, I can set it to false.
Now of course, the interesting question is what happens if I now reassign hasHobbies to let's say
one?
Well, the IDE is already not liking it,
if I run tsc in the console, you see I get an error.
So even though one could be cast to a boolean, you could say that one means true,
it still gives me an error because one is a number and hasHobbies is a boolean and/or likes to have
booleans and not numbers.
So this gives me an error, even though you can cast it.