These were some basic types and how we can use them and what gives us errors
but how can we actually be more explicit about the types we want to assign?
Right now, we're always inferring them
but what if I want to assign types on my own because maybe I want to create a variable, myRealAge and
don't want to initialize it right away?
Now if I do it like this, I can set this to be 27
but then I can also overwrite it to be 27 as a string.
Now if I now compile this with tsc, I don't get an error because since I don't assign a type here, TypeScript
treats this as type any.
This is a special type in TypeScript,
I will come back to it and it basically means what the name implies,
this could be any type, we're back in Javascript world.
Now the issue with type any of course is that we don't have any of the advantages
TypeScript offer us,
we're not getting the compilation check if we're trying to assign a wrong type,
we don't get IDE support, here
we're really back in the world of Javascript where we don't know which type this has.
In order to fix this if we know that this should be a number for example, we can be explicit about the
type, when creating the variable,
we can assign a type by writing colon and then the type.
Now here we get a couple of possible types,
right now it is type any,
that's the default but we can set it to type number.
Now note, this is no string,
we don't have quotation marks here,
it's just a word number. As soon as I do this,
if I rerun my compilation, now I again get an error for this line here where I try to assign a string.
So I'll comment this out again to get my code working
and this is how we can explicitly assign types.
Now with that information, we can also assign them here, though we don't need to because TypeScript
did infer it but just to show you what the types would be,
well this is how you could be explicit about assigning them. Again, not necessary but also not bad or
not wrong.