Now that we had a look at these basic types, let's have a look at
a type you certainly know but which is a bit more advanced, the array type or @arrays.
Let's say I would have some hobbies even though I state it to be false, if hobbies is an array of let's
say cooking and sports, then this is obviously my array
and I could log an item
to the console, so like hobbies 0.
Now to actually see that being logged to the console, I'll open a new window here and I'll run npm start
to start my lite server which we set up in one of the earlier videos and head over there, open up my
console,
we see cooking of course.
So far, so not very spectacular but let's see, which type does this hobbies variable have? Well we can
check this by printing typeOf hobbies.
If I save this and then recompile my code here,
now we see object here.
Now that's not very surprising because obviously an array is an object.
The interesting part comes if we try to do something else,
if I take my hobbies variable here and I try to set this equal to a new array which holds one number,
and now I try to compile this,
I get an error,
the error is type number or array of numbers is not assignable to type array of strings.
Now that might be a bit surprising but if you think about it, it's not, TypeScript infers the types automatically
and since we initialize this hobbies variable with an array of strings, it thinks that this should only
be an array of strings,
it doesn't allow any other types in this array.
So if we then set it equal to an array of numbers, we therefore get an error, as soon as I change this to a
string again, the error is gone and I can then recompile this without any issues.
So that's important to keep in mind, using a number here will give us an error because TypeScript infers
this to be an array of strings.
Now we can overwrite this by assigning a type explicitly.
If I assign a type and set this to be an array of anything,
well now you see my IDE error is gone
and as soon as I recompile thsi, we see this error is gone too. The reason for this of course is that now I'm
overwriting the type TypeScript infers and I'm telling it
no that's not only an array of strings, it may hold any item and I increase the flexibility of that
array
therefore. It still has to be an array of anything,
so setting hobbies to just 100 will still give us an error because that is just a number and not an
array.
So I only overwrote the types of the items in the array,
not that this is an array,
I set this by adding the square brackets here.