Staying in your world of arrays, we get a new type with TypeScript which isn't available in Javascript,
tuples. Now
tuples are really just arrays with mixed types and a limited number of items.
So let's say I want to store my address and
no, this is not my actual address and I would have this format, Superstreet.
and then the house number, 99.
That's just a normal array with a string and a number,
nothing wrong with that,
we could compile this, no error.
Now if I'm sure that this array will always have this format, two items,
first item is a string,
second item is a number,
then I could be explicit about this because right now, it's just assumed to be this type, an array
of any item or any type.
So I could assign this to be a tuple by adding a colon and then square brackets and here, string and
number
in this case, so two items,
first one is a string,
second one is a number,
this is how I set up my tuple. And if I now were to reverse the order here, have the first item be a number
and the second one be a string,
well if I try to compile this, I now get an error because the order is important, a tuple really has
to be that
format, two items,
first one being a string, second one being a number,
all other combinations or values like this one here are not valid.
So I have to revert this back to 99 at the second position to be able to compile this without any
issues again.
Now you see it works
and this is how you can tuples if you've got some data object or some array which has one single way
it may look like, if you get an array which has a fixed value format,
to put it like that.