Another new type added with TypeScript are enums. Now enums are a cool feature to make numbers
more expressive.
So consider this case, you get a couple of callers and you want
to check in a switch statement which one was chosen.
Now you could have a switch statement where you check for strings being green or red or blue,
so you have a string representing the color, that would work
but in code that would really be well, it's just occupying more memory for information your computer doesn't
really care about,
you could also just have zero, one, two, three, each number standing for one color.
So that would be how you could normalize this
which also has some other advantages,
saves you the danger of making typos and so on.
So that would be a good thing but it is of course a bit harder to remember which
value one stands for, was that green, was that blue?
So in order to make this easier, you can use an enum. We create an enum by using the enum keyword and then
the name we want to give to this enum, for example color,
this will basically create a new type we can use later on and you'll see this in action soon.
So now I created my color enum here and then I simply add curly braces to fill it with some values,
now I could add gray, green and blue here for example, that would be three possible values.
Now these values behind the scenes stand for some integers or some numbers.
So now if I create a new variable,
let's say myColor and set this of type color, I can use my new enum here as a type,
I can set this equal to color.green for example.
Now if I console log my color, what do you expect to see in the console?
I'll compile it and then head over to it.
We see one, we don't see green, we see one,
the reason for that is that behind the scenes, numbers are assigned to that automatically.
This receives the number 0,
the second item receives the number 1 and the third item receives the number 2
and so on,
so this simply continues
and this is how you can add multiple values to this enum and then refer to them here.
Now you might also have some applications where you want to overwrite the default values taken here.
Maybe you want this to be 100 and not one but then this should again be two maybe. Well you can do this
by simply assigning a value here,
you can set this to 100
and now if we print my color, so first we compile this and print it, we see 100.
Now what would you expect to see if I set this to blue?
Will it be 2 or 101?
Well let's recompile and see, it's 101,
so it continues incrementing with the latest number, with the number of the item prior to this one.
So if we want this to be 2, we have to set it to 2, the next item will then be 3 though,
so it will always refer to the last item in front of it.
This is how you can enums to encode some numbers into more user-friendly values which you can use during
coding.