The last basic type I have here is the any type. We already had a look at that and it's not really
that surprising. If I have a car and set it to type any, I can assign a string to it, BMW and then I can
take my car object and log it to the console and thereafter, I can simply overwrite it to suddenly be
an object where my brand now is BMW
and I have the series with number three let's say and I can log this again.
Now with this approach, I'm basically taking my car variable, set it to a string and then I set it to an
object.
Now if I wouldn't set any here like this, then I would get an error if I try to compile this. The reason for
that error being that
well it is a string, TypeScript infers this to be of type string
and once we set it to an object, we get an error.
So therefore, I'm setting it to type any
and I showed you this earlier,
any
is the most flexible type you have in TypeScript and therefore, you should really carefully use
it,
it should really be an exception that you use any. Try to be explicit,
try to avoid it,
try to really find out which type you want to use and only if you really can't tell and need all the
flexibility, then use any because any basically gives up all the features or all the advantages TypeScript
offers you related to types.
So with this set up, if I head over to the window, you see BMW and then this object,
so with type any, this is a valid code and it works.