Now before I continue to put more advanced topics about types, like using them with functions and using
them in objects and so on, I want to answer one important question,
what does all this code actually get compiled to?
We use all these types here
and how does this look in Javascript code?
Well the best answer is to simply have a look.
We can have a look at our app.js file which is the result of all these tsc commands I'm running
here, the compiled code
and as you see, all the types here are gone
and that's not really that surprising because Javascript doesn't have types in this way,
we can't assign types
therefore it's simply stripped out. The role of TypeScript is to be aware of the types and warn you at
compilation time, once the code has made it to Javascript code,
well you're done and
the only thing you're getting then are runtime errors again.
So types are no longer available there
but it was the job of TypeScript to make sure you wouldn't assign anything wrong
before we get to that step, before we actually compile the code. Therefore you don't see any types here,
the only thing you do see is the enum here which is kind of constructed with this self-executed function
and this color object here.
So the enum is actually created in code here too, so that we have this mapping then and we actually do
print a number instead of the name we assigned. But that's the only thing,
all the other types are not really converted to Javascript because you can do this.