Welcome to the next module in this course. Now that we know what types are and how we can use them,
let's have a look at another cool feature or
key advantage TypeScript offers you. TypeScript gives you access to a lot of the ES6 features, so of next
generation Javascript and that it does today.
So your code, since it will compile to ES5 will run in all browsers, even though you're using
ES6 features,
how cool is that?
Advantages TypeScript offers plus ES6 equals awesome.
Well, there's one thing to keep in mind,
Typescript doesn't support all features of ES6 yet
and to find out which features are supported,
have a look at this compatibility chart to which you'll find a link in the next lecture.
Here, you get this TypeScript row and you can learn which features of ES6 you may safely use with TypeScript.
Now as you see, that basically are a lot but there are also some features which are not supported, which may
not be important to you but it's important to know what you may use and what you may not use.
Throughout this module,
I'll give you a brief introduction to some of the core features of ES6.
This is no ES6 course though, so don't expect to get a full ES6 introduction here, again just to some of
the core new additions or syntax changes like arrow functions or the let and const keywords.
If you want to learn more about ES6, have a look at a dedicated ES6 course. As it turns out, I also do
have such a course, might be interesting to you.
Well enough of the advertising, let's dive into this module.