So after rest and spread, there are two other important changes I want to talk about in more detail here.
The first one is destructuring,
that's another great addition or important addition that came with ES6 and that is also available in
TypeScript.
Again, check the compatibility chart to learn more about which ES6 features are available in
TypeScript
overall. So destructuring is the next topic here.
What is destructuring all about?
Well, consider you have an array which looks like this,
that could be myHobbies and well, my hobbies are cooking, not cookies,
oh cookies are also great
but cooking and let's say sports. So
these are my hobbies
and then I wanted to print out the individual hobbies. So I could print myHobbies and
then the first element
and then of course also the second element, like this. If I save this, you see I print cookies,
well I really have it with the cookies, I probably should eat some,
so cooking and sports. Well that of course is great
and that is the way you know how to do this
and if you want to store them in variables, like let's say const hobby1 could be myHobbies
and then of course the index 0 is and and hobby2 could look like that
and then you can simply print out hobby1 here and here would be hobby2
and that would give us the very same output as we saw before, cooking and sports. Yes, that will work
but then we have to write quite a lot of lines for that and we can have a shorter syntax available with ES6
and it is also supported in TypeScript, destructuring. Destructuring works like this,
we create new constants and then we use this array notation
but on the left side of the equals sign. On the right side, we assign this array which we want to destructure,
so of which we want to get elements out of it and then we have hobby1 and hobby2 here in the kind
of array on the left side of the equals sign.
So while this does look strange, what it will do in the end is it will do the exact same thing as before,
it will create two new constants, hobby1 and hobby2 and they will assign the values of this array
by the position of these values here in this kind of array on the left side of the equals side.
So hobby1 will receive the cooking value and hobby2 will receive the sports value.
That is what destructuring does and if I save this,
we still see cooking and sports being printed out and they are stored in two different constants here
but I have this one liner of creating these constants and also fetching the values from myHobbies
array without having to manually type which index I want to fetch or using multiple lines or something
like that.
So really a clever and neat syntax to easily get the values out of an array.