Now destructuring is not only available for arrays. I could also have an object let's say, userData
like this and my userData should have let's say a username which might be Max and should then also
have an age, 27.
Now again, I could fetch these values, userName like this, userData, userName and then I could also fetch
the age which would be userData and then age
and then of course I can print userName and age, something like that,
save this, if we go to the console, we see Max and 27 which of course matches the values I have
here in my object. So far, so traditional,
that is how you know how to access the values.
Now if the goal is to simply extract the values of my object and assign them to new variables or constants
and of course destructuring does work with the let keyword too,
well then I have a shorter syntax here available too. Since I'm using an object, I'm not using
square brackets here,
that is the syntax for destructuring an array. For destructuring an object, I'm using,
well you guessed it, curly braces.
Then I assign the values I want to extract, userName and age
and it's important that the name here matches the key name in the object, otherwise TypeScript and the
same is true for ES6 has no chance of knowing which key you want to assign to which variable or
constant here because the order doesn't really matter here
and the order is something you can't rely on, just because you wrote it in this order doesn't mean that
this will be the order the object has internally once your code runs.
So the naming here is important
and then of course I set this equal to userData.
So now it works really similar to the array
and I can save this and see that I'm still extracting Max and 27 through object destructuring. As a side note,
if you want to use different names for your constants,
you can assign them with a colon, like myName and then myAge and then you can use
myName and myAge here and that will again work and print Max and 27 here because I'm using these aliases here.
Notice that I no longer can access userName and age though because the variables or the constants
created are named myName and myAge, not userName or age.
So that is the alternative syntax you have available
but this is purely optional as you saw before,
you don't have to assign aliases or different names.