The final important or bigger change to the syntax I want to talk about is about template literals. Now
what are template literals? Template literals are kind of extended strings or strings with more features.
Consider this, I have a normal string, myName which is Max and I already use myName in the destructuring
as I just saw,
so I'm naming this userName now
and then I want to have a more complex string, like in the template of let's say a server-side rendered
language or something like that.
Now in a normal string, I could print my name like this,
Hello I'm and then simply concatenate userName with the plus operator here and then I can print the
greeting here to the console of course
and if I save this and go back to the console, we see that I print Hello, I'm Max.
So this works but it really gets troublesome if I want to use it in this username in multiple places
in the string because each time I have to skip out of the string with a plus and then thereafter, I have
to re-enter and type whatever I wanted to type
and I also can't write multi-line strings, so that really is kind of cumbersome and not always the best
choice. If I want to store a more complex text in my greeting constant here,
I could use a template literal instead and I create one with the back ticks. Back ticks,
these are the signs or characters you probably never use before, you can find them on your keyboard
though
and back ticks allow you to create more complex strings, including multi-line strings,
so I can simply write over multiple lines here.
I could then write this is a heading, skip into a new line and write
I'm Max.
Now I don't have to skip out of the template literal here with this plus this, even though I could, the
shorter way is to write dollar sign and
then curly braces to output a variable inside this template literal here.
So I'm Max, this is cool, like so.
If I save this and print this result, you see we get a multi-line string here with my heading, then I'm
Max, so Max is entered dynamically and is entered correctly and then we get a new line again.
So template literals allow you to write more complex strings and they allow you to easily output variables
in your string with that dollar sign curly brace syntax here.
Now as always, if you want to learn more about template literals and so on, definitely have a look at
some dedicated ES6 resources,
that is the quick overview over this feature and how to use it in TypeScript,
the usage is the same as you would use it with any other ES6 compiler or transpiler. If you do
have say an Angular 2 background and you took some Angular 2 courses, this back tick notation is probably
something you're familiar with from the Angular 2 inline templates, so templates you write in a file
and indeed, that or these templates use exactly this notation and this notation is nothing too specific,
it's something TypeScript offers you as ES6 will offer it to you.