Now there are a couple of other additions
ES6 offers you and TypeScript covers too, for example symbols, iterators or generators
and I deliberately cut them out here because these are more advanced concepts and they have nothing
to do with TypeScript,
they're ES6 features supported by TypeScript
but again, this is no ES6 course, it's about learning TypeScript and I showed all these features because
these things here are things you'll probably often use in your TypeScript programs and therefore, it's key
to understand how they work and that they exist.
Now symbols, iterators and generators are probably something you don't need to use every day
and therefore, I think the best solution here is if you will learn about them in dedicated ES6 resources
and then you can remember this section here and know that you can use them in the exact
same way in a TypeScript program.