I hope you had fun with the exercises. In case you didn't do them, definitely consider solving them
on your own, you'll learn a lot whilst doing so
but nonetheless, here are some possible solutions for these exercises.
Now these are just the exercises again in one single Javascript file
and now I'm going to create a new file which I'll name solutions.ts which will contain all the
solutions
and of course you find this file attached to this lecture.
So here, I will skip out of my compiler for now and I will go to my index.html page and simply
replace
app.js here with solutions.js which will be created for me by the compiler and this will allow
me to then show you the solutions.
I will therefore compile the solutions files standalone and manually by typing tsc solutions.ts,
like this and then I can navigate into the browser, reload and currently we don't see anything but
here we will then see the solutions.
If you download the source code attached to this module, make sure that you have app.js here to
see the real app and not just the solutions.
So with that out of the way, let's have a look at the first exercise.
The goal here is to rewrite this part here with TypeScript,
so what are we doing here?
Well, we have a function where we basically double a value and the goal was to rewrite this as an arrow
function.
Well that shouldn't be too hard,
I will do it here,
Exercise 1 -
As Arrow Function.
So I will create this function here,
double, it will get the value which is of type number and it will return me value times two,
just like that and then I can simply call double 10.
With that, I can run the compiler on my solutions file and if I go back to the browser, we see 20 here,
which of course is the right result because we pass 10 as a parameter and we double it with our function.
So that's really all, that's
the solution to the first exercise,
rewriting it as an arrow function.
Now you might say that was very simple and yes it was
but it's important to understand this arrow function syntax and especially that we don't need a return
keyword here, that we don't need curly braces if we only have one line here and that it's important
or advisable to define the type here.
With that, let's go onto the next exercise, Exercise 2. Here the goal was to create a function which
has a default parameter, with vanilla Javascript you see that this is rather difficult or complicated
because default Javascript, ES5 Javascript doesn't have default parameters, so it always expects to
get a name
and if we call the function without a name, well we have to handle this case where I check if name is
undefined and where I then set name to some default value.
Yes, this is possible but it would be nice if we could leave out this line with default parameters.
So back in the solutions file, let's write the solution for this case here,
so Exercise 2 - Default Params.
I will create my greet function here and this expects to get a name and I'll set this name to the default of Max,
that is how I use default parameters after all
and then I will, in this case here, use curly braces,
I will simply log
hello and then name to the console, like this.
With that, I can then call greet without any arguments,
I should see Hello Max in this case
or I could call it with Anna being passed as a name,
in which case I should see
Hello Anna.
So I'll quickly recompile this,
head over to my browser and I see Hello Max and Hello Anna,
so this does work. On to Exercise 3,
here we have an array of numbers and the goal was to call the math.min function without having to use
apply
which is kind of the ES5 way of passing an
an array as parameter to a function which expects to get a list of values because what
apply will do is it will basically apply this math.min function here to all the values in the array
but of course keep in mind which value then in the end is the smallest available value,
so kind of a more difficult way to do this.
Of course we know better,
so let's tackle Exercise 3 with the help of the spread operator.
So I'll create my numbers array here
and of course choose any numbers you like, I'll use these ones here
and then I want to simply get the smallest number. So I will call math.min and then I can also or simply
pass numbers
but of course that won't work because an array is not what this function wants
but I can use the spread parameter to spread out this array and get a list of numbers instead.
With that, if I compile this and then go back to my console, we see -3 as the result
which of course is correct because -3 is the smallest value in this array here.
Let's have a look at Exercise 4 which gives us another chance to use the spread operator.
I do have a new array with two elements inside of it and I want to push my numbers array onto this new
array.
Now the issue is with the traditional new array push method,
I can't push an array,
I can just push values,
so we need the operator, the spread operator to basically create a list of values of these numbers array.
So
this is the vanilla Javascript way of handling this case here with the array prototype
push method and then applying this on new array and the numbers
but of course we got a better way to do this,
so let's have a look at Exercise 4 which is again about the spread operator. So we have my new
array here, which has like let's say these two numbers and I want to push the old numbers array,
this one here onto this array, kind of concatenate these values so that the new array has these two values
and all these values. Well I can simply do this by taking new array,
so my new array I just created and then use the push method.
Now again, the push method
expects some values like 1, 5, 10,
it doesn't expect an array.
So I can use the spread operator, the three dots to take my numbers array and create a list of values
instead of using this array.
With that if I then log my new array to the console, save this and compile it, you'll see my new array
holds 66 and 2 which are the two values
of the new array before pushing the numbers on it
and then it has all the values my numbers array has.
So that is a convenient way and that's why I'm showing this as a separate exercise to push an array
of items onto an existing array, something which is a bit more complicated with vanilla Javascript.
Let's have a look at Exercise 5, here we also have an array of numbers and then I'm extracting
the individual numbers here and I'm logging them to the console.
Well that shouldn't be too difficult,
what we need here is destructuring, right?
So let's do this,
Exercise 5 is about destructuring arrays.
I'll create my test results array here which should just hold a couple of test results and of course
the values are totally up to you, like this
and then I want to destructure this, so I'll use square brackets on the left side of the equals sign,
that's important
and in the square brackets, I list the variable or constant names
I want to create,
so for all the constants I want to create in this case here. So result1, result2 and result3
and these names are of course up to you.
I set this equal to test result to basically tell TypeScript or the same would be true for ES6, that
I want to take this test result array and assign the first element to
result1,
the second element to result2
and the third element to result3.
With that, I can then simply log them like this,
result1, result2 and result3.
So if I save this, compile the file and have a look at the log, well we see these three individual values.
Notice that this isn't an array,
I'm just logging three individual values. Though of course what I could do is, I could create an array
of these items by simply enclosing them in square brackets again and
if I now save this, log this to the console, well we see we got an array again,
so nothing was gained by destructuring here and that is just a small example to again show you how these
values all relate to each other.
Time to have a look at the last exercise, Exercise 6. Now Exercise 6 is also about destructuring,
I got my scientist which has a first name and some experience and this is a Javascript object here.
Now in vanilla Javascript, we would extract these values by accessing them with dot notation,
these properties here
and then we could assign them to variables and then we could log these variables.
Now with TypeScript and ES6 features, we got some other ways of doing this or a nicer way of doing
this,
so we're talking about destructuring objects. I'll create my scientist here
and my scientist will be a Javascript object of course who has first name of Will and experience
of whatever, 12 years or what it could be
and then I destructure it by using curly braces, that is important because we're destructuring an object
here, not an array, so use curly braces
and I want to extract the first name and the experience and as explained before earlier in this module, these
names here have to match the property names otherwise TypeScript and the same is true for ES6, has
no chance of knowing which property you want to assign to this constant and which property you want
to assign to this constant,
so definitely make sure to match these names.
You learned about assigning aliases if you want to do this
but the assignment here is definitely important and otherwise, nothing will work.
So I set this equal to scientists and that I can log the first name and I can log the experience
like this. If I now compile this file
and have a look at the result, we see Will and we see 12.
So this is how destructuring objects works, how you learned it throughout this module and how it hopefully also
looked in your solution.