So we had a look at some of the most important ES6 changes or syntax changes and how we may use them
with TypeScript. That already allows you to write much better code and much leaner code and use many
of the cool new features.
Now as I mentioned in the intro video, this is no ES6 course, TypeScript supports more features
ES6 offers than the ones you saw in this module.
Basically, you should reach out to a dedicated ES6 course to learn more about that and then have a
look at this compatibility chart to see if the feature you want to use is supported by TypeScript, in
which case you're good to go.
Now with that, definitely have a look to
dedicated ES6 resources to unleash the full power of TypeScript combined with ES6.