I want to start with one of the most important changes probably, definitely some syntax you will use
all the time in TypeScript and which is introduced with ES6,
it's let and const, so these two new ways to create
variables or constants. You already know that you can create a variable with var keywords, so like
var variable could be well anything, like test for example
and that would work but with ES6 we also got the let keyword to create a variable.
Now you might wonder what the difference is and the difference is the scope of the variable, the let keyword
creates a block scope variable,
which means it's contained in the block in which you define this variable
and I'll give you an example for this in a second. The var keyword creates a global scoped variable which
then sits on the global scope and doesn't have a block scope, again
you'll get an example for this block scope thing in just a second.
So from now on
or as you already saw in the first module with TypeScript, you're going to create your variables
with the let keyword which is the preferred way and better than the var keyword since it only has advantages
and no disadvantages.
So this is used as a normal variable and you saw all of that, I can console log this and I will run
tsc -w to go into watch mode and then we see tests here in the console, so that prints out as
expected.
Of course I can then go ahead and reassign this to another value and log this, again to the console, like this
and if I save this, we now see test and then another value here and that of course is possible because
let creates a variable.
The only difference is the scope where this variable sits on
but it is a variable, in the end therefore, you can of course change the value
but you have to keep in mind that the type of course has to be equal the type this variable had before
as it automatically inferred the type here
upon declaration. That of course is true generally for values in TypeScript.
You can't change the types, you declare the types at the beginning,
that is what TypeScript is about,
you saw that in the first module.
So that's the let keyword,
we also have the const keyword
to create a constant.
For example we might have the maximum levels we have in let's say a game and this could be 100.
Now of course, I can print this to the console like so and we see 100 here but if I go back here and then
I try to change max levels to let's say 99, I already get an IDE error and if I save this, let's see
what happens in the TypeScript console here.
You see we got an error here too, left hand side of assignment expression cannot be a constant
and the reason for this error is that we're trying to reassign a constant which doesn't work, a constant
like name implies has a constant value, we can't change this.
So that's a definitely important addition which allows us to create immutable data structures or data
variables in the end and they're not the variables after that of course, they're constants. When
would you use the const keyword?
Well it's a good practice to use it whenever you know that a value is not going to change because then
you make this clear in your code and you also get compilation support and you get warnings or errors
if you do indeed try to change it even though you did not want to do so.
So I'm commenting this out because this as you saw won't work