Now what's this block scope thing?
We saw let and const but what is this block scope
thing I was talking about? Well let's have a look at it.
I will create a new function here and I will name it reset and this function should basically then also
create a variable with the let keyword and now this sets it the same name as this variable
up here has.
So that variable should be null and then I try to log variable here
and I will log variable after calling this function.
I'm not calling it yet,
I'll implement the call here, like this.
So saving this,
let's have a look at the console, I'm going to reload this so that we can see all the values.
Well these three values are from up here but then, we got console log variable here in the reset function
which gives me null since I set it equal to null
but after calling this function, I log variable again and I get another value again and that is
what block scoping is. This let variable here is contained in this function context here, which means
the fact that I set this variable to null doesn't overwrite the variable outside of this function.
They have the same name but technically, there are two different variables
and therefore I can't set their values independently.
I can even try to log variable here in the function before declaring it,
my IDE is already complaining and if I do this, you see I get undefined here.
The reason for that of course is that again, the variable I try to access here is defined outside of
this function,
therefore I don't have access to it inside of my function,
I would have to pass it as a parameter to the function.
That's the behavior you probably know from a lot of different or other languages
and now we finally have this with Javascript or TypeScript here as well
and this is just ES6 syntax of course but it is available on TypeScript too and therefore using let and
const definitely is the way to go.
Going to comment this out here even though it wouldn't give me an error or way to work
but yes, now I just have clean code here again which gives me these values.
So that has been let and const, now that I have this, I'll just add a message here that we can always see
where we were at.
Let's go on to the next topic.