Another important ES6 feature or syntax change are arrow functions,
so I'll have a look at them here too.
I'll first print out something so that we can always see where we are at in the console,
and then let's have a look at
arrow functions, what they are and how we use them. I'll first click create a traditional function, I'll
call it addNumbers and this will be a function and this function then
and of course I could have used the other syntax to declare this function as well,
so this function here will get number1 which is a number or of type number and then I will get another
number which is of type number and it should return me a number,
lots of numbers here.
So then what it should do is basically do is return me number1 plus number2, like that.
That is a traditional function as you know it and if I call this addNumbers function and I pass 10
and let's say 3 to it as arguments and I save this and go back to my application, reload the page here,
you see we're now here at arrow functions, you see 13 here as the result which of course makes sense
and is the result of this addition.
So that is functions as we know them. Now
an arrow function would look like this, I'll create a function, multiplyNumbers and for an arrow function,
we don't have the function keyword.
We start with the list of parameters, still in parentheses,
the only exception here would be if you only have one argument,
then you don't need the parentheses around it, though you will need it if you also want to declare the
type which you should.
So here, I'll have two arguments, number1 which should be a number
and number2 which should be a number and then they're called arrow functions because we use this arrow,
the equals sign and the greater than sign to then point to the function body.
Now if you only return one or if you only have one line and want to return something, then I could simply
write number1 times number2
and while this still does look strange, this short syntax here is basically the same as this one, with
curly braces around it.
So if you only have one line of code and you want to return this one line because the return statement
will be added automatically,
then you could change this code to look like this, like before.
Now with that, I can also log this to the console and I can call multiplyNumbers 10 and 3 here and
we should expect to see 30 here, and indeed we do as
you can see here at the very bottom of the page.
So that is how we can create a function using this arrow function syntax.
Now if you want to learn more about arrow functions and especially which other big advantage they have
concerning the this keyword, you should definitely check out some ES6 sources because again, that's not a
TypeScript feature at all,
it's an ES6 feature but it is important to understand that TypeScript offers this feature as it offers
quite a lot of features and arrow functions is one of the important changes you're probably going
to use a lot.