Of course you could also have arrow functions which don't need arguments,
for example you could have the greet function which would look like this.
You need to pass an empty pair of parentheses,
that is required if you have no argument,
again the only exception would be if you only have one argument, then you could leave out the parentheses
but for zero arguments or more than one, you need parentheses and if you have no argument, well then
you just call your function body like that for example
and then I could just log hello to the console
and again if I call the greet function thereafter and have a look at the console and I will reload my
page so that you can clearly see this, we see Hello here.
So as you see, this works fine too and you don't have to pass arguments to arrow functions to have them
work correctly. To also give an example for this one parameter case
I was talking about, if you have greetFriend here and you want to greet a friend, then you could
have the friend name and now notice,
I'm not assigning the type of friend here which I should do
but this syntax here would give me errors.
So I have to leave away the type declaration if I want to use this no parentheses syntax
but keep in mind, declaring the type or explicitly stating which type this is is always better.
But this would be kind of the shortest way I could write this console log friend and then I could call
greetFriend and could call Manu or greet
Manu here.
So if I save this and go back to the application, you see that I greeted Manu here at the very bottom
of the page.