ES6 also added another function or function change, Default Parameters. With default parameters,
I can assign some default parameters to functions or I could set some defaults to certain
parameters in my function. This works both on the arrow syntax or the arrow function syntax you
just saw, as well as the old kind of old syntax which is still valid of course with the function keyword.
So to show how the full parameters work, I'll use an arrow function here
but again, it will work for the function keyword, function too,
so here I will create a function which I call countdown and I want to then have a start
which should be a number
and I will return nothing
and then what I want to do here is, I want to create a little countdown. So we should say as long as
start is greater than zero,
I want to decrement start
and once I am at zero, I will log something like done and the start value to prove that it is now zero.
So that is a very simple function, if I call countdown with let's say 10, see what happens, we see done
and zero at the bottom here.
So that works
but what if I call countdown like this? You see I got undefined, we're still seeing done because we exit
out of this while loop immediately
but this certainly is not the behavior
and actually we got an error here in the compilation too or in the compiler too and the error of course is
something we get because this is wrong, we're calling this function wrong,
we expect a parameter and we're not passing one.
Now we can set a default parameter to provide a default value for cases like these.
If I set this to 10 in the parameter list here, then you see the error disappeared here in my IDE.
If I save this, you also see that it compiles without any issues
and the reason for that is that it now has this default value it uses.
So if I save this and go back, we see done and zero again, instead of done and undefined as we did before.
If I do pass a value, like 20, I can prove that this value gets passed by logging it here before starting
the loop, like this,
you see we see 20 here and thereafter we see done
and if I delete 20 again, we see 10 which is the default value and then done.
So that is how we can set the full parameters
and you do need to watch out that these default parameters here follow some rules and you can learn
more about these rules in the ES6
courses or resources,
basically some rules are for example if you would have something like an end parameter here as well which
should be a number, then you could set this equal to start -5 for example,
that would work but it would not work if you would have it before start, like that.
That won't work because at this point of time here, start is not known yet,
so the order here matters and that's just one example here,
so really some things I think you should be able to sort out with some common sense anyway.
But generally, the ES6 rules which apply to default parameters also apply here in the TypeScript syntax.