With that, we had an extensive look at functions and this was important because these arrow functions
as well as default parameters are some huge additions
ES6 brought to Javascript and it's great that we can use them in TypeScript too.
Another big addition which is very useful
are some new operators, specifically the rest and spread operators. In this video and the next videos,
I want to show how they work and what they offer us, so rest and spread is the topic we're going to talk
about now.
Basically the rest and spread parameters do kind of similar things or they are closely related,
they allow you to work with arrays and lists of data
and the difference of course is an array is kind of an object where you store multiple values whereas
a list of values is just well, a list of values, that's all.
So to be more precise, we could have an array, numbers for example where you have 1, 10, 99 and
let's say -5 and a list of numbers would just be 3, 2, 1 and that of course doesn't work like
this
but you pass a list of numbers to functions like the math.max function.
So if you have something like this, math.max to get the maximum number, then you don't pass
an array as the argument, that won't work,
you pass a list of numbers you want to check,
so like 33, 99, 10 or/and -3,
so that is how you would use the max function on the math object here.
Now again, this is no array,
this is just a list of numbers.
So if I save this and go back to the console, we see 99 here because 99 clearly is the biggest number
in this list of numbers
but what if we wanted to check these numbers array? As I just showed, passing numbers won't work
and we do get a compilation error here because we can't assign a number array to
this function which just expects numbers, a list of numbers.
The solution is the
spread operator which looks like this,
three dots. Now that might look strange
but basically what this does and the name spread implies it, it spreads out this array into single values.
So it turns this array into a list of values, kind of like removing the square brackets,
of course that won't work,
I can't assign such a list to a variable but this is what the rest parameter or the rest operator, excuse
me, does behind the scenes.
So it passes this max function here, a list of numbers based on this array of numbers where it basically
just fetches all the list items or all the array items here.
With that if I save this, we see 99 twice and the first 99 of course stems from this console log
which I wrote a few seconds ago
but the second 99 here of course is the 99 in my array here, which I'll spread out with the spread operator
here.
So that is what is the spread operator does
and the spread operator is really useful therefore because it allows you to flexibly transform your
arrays without having to write any complicated loops or something like that,
instead you just add three dots and you're good to go.