So that's spread operator, the rest parameter as I said is closely connected to this and I'll have a
look at it here.
Imagine we're going to write our own function, makeArray
and we expect to get some arguments which should be numbers but this should be a list of arguments,
so I return args here and args should be an array.
Now of course this doesn't work, I get a list of numbers here and I only have one element or one parameter,
so I would only fetch the first value.
Of course I could have something like arg1 and then arg2 which could be a number and then I could simply
return arg, like this.
So I would return an array and if I log this or if I call this makeArray function with 1 and 2, like
this, then you would see I get an array with 1 and 2 but this is very cumbersome and of course well
how do you create this function in a more flexible way,
it only allows two values here
but what if you don't know how many values you want?
Well that of course would be an issue
and therefore there is a simpler way.
I'll change this back to args and I will return args here.
Now keep in mind, I want to return an array but here I want to get a list of elements.
So first of all, that should be a flexible amount of or number of elements I get, could be 1, could be
2, could be 100
and also I want to turn them into an array.
Well I can use the rest parameter and wonder how it looks?
It looks like this, three dots and you would say wait, that's the spread operator, right?
Well Javascript figures out or TypeScript here in our case figures out how to use this operator. If we
use it in a function call, so we call a function and pass something to the function, then it will use
the spread operator or then put in other words, three dots will mean spread because it will spread
out an array.
It won't turn a list of numbers into an array because that does not work because how should that look
like,
we can do something like this,
right?
It will not work because 3 and 5 would be separate arguments,
the three dots would now only refer to the one. So that is why there is no other syntax available than just
using three dots, one variable and that variable has to be an array.
Now when we create our own function and we have three dots here,
well then this means whatever args is and it can very well be multiple arguments, turn them into an array
and therefore of course this has to be of type number array or an array of numbers because it will fetch
all the parameters we pass to this makeArray function,
for example two parameters in this case but could of course be three, like this.
It will take all these parameters and put them into one array,
so it kind of puts like square brackets around it, like this here.
So really, the opposite of what the spread operator did
and what it does simply depends on the place in the code where you use it.
So with that if I save this, we see we get an array with 1, 2 and 6 inside of it because that is what
I pass as values here
and what the rest operator does with my arguments.
Now of course an important thing to keep in mind is if you use the rest operator here in the function
to combine your arguments, it will combine all the arguments.
So if you have a function where you only want to combine some of the parameters passed to the function,
then you would have to handle the not to be combined parameters first.
So if I have something like a name parameter which should be a string, well then I would have to rewrite a
function like this to still have it work the way I want it to work.
So you see, I still get that array, name is simply ignored because I'm not doing anything with it
but it also doesn't conflict with my rest parameter here.
So that is the rest parameter and that before was the spread parameter or operator, excuse me, operator
not parameter,
rest and spread operators. Really useful operators for working with arrays or lists of values
and of course values does not only mean numbers like in examples here,
you could have any values which you want to either combine into an array with the rest operator or split
up into a list of values with the spread operator.