This is the code we ended up with at the end of the last course section.
Our practice project a lot of code all in one file and this is arguably not a super complex project.
You can definitely ride way more elaborate projects and applications and you would end up with way more
code so putting it all into one file is probably not what you want to do.
So what you want to do instead is you want to write modular code which simply means you want to split
your code across multiple files so that each file on its own stays manageable and maintainable and you
then simply import and export from into these files and make sure that data for all these files are
connected but they're connected by typescript or by the browser or by some third party build tool and
not by you.
By merging them all into one file during development.
Now in this module we'll have a look at two main options that help us with organizing our code in multiple
files and we'll not just learn about them in theory but also in practice will of course apply these
different approaches and see how we can split our code.