And that's it for modules now using modules is a super useful and important feature because it allows
you to write more maintainable and manageable code.
Having it all in one file is a mess and really not an option for anything but very tiny projects using
either namespace or EA's modules is stale for a way better alternative since it makes sure that every
file on its own is relatively small and therefore stays manageable.
And still you end up with debt and higher bake application.
You want to have in the end.
Now when it comes to these two approaches name spaces and is modules the clear recommendation is is
modules because you get that extra type safety and you ensure that every file has to clearly specify
what it wants with name spaces.
It was enough if one file import that's something that a number of file also needs.
The downside is if that one file which imported the thing is removed that other file all the breaks
without you noticing at least without you noticing before you run the code.
So they offer you as EA's modules use namespace as in smaller projects or if for some reason you can't
use EA's modules and you can't use a number bundler which would translate such modules to non module
code which also works in older browsers but other than that really use modules is modules and what I
just said is important.
These modules here right now the way we used them only work in modern browsers because we rely on the
browser to basically import all these files.
Right now of course we want to build applications with typescript did all the run in older browsers
Internet Explorer 9 for example there.
This would not be supported this syntax is not supported there.
So the app would not run there.
We might also be using some other features that are not supported there but mainly this year is not
supported in all browsers.
So to make that work in all browsers we can use a bundling tool we can use Westpac for example to bundle
that together into one JavaScript file so that during development we have this multi file strong typing
experience but when we ship our code we actually have one file only and no advantage of shipping one
file instead of all these files we have here is that we also ensure that the browser doesn't have to
download that many files because every file that has to be downloaded is an extra hour round trip in
the Network tab of the daft words you can actually see that there you see this waterfall chart and you
see this little white box at the beginning of every block.
This is basically the setup time it takes to set up the HDP request.
So even though the files we are downloading are very small as you can tell this still takes some time
because of all that redundant extra setup for every HDTV request.
So doing less requests is a good idea anyways regardless of browser support.
So for these two reasons browsers support and less requests will have a look at bundling with Westpac
in the next course section.