We can't ignore isolated modules but there is one other option which is actually not even mentioned
here which I still want to mention myself though and that's D No emit en error option.
You can set this to true or false and the default is false.
And what does this do if we set it to false.
Let me show you where this might be a problem.
It is a problem if we introduce an error or it can be a problem.
Let's say here I do with my button and I removed his exclamation mark.
Now even though we don't fully understand what's going on.
The problem here simply is that typescript does not know.
Dad we certainly have a button here after all when querying for a button we might not get one.
If there is no element in the dorms that satisfying this selector then this will return null.
And that's basically what types of complaints about here we access something on a potential null object
and that's not good.
Now that's an error we have here.
If we compile our code we also get this error here in the console.
Nonetheless the file is created.
So even if I delete the app just file it will be recreated.
So even if we have an error typescript creates a javascript file.
This might or might not be wanted.
Maybe you have an error in your types could file and you don't really know how to work around it but
you know it will not be a problem in the final app like here.
Even if we don't know about the exclamation mark.
Well if we don't know about the exclamation mark we might not know how to disable this they are basically
but still we know that this will work in our page here.
So we might be fine with compiling this despite having an error but of course in reality you should
aim for error free projects and rather learn how you can work around this issue then ignore it nonetheless.
You could set this to false or not set it at all because falls is the default if you are fine with generating
JavaScript files if you have an error.
If you set this to true however what will happen is that problematic files will not be generated.
If I now rerun this you see nothing is generated actually even the analytics team's fault is not output
there.
If we have some content in there besides console log you see it's not getting generated.
And the reason for that is that we have an error in a file and if any file fails to compile no files
will be emitted.
So here therefore we have to make sure we fixed as they are before we then can get typescript to again
compile files for us and therefore it is an option.
I typically like to set because I'm not interested in getting JavaScript files if I still have errors
in my type good files.