And that's it for this module.
We had a very detailed look at the types of compiler how you can configure it and how you can make sure
that it really compiles your code the way you want.
We had to look at all these different options especially district options really allow you to write
correct code and not run into strange bugs strange or runtime bugs you might face for example with the
strict null checks.
And in addition to that we had a look at debugging how you can easily configure chrome and view as code
such that you can debug from inside view as code debugging from inside chrome with source maps and the
sources tab of course is always an option.
The key here also are the source maps which you are configuring to be generated in the tiers config
file which are these map files that live next to your JavaScript files.
They basically act as bridges for the debugger between your JavaScript files and your Tapscott files.
And with that we know a bit more regarding how to manage our projects.
Let's now see what else we can do with TypeScript and JavaScript.