Now also interesting is allow J.S. with allow J.S. and by the way all the way Czech chess.
You can also include JavaScript files in the compilation.
Now with allow J.S. a jobs good file will be compiled by typescript so even if it doesn't end with thought
yes types could will compile it with check.
J.S. It will not compile it but it will still check the syntax in there and report potential errors.
This could be nice if you don't really want to use typescript but you want to take advantage of some
of its features.
And as far as typescript can help you with any type only which is effectively what you have in JavaScript
it will do so if you enabled these options.
Now we don't need it for this project and for this project we would want to make sure we don't double
compile these JavaScript files which do stem from types of files so we would have to tweak to include
and exclude settings a bit but you could use that in projects where you don't want to use typescript
at all.
Or where for whatever reason you have some vanilla javascript files next to your types good files and
you want to check the vanilla javascript files as well.
Now let's fast forward a bit.
J as X is an option that can help you with react J.S. which does not really matter for us here.
Declaration and declaration map is all is not important.
Your DTA s files are an advanced concept which matter to you if you are shipping your project as a library
to our people and you need it basically a manifest file which describes all the types you have in your
project.
That's such a detail as file source map is an interesting one.
Though.