So you saw typescript in action and it offers great advantages.
It makes writing clean code really easier typescript adds types and Data's super important with types.
We have to be way more explicit about how things work and we can avoid many unexpected and unnecessary
errors by using types.
In addition to that we also can use I.D. modern I.D. which have built in types of support which can
pick up on these types and give us better auto completion and built in errors which show before we even
compiled a code because they all understand typescript.
But besides the types and the huge advantages we get a loan by using types we also get our features
added by typescript we can use certain next generation javascript features which you can write and use
in our typescript files and then they will get compiled down to JavaScript code to work arounds that
even work in older browsers.
If you know Babel which is a tool that allows us to do that with vanilla javascript as well.
It's a bit like debt just already built into typescript we can use modern javascript features and still
produce and ship code that works in older browsers as well.
Types could also add certain features which only types could understand like interfaces and generics.
These are features which can't be compiled to javascript but they don't have to because they are features
that help us during development that give us clearer errors and help us a wide.
Even more errors.
So it even adds more features on that front.
Besides the types we already learn about it also gives us certain meta programming features like decorators
on which I have a whole module in this coords where you will understand what exactly decorators are
why they are so meta and why they are amazing typescript could all is highly configurable.
We didn't configure it thus far but I have a whole module in the course where we talk only about the
compiler and how to configure it and you can really fine tune it to your requirements to make it stricter
or looser and to ensure that it behaves in exactly the way you wanted to behave and with modern tooling
with modern I.D. you even get support in non types good projects.
The idea you just saw visuals through you code that even gives you better support in plain JavaScript
files because it is able to use some types of features under the hood without you explicitly using typescript.
So that's a free gain you get out of the box when being aware of TypeScript and when using modern tools.
So there are many reasons for using TypeScript and that's probably why you took this course in this
course we will now learn it step by step and we will learn all about the amazing features it adds.