This course is packed with content.
We're almost done getting started and they're off there will dive right into TypeScript and into all
its exciting features to learn them step by step.
We'll start with the typescript basics of course the core types how it generally works.
Some of the new features it adds and all you need to know to get a good understanding of typescript
they're after will already dive deeper into the types of compiler and the configuration of it because
it's super important for you to understand what you can configure there and what all these different
settings do.
So we'll have a closer look at that in this module.
Thereafter We'll explore next generation javascript features supported in typescript how they work and
how you can use them in typescript.
We'll continue with classes and interfaces a super important concept partly also in vanilla javascript.
In the case of classes but with interfaces we also got a brand new typescript feature and you will understand
what they are what they do and why we might want to use them.
After it's time to dive deeper.
We'll have a look at some advanced types and advanced types good features in general.
Taking it to the next level there and building up on the basics we already learned about up to this
point.
Also an advanced feature which definitely deserves its own section is d generics feature.
You will learn what that is and why it's really really helpful.
In this module followed by decorators decorators are a pretty cool feature also added by TypeScript
and we'll have a closer look at decorators and all the builds I'm really useful decorators in that module
and thereafter we will have learned a lot about typescript now the course is organized such that I show
all these individual features in relatively small simple demos.
Now to also give you a bigger picture and to see how you would apply all these features in a real project
will build just that we'll have a whole module where we built an entire project entirely with typescript
from scratch so that you see many of these features.
Most of these features you'll learn about up to that point in action and you'll see how they work together
and why they simplify the process of building such a project.
Once we're done building this project will identify a new problem and we'll learn how to solve it by
working with namespace and modules which will help us make our code more manageable and readable.
Building up on that will also explore Westpac with typescript Westpac is a build tool we use in modern
front end web development and you can use it combined with typescript to get a better project setup
which simply makes certain things easier and allows you to get the best of both worlds.
A great development experience and also code that works really well for your end users.
Once we're done with that we have a very solid picture of TypeScript and how to work with it in projects.
Now what you will need in a lot of real projects are third party libraries so we will take a closer
look at that because there are certain third party libraries which really embrace TypeScript and have
built in typescript support but there also are many libraries which don't and we'll have a look at how
we can work with both types of libraries in a great way.
Entire good projects.
Well and then there are some specific scenarios which does serve their own modules.
We'll have a whole module about react with typescript how you can build an entire react application
with typescript only and also an entire module about node J.S. and express and typescript.
So did you also have great examples for these very popular and specific use cases of typescript where
you can suddenly create react or node applications in a brand new way with a brand new language.
So lots of exciting content in the course.
Let's not waste any time.
Let's see how you can get the most out of the course and thereafter.
Let's dive in.