Your success matters to me and I want to ensure that you get the most out of this course.
No of course that starts with watching the videos.
This is a video on the mind course self.
Course watch the videos.
You can go through this course step by step.
It's built in such a way that all the modules and lectures built up on each other.
You can also skip cert modules of course because all the modules all do work on their own.
If you already know a concept for example now when watching the videos of course do that at your speed.
You got speed controls here in the video player and you can slow me down if I'm going too fast or speed
me up if I'm going to slow for your taste.
I also recommend that you code along.
It's not a must do but you typically learn better if you write code on your own and you have to find
and fix your own mistakes all the pause and rewind the videos for that because the videos are of course
recorded in a way that also makes sense to people who are not coding along.
So if you do you might need to pause occasionally try out the next steps on your own or go back to an
earlier point in a video to see how exactly I implemented something there and in general practicing
is important in this course we work on real projects and we have many smaller demos and I can only encourage
you that you sometimes pause and try out the next steps on your own or that you deviate from what I
do and try out your own things.
So definitely all the advance on your own.
Of course only to a certain extent because if you haven't learned about a certain feature it might be
hard to implement it on your own but whenever possible whenever you feel like it.
Definitely try out things on your own.
Now when you do that or when you just code along as well you will also face some errors.
Things don't always go as planned.
You introduced a mistake in your code and you get an error.
Now debug these errors and search on your own you will see attached code which you'll find attached
to many lectures in the course always to the last lecture of each module so that you can compare your
code to mine and find out where it deviates but also if you get error messages google them or use the
search here and you'll need me to also search the Q and A section because chances are someone else had
a similar error and you can quickly fix it by looking at their solution.
Now of course if you're really stuck or if some concept is unclear you can also ask but also answer
here in the Q and A section.
I do my best to provide quick support there but also try to help others there on your own because besides
fixing your own errors if you all will help others and work with our students you get a lot out of this
course as well so that's definitely all the recommendation I have.
And with all these steps or all these building blocks you have everything you need to get the most out
of this course.
In the next lecture I will show you d d setup the idea e I will be using for this course and thereafter
we can already dive into typescript.