Typescript is amazing but an order to work with it efficiently.
I strongly recommend that you also have a powerful code editor a powerful idea.
And here my clear recommendation is Visual Studio code.
It's free to use and it has amazing typescript support built in.
Now you still need to install the types of compiler and we already did this but this has to be built
in support.
Which shows you a lot of errors directly Endy i.e. before you even compiled the project so you can simply
visit code or visuals to do dot com and there you can download it for any operating system and simply
walk through the installer there to get this modern idea.
Now it is the idea I will be using for all this course.
And you can find tune and configure it to your requirements and needs.
Here are just some settings I'm using under a code references.
You can change the color theme and there I am using the dark plus theme.
So if you want the exact same look that's the theme I'm using.
But of course you can also play around with any arrow theme here.
I also installed certain extensions so third party plugins so to say which changed the appearance or
behavior of the editor.
You can click on View and then extensions to be taken to the extensions menu or the marketplace and
it's all free.
No worries nothing here cost you money.
Now I got tons of extensions installed but the extensions I would recommend that you definitely have
a look at is E as lint that you installed this to get a listing to get code quality check support in
your projects and that you installing material.
I can theme if you like these file icons I have in my projects.
That's a pure visual thing of course.
It doesn't change any behaviors and it can all recommend path intelligence so that later in the course
once we work with imports you get better support their and prettier which helps you format your code
so that it always looks nice and is readable prettier works together with a certain shortcut which you
should be aware of under Preferences Keyboard shortcuts there.
If you search for format document this shortcut here is a shortcut you can always press in your code
to auto format it to add missing semicolons to make sure you use the right indentation everywhere things
like that it makes your code more readable and your life as a developer easier and that's it.
You can also install t as lint but that will be merged with E as lint in the future so EA's land should
be all you really need.
With that we can go back to view explorer and you should have the same settings.
I have here but all the dive into the settings in general and explore them and find to everything to
your needs and to your likings.
And with that you have a great editor which allows you to write great code powerful code with a lot
of build and type support and you're well-prepared to get the most out of this course.