In this module we'll dive into a concept called generics.
Generics exist in typescript not in vanilla javascript.
So there is no real translation here but we can utilize him in typescript and the concept of generic
types all exists in our programming languages not in all our programming languages of course but in
some.
For example in C sharp now this course of course is not about C sharp though.
So let's have a look at what generics are and what they are in typescript and how we use them there
and why we use them there.
Specifically we'll have a look at what exactly generics are and why they are interesting and helpful.
We'll then build our own generic functions and classes because turns out we can do that will then have
a look at generic constraints and what that is and why we would use something like that.
And we'll have a look at a couple of special typescript types which also typically are generic and which
we do have for only really can understand now.
So let's see what we got there.