Speaking of more generic types as a little bonus you could say on one point your direction.
Add a couple of built in types TIBCO chips with which utilize generic types or which are generic types
to give us certain utility functionalities.
There is a little bonus here and from time to time these special types might come in handy.
Now it helps to find a link to the full documentation of all the built in utility types here.
I just want to give you a few examples now just as all these type things these types only exist in types
of the world and therefore only prior to copulation.
But during this compilation step they can give you extra type safety or extra flexibility.
For example there's two built in partial type.
Let's say we have a new type a new interface which we define or a custom type.
Really doesn't matter.
Course goal the course gold does have a title which should be a string.
And let's say a description which should all be a string maybe we also have a com pleat until property
which is a date.
Now we want to have a function let's say create course goal which creates us such a object.
Of course we could have created a class as well but we have such a function because in that function
we might be drawing in some data from a database or whatever it is so we have this function and in the
end here I want to get my title which is a string I might get my description which is a string and I
hopefully get my date which is a date.
Now in that function of course we could return an object but we just set up all these things or so where
we set title to title description to description and complete until to date.
We could do all of that and if we then to find that this function will always return a course goal we
would have a correctly setup function.
Now for some reason that say we're not doing it like this though we're not doing this all in one step
instead what I want to do is I want to start by creating a variable here which holds an empty object
and then step by step I want to add my title here I want to add my description here and I want to add
my date here now here I'm getting errors because of course a concert titled Is this not a property of
this object.
And while this works in vanilla javascript typescript doesn't really like that on the fly adding here
so we might want to say that this should be of type course goal here.
Now typescript is not complaining about this but about the fact that this is an empty object which clearly
is not fitting our type here.
So in the end I want to return to that I want to add all these things step by step maybe because we
have extra validation before each step.
And Dave for want to add it like this.
Now here's where the partial type can come in handy we could set a course goal here should be a partial
type which in the end thanks to generic types will hold a course goal.
Now what this does is it tells typescript that this is an object which in the end will be a course goal
but initially partial kind of wraps our own type and changes it to a type where all these properties
are optional.
That's what partial does one of these built in types TIBCO chips with.
So it turns this into a type which is all an object type where all the properties are optional therefore
we can set this to an empty object initially and still add all these things step by step.
The only problem is that in the end we can't return this because now it's still of type partial course
goal and not type core skill.
We can fix this by converting this to chorus goal with typecasting because we know at this point of
time we will have added all the data so it will be a real core goal and not a partial one.
And of course this is a bit made up but you could have scenarios like this where you want to temporarily
switch one of your object types one of your interfaces to be optional only to make sure that all the
properties and data can be optional only temporarily and then the partial type would allow you to do
that and no built in utility type.
What you have is the read only type that can all be very useful.
Let's say we have an array of names in there I got Max and sports now correctly typescript infers that
this is a String array.
Now what can we do.
We can of course push manual on there and probably I should change this too and not sports to have a
name in there.
So this works.
Now let's say however I want to make sure that this is a locked array we can't add more here that we
can always add more here but at least I want typescript to yell at me if I try it.
Well that's where we can use to read only type.
We could set this to read only string array.
With that we tell typescript Well what we story here is a it's an array of strings but it's also an
array of strings which is read only.
So when we try to add something with push or if we tried to remove something with Pop we get errors
because we're not allowed to do these things with this array.
And this is not limited to erase right away.
You can also use read only on an object for example to market as read only so that you're not allowed
to change the properties or add new properties to this object.
So this can all be very very handy and give you more flexibility or be more precise about what you're
aiming to do in your code.
Now all these are just utility types that only exist in typescript world so they're not compiled to
anything but during compilation they give you extra strictness or extra checks or skip certain checks
as we did it with partial.
Now you've got more than read only in partial and as I mentioned attached you find the documentation
to a full list of these utility types in certain scenarios they can come in really handy and therefore
I definitely did not want to hide them from you but instead you should be aware of them so that you
can use them when you need to lock something down.
Or as Nic has a partial open anything up or with all the other ones which I didn't discuss here.
If you've got some other operation which can be enhanced with one of these built in utility types and
these utility types are all generic because what they do is they take some other value which is of any
type and do something with it.
They set everything to optional they lock it down not caring about whether this is an array or object
or an array of strings array of numbers and so on.
That's why these are generic and to gather with the other built in generics we saw earlier and your
own generics does now hopefully all that again helps you understand why generics can be useful in why
they exist.