So you did it.
You'll finish this course and you learn a lot about typescript.
I can only encourage you to keep on practicing and working with it and use all the cool features you'll
learn about.
Now of course there also are Thurber resources which might be interesting to you.
Most importantly the official typescript web page.
There you can learn all about the niche features nitty gritty details and of course all the latest features
as well though to be honest we covered basically everything you find in there as well.
But if you want to dive deeper want to learn more or want to have a written guide.
This is a great resource to also learn about key concepts.
I also covered for all this course.
So this is one resource I would recommend dare you all to find a playground where you can quickly check
out some typescript scripts and run them here in the browser without any local setup.
Now as a next step I also recommend that you have a look at some types of projects and add some examples.
For example angular angular is a browser site framework that uses typescript that is built up on typescript
so to say it embraces TypeScript and therefore learning angular can be a great idea.
Now I've got a complete course on angular if you're interested but even if you don't do you want to
work with angular debt much checking out their open source code base could be interesting as well just
to learn how they are using TypeScript and to give you some ideas on how you could use it in your future
projects.
It's similar for Nest.
J.S. I showed this Andy node module nest J.S. also has a framework that embraces typescript but unlike
angular which is for the browser side nest J.S. is based on no tree s and is for the service site side
nest J as is also a really cool framework that uses tons of amazing types of features and it can be
interesting if you want to build a node application with typescript or even if you don't want to do
that justice with angular you can check out their code base to get some ideas on how to use typescript
how to use certain features and how to build cool things with typescript.
And last but not least if you need some inspiration did some other tutorials and guides maybe you can
of course use Google for example Google for typescript examples to find more articles on what you can
do with typescript find some example projects simply so that you get more and more used to the language
and get used to how to work with that language and how to build certain features with that language
and with that.
And of course with this course which you can also use as a reference to which you can come back whenever
you need to.
You have plenty of resources that should ensure that you can become a real typescript master.
I wish you all the best.
And if you build something awesome definitely share it with me.
I'm super excited to see what you're building with help of discourse.