Now with all the things we covered thus far in the course it's now time to practice a bit.
We're definitely not done with typescript.
There are more things to explore and more things will cover in the course.
For example how we can combine TypeScript and react.
But for the moment it's time to take a short break and practice some of the things we learned about
in a little demo project.
Now in this module we'll work on this project together but I definitely encourage you.
Did you occasionally hit the pause button and tried the next steps on your own.
Of course following along is also great and nice but you might learn a bit more if you also try things
on your own before you then compare your solution to mine.
And with that let's dive right in and practice working with typescript.