So we got two issues.
If we want to call them like that to fix now one to start with the issue dead projects show up in both
boxes I want to introduce some filtering and the best place to filter is of course our listener function.
If we go to the place where we register our listener
here in the project list class then here we get a list of projects right now.
That list of projects comprises all projects now inside of the project list class.
However we're only interested in active or finished projects.
Now here by the way we could also theoretically use our enum BUT ACTUALLY I NEED THE CONCRETE values
stored in the enum down there or in the type down there.
And therefore here I don't want to use it enum also because I want to show the string literal types.
So what we'll do here instead of our listener function is before we store the project and render them
we want to filter them.
So here we have our relevant projects.
You could say and that's of course projects filtered the filter method as a default method which exists
on any array in JavaScript.
This takes a function which then executes on every item in that projects array.
And when this function here returns true we keep the item in a newly created array which is then stored
in relevant projects.
If this function returns falls we dropped the item not from the original list but in the new list which
is generated in which is stored in relevant projects.
So in here we have to return true or false depending on whether we want to keep the project or not.
And for that of course we just need to look at the status project status is a enum and we want to check
whether project status is equal to Project Status Active.
If we're in an active project list so if the type property is active or if the project status is finished.
If we're in a finished list so here I'll actually write a real function body by wrapping this with curly
braces not using the arrow function shortcut and then we can check if this type is equal active.
Then I want to return the result of this check here.
Else and therefore simply offered as if statement.
I want to return the comparison to the finished project status.
With that we get our relevant project which we can now store here in assigned projects.
So let's now see whether that works.
If I reload and we add a project here does this work.
This works and you see it only is added to active projects not to finish projects.
However if I add a second project here we still have that duplication going on now.
That's related to how we render our projects instead of render projects.
We always go through all our project items and append them to the list.
Now the problem with that of course is that we already might have a project item rendered out onto the
screen now.
The best possible solution here would be to kind of run some comparison where you check what has already
been rendered and what you need to render to avoid unnecessary rendering.
However running this comparison by looking at the real Dom all the costs quite a bit of performance
for dis application here is there for perfectly fine to simply take our list element and clear all its
content by setting inter HD Himmel to an empty string which means we get rid of all list items and then
re render.
That means that whenever we add a new project we we render all projects but for the purpose of this
project here for does application here that is absolutely fine.
So now with that if we save that let's give it another try.
Does this work is the first project.
And now if I add another project here you see it gets added.
But the other project doesn't get added again whips.
And now here I got a malicious error because the description wasn't long enough.
So this now all works as you can tell and we're rendering these projects in the way they should be rendered
which of course is great.
And with that the application doesn't look too bad.
Now one thing that's missing is some drag and drop functionality or some way of getting projects from
this first list to the second list.
We're also not really outputting the other information we got.
Description A number of people.
So that's also not great.
And we also have a bit of code duplication when we actually have a look at project list at this class
here and that the project input class in both we have template element host element and element and
we have an attach method and so on.
So I want to improve the code here and reuse some code by using inheritance and using a base class enter
after I also want to create a dedicated class for every project item where we then just instantiate
that project item class instead of project list instead of appending a list item manually like this
and then inside of that to be created Project item class that appending part should happen and then
I always want to output more information about the project item including its description and the number
of people assigned.
So there is some work left to do and before we work on the project item in that forum in which I want
to have it let's actually make sure we first of all add some inheritance to make our project list and
project input or a certain parts of it more reusable.