And this is it for this little demo project.
Now of course there's always more you could do.
But here we're already using a bunch of nice types good features.
You'll learn about wrote this course.
And with this project you hopefully have a better idea of when we use which feature why certain features
like decorators and interfaces exist how they can help us and how we can write type safe scalable code.
Now Definitely feel free to build up on this project add more features on your own explorer what you
could change there and simply practice working with typescript.
I'm happy with the current state and in the next module I now want to tackle a quite obvious problem.
We got one super huge file here so splitting this up into multiple files would really help us with managing
our code base because right now we want to change something somewhere.
We always have to scroll for the entire file and find the place where we want to make a change.
That's not ideal.
This already is quite a lot of code an even bigger project.
It would be totally unmanageable.
So in the next module we'll have a look at the features typescript gives us that help us with splitting
our code across multiple files.